1
00:02:30,490 --> 00:02:33,994
You'd better take this along, Don.
It's gonna be cold on the farm.

2
00:02:34,077 --> 00:02:36,038
- How many shirts are you taking?
- Three.

3
00:02:36,121 --> 00:02:38,040
- I'm taking five.
- Five?

4
00:02:38,123 --> 00:02:41,293
I told them at the office
I might not be back until Tuesday.

5
00:02:41,335 --> 00:02:44,629
We'll get there this afternoon.
That's Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday.

6
00:02:44,671 --> 00:02:47,174
We'll make it
a long, wonderful weekend.

7
00:02:47,257 --> 00:02:48,800
Sounds long, all right.

8
00:02:48,884 --> 00:02:51,261
It'll be good for you, Don,
after what you've been through.

9
00:02:51,345 --> 00:02:54,306
Trees, grass,
sweet cider and buttermilk...

10
00:02:54,389 --> 00:02:56,433
and water from that well
that's colder than any other--

11
00:02:56,516 --> 00:03:00,187
Wick, please. Why this emphasis
on liquids? Very dull liquids.

12
00:03:01,980 --> 00:03:03,565
Sorry, Don.

13
00:03:06,985 --> 00:03:09,571
I think it'd be a good idea
if we took along my typewriter.

14
00:03:09,654 --> 00:03:11,031
What for?

15
00:03:11,114 --> 00:03:13,867
I'm gonna write there,
get started on that novel.

16
00:03:14,659 --> 00:03:17,704
- You really feel up to writing?
- Why not?

17
00:03:17,788 --> 00:03:19,164
After what
you've been through.

18
00:03:19,206 --> 00:03:21,166
I haven't touched the stuff
for 1 0 days now.

19
00:03:21,208 --> 00:03:23,960
I know.
I know you haven't.

20
00:03:25,212 --> 00:03:27,631
- Where is the typewriter?
- In the living room.

21
00:03:29,007 --> 00:03:30,592
In the closet.

22
00:03:34,221 --> 00:03:35,806
Towards the back.

23
00:03:46,817 --> 00:03:48,777
Are you sure it's in the closet?
I can't find it.

24
00:03:49,528 --> 00:03:51,446
Well, look by the desk.

25
00:03:55,826 --> 00:03:57,744
Isn't it under your bed?

26
00:04:00,747 --> 00:04:03,375
- Did you find it?
- Oh, sure.

27
00:04:03,458 --> 00:04:05,919
Here it is.

28
00:04:05,961 --> 00:04:09,047
Here's some paper. We'll
fix up a table on the south porch.

29
00:04:09,131 --> 00:04:11,383
Nobody will disturb you.
I'll see to it.

30
00:04:11,425 --> 00:04:13,427
Maybe Saturday, we can run down
to the country club.

31
00:04:13,510 --> 00:04:15,846
- I'm not going near that club.
- Why not?

32
00:04:15,929 --> 00:04:18,432
They're all a bunch of hypocrites.
I don't like to be whispered about.

33
00:04:18,515 --> 00:04:21,435
'' Look who's here from New York,
the Birnam brothers.''

34
00:04:21,476 --> 00:04:23,562
Or rather,
the nurse and the invalid.

35
00:04:23,645 --> 00:04:25,647
Stop it.
Nobody there knows about you.

36
00:04:25,731 --> 00:04:28,483
The minute we get off the train,
the alarm is sounded.

37
00:04:28,567 --> 00:04:30,527
''The leper is back.
Hide your liquor.''

38
00:04:32,279 --> 00:04:34,573
- That's Helen.
- I'll take it.

39
00:04:36,908 --> 00:04:39,494
- Helen.
- Hello, Wick. Where's Don?

40
00:04:39,578 --> 00:04:42,539
I'm glad I made it.
I was afraid you'd be gone. Presents.

41
00:04:42,622 --> 00:04:45,000
The new Thurber book
with comical jokes and pictures...

42
00:04:45,083 --> 00:04:47,586
a nice, quiet little double-murder
by Agatha Christie...

43
00:04:47,627 --> 00:04:48,879
cigarettes, gum.

44
00:04:48,962 --> 00:04:50,881
And darling, have a wonderful time.

45
00:04:50,964 --> 00:04:53,008
And don't forget:
lots of sleep, lots of milk--

46
00:04:53,091 --> 00:04:56,678
Lots of cider and lots of
nice cold water from the well.

47
00:04:56,762 --> 00:04:58,805
Bend down.

48
00:05:03,226 --> 00:05:05,562
I must be going.
I'm ten minutes late for the concert.

49
00:05:05,645 --> 00:05:07,314
- So long, Wick.
- What concert?

50
00:05:07,397 --> 00:05:11,485
Carnegie Hall. Bob Roller's conducting.
They gave me two tickets at the office.

51
00:05:11,568 --> 00:05:13,487
- Who are you going with?
- Nobody.

52
00:05:13,570 --> 00:05:16,823
Nobody? What are they playing?

53
00:05:16,907 --> 00:05:21,036
Brahms second symphony, some Beethoven,
Handel and not one note of Greek.

54
00:05:21,119 --> 00:05:23,163
- Sounds wonderful.
- Good-bye, boys. See you Monday.

55
00:05:23,246 --> 00:05:24,956
- Tuesday.
- Wait a minute.

56
00:05:24,998 --> 00:05:27,417
- I just had a crazy idea.
- For instance?

57
00:05:27,501 --> 00:05:29,795
Who says we have to take
the 3:1 5 train?

58
00:05:29,836 --> 00:05:32,923
- We could go on the 6:30.
- What are you talking about?

59
00:05:33,006 --> 00:05:36,385
If we took a later train, Helen
wouldn't have to go the concert alone.

60
00:05:36,468 --> 00:05:38,887
She's got two tickets,
hasn't she?

61
00:05:38,970 --> 00:05:41,640
No, I'm not going to upset
any of your plans.

62
00:05:41,682 --> 00:05:43,892
You're going on the 3:1 5.

63
00:05:43,975 --> 00:05:46,144
Helen, that's so silly.

64
00:05:46,228 --> 00:05:48,313
A whale of a concert,
an empty seat next to you.

65
00:05:48,355 --> 00:05:49,940
Everything's all set.

66
00:05:50,023 --> 00:05:52,025
They'll be at the station to meet us
and dinner will be waiting.

67
00:05:52,109 --> 00:05:55,779
Put in a call that we're taking a later
train, dinner at 9:00, in bed by 1 0:00.

68
00:05:55,862 --> 00:05:57,823
- Nothing doing. We're going.
- Wick is right.

69
00:05:57,906 --> 00:06:01,660
Don't worry about that seat. I'll find
a handsome, South American millionaire.

70
00:06:01,743 --> 00:06:05,497
There you are. Besides, we have to break
our necks anyway to catch the train.

71
00:06:05,580 --> 00:06:06,998
- Five to 3:00.
- You see?

72
00:06:07,040 --> 00:06:11,628
- Don't be so stubborn.
- All right, go ahead.

73
00:06:12,713 --> 00:06:16,633
-Just a minute. I'm not going.
- Then what are we talking about?

74
00:06:16,717 --> 00:06:19,511
- I want you to go, you and Helen.
- Me and Helen?

75
00:06:19,553 --> 00:06:21,596
That's the idea.
Who likes Brahms, you or I?

76
00:06:21,680 --> 00:06:26,351
- Since when don't you like Brahms?
- I'll just finish packing, take a nap.

77
00:06:26,435 --> 00:06:29,187
Nonsense. If anybody goes--
Helen's your girl.

78
00:06:29,229 --> 00:06:32,858
- There's something in that, Don.
- What's more, you shouldn't be alone.

79
00:06:32,941 --> 00:06:35,318
I shouldn't?
I'm not to be trusted, is that it?

80
00:06:35,402 --> 00:06:37,446
- Really, darling.
- After what you've been through--

81
00:06:37,529 --> 00:06:39,656
I couldn't go to the concert.
I couldn't face the crowds.

82
00:06:39,740 --> 00:06:41,658
I couldn't sit through it
with all those people.

83
00:06:41,742 --> 00:06:44,036
Besides, I wanna be alone
a couple hours to assemble myself.

84
00:06:44,077 --> 00:06:46,038
Is that such
an extraordinary thing to want?

85
00:06:46,079 --> 00:06:48,582
Don't act so outraged.
Would you mind?

86
00:06:48,665 --> 00:06:51,376
- All right. Anything else?
- Please, boys.

87
00:06:53,754 --> 00:06:55,672
Come on, Helen.

88
00:06:55,756 --> 00:06:58,342
- You'll stay right here.
- Where would I go?

89
00:06:58,425 --> 00:07:00,969
- Then you'll be here when we get back?
- I'm not leaving this apartment.

90
00:07:01,053 --> 00:07:02,929
You told us a good many things.

91
00:07:03,013 --> 00:07:05,849
If you don't believe me take my keys,
lock me in like a dog!

92
00:07:05,932 --> 00:07:08,060
We've got to trust Don.
That's the only way.

93
00:07:08,894 --> 00:07:12,522
Sorry, Don.
Let's go, Helen.

94
00:07:12,606 --> 00:07:14,941
- So long, Don.
- So long.

95
00:07:16,109 --> 00:07:18,528
Bend down.

96
00:07:36,338 --> 00:07:38,090
- What's this?
- Whiskey, isn't it?

97
00:07:38,131 --> 00:07:40,092
- How did it get there?
- I don't know.

98
00:07:40,133 --> 00:07:44,012
I suppose it dropped from some cloud, or
someone bounced it and it stuck there.

99
00:07:44,096 --> 00:07:46,765
- I guess I must have put it there.
- Yes, you must.

100
00:07:46,848 --> 00:07:49,768
But I don't remember when.
Probably during my last spell.

101
00:07:49,810 --> 00:07:51,812
Maybe the one before.
I don't know.

102
00:07:53,522 --> 00:07:55,982
Don't look at me like that.
It doesn't mean a thing.

103
00:07:56,066 --> 00:07:58,610
I didn't know it was there.
If I had, I wouldn't have touched it.

104
00:07:58,652 --> 00:08:01,029
- Then you won't mind.
- Mind what?

105
00:08:13,709 --> 00:08:17,754
- Now, you trot along with Helen.
- Why? Because of that?

106
00:08:17,838 --> 00:08:20,382
You think I wanted you out
because of the bottle?

107
00:08:20,465 --> 00:08:22,968
I resent that like the devil.
One more word of discussion...

108
00:08:23,010 --> 00:08:25,512
I don't leave on your blasted weekend!

109
00:08:25,554 --> 00:08:27,139
Let's go.

110
00:08:33,020 --> 00:08:35,022
You'll be good, won't you, darling?

111
00:08:35,105 --> 00:08:37,482
Yes. Will you stop
watching me all the time?

112
00:08:37,524 --> 00:08:39,901
Let me work it out my way.
I'm trying. I'm trying!

113
00:08:39,985 --> 00:08:42,237
We know you're trying.

114
00:08:42,320 --> 00:08:44,865
We're both trying.
You're trying not to drink...

115
00:08:44,948 --> 00:08:47,659
and I'm trying not to love you.

116
00:08:52,581 --> 00:08:55,167
Call the farm and tell them
we're taking the 6:30.

117
00:08:55,208 --> 00:08:57,169
Sure.

118
00:08:57,210 --> 00:08:58,837
So long.

119
00:09:02,382 --> 00:09:04,801
Come on.
He'll be all right.

120
00:09:04,885 --> 00:09:06,803
What if he goes out
and buys another bottle?

121
00:09:06,887 --> 00:09:09,014
He hasn't a nickel.
There isn't a store or a bar...

122
00:09:09,097 --> 00:09:11,058
that'll give him
five cents' worth of credit.

123
00:09:11,099 --> 00:09:13,060
Are you sure he doesn't have
another bottle hidden?

124
00:09:13,101 --> 00:09:16,021
I went over the apartment
with a fine-tooth comb.

125
00:09:16,063 --> 00:09:17,481
The places he can figure out.

126
00:10:24,214 --> 00:10:26,550
Who is it?
Who is it?

127
00:10:26,633 --> 00:10:28,593
Mrs. Foley.
I've come to clean up.

128
00:10:30,220 --> 00:10:32,222
Does it have to be today?

129
00:10:32,305 --> 00:10:35,225
I ought to change the sheets,
and it's my day to vacuum.

130
00:10:35,267 --> 00:10:38,395
- Come on Monday.
- All right, Mr. Birnam.

131
00:10:38,478 --> 00:10:41,023
- Is your brother in?
- No, he isn't.

132
00:10:41,064 --> 00:10:45,736
What about my money?
Didn't he leave my money?

133
00:10:45,819 --> 00:10:48,238
- What money?
- My ten dollars.

134
00:10:48,280 --> 00:10:51,324
- Didn't he leave it?
- Probably. Where would he leave it?

135
00:10:51,408 --> 00:10:54,369
- In the kitchen.
- Where in the kitchen?

136
00:10:54,453 --> 00:10:56,413
In the sugar bowl.

137
00:10:57,914 --> 00:10:59,499
just a minute.

138
00:11:14,097 --> 00:11:16,308
I'm sorry, it isn't there.
He must have forgotten.

139
00:11:16,391 --> 00:11:19,644
I wanted to do some shopping.

140
00:11:19,728 --> 00:11:22,606
- You'll get it Monday.
- All right, Mr. Birnam.

141
00:11:47,381 --> 00:11:49,925
- Two bottles of rye.
- I'm sorry, Mr. Birnam.

142
00:11:49,966 --> 00:11:52,094
- What are you sorry about?
- Your brother was in.

143
00:11:52,135 --> 00:11:55,389
He's not gonna pay for you anymore.
That was the last time.

144
00:11:56,640 --> 00:11:59,101
- Two bottles of rye.
- What brand?

145
00:11:59,142 --> 00:12:01,812
You know what brand.
The cheapest.

146
00:12:01,895 --> 00:12:05,065
None of that 1 2-year-old,
aged-in-the-wood chichi for me.

147
00:12:05,148 --> 00:12:07,192
- Liquor's all one anyway.
- You want a bag?

148
00:12:07,275 --> 00:12:09,194
Yes, I want a bag.

149
00:12:11,822 --> 00:12:14,533
Your brother said not to sell to you
even if you had the money.

150
00:12:14,616 --> 00:12:17,619
I can't stop anybody, can I?
Not unless you're a minor.

151
00:12:17,661 --> 00:12:20,163
I'm not a minor.
And just to ease your conscience...

152
00:12:20,205 --> 00:12:22,582
I'm buying this to refill
my cigarette lighter.

153
00:12:35,679 --> 00:12:37,305
Yes, sir?

154
00:12:39,057 --> 00:12:41,435
Thank you.

155
00:12:44,438 --> 00:12:47,983
- Good afternoon, Mrs. Deveridge.
- Hello, Mr. Birnam.

156
00:12:48,025 --> 00:12:51,570
That's the nice young man
who drinks.

157
00:12:56,533 --> 00:13:00,203
- How is my very good friend Nat today?
- Yes, Mr. Birnam?

158
00:13:00,287 --> 00:13:02,205
This being an especially
fine afternoon...

159
00:13:02,289 --> 00:13:05,459
I have decided to ask
your hand in marriage.

160
00:13:05,542 --> 00:13:08,545
If that's your attitude, I'll have to
drown my sorrows with a jigger of rye.

161
00:13:08,628 --> 00:13:11,256
-Just one, that's all.
- It can't be done.

162
00:13:11,298 --> 00:13:14,092
It can't?
Let me guess why.

163
00:13:14,134 --> 00:13:16,720
My brother was here undermining
my financial structure.

164
00:13:16,803 --> 00:13:19,222
I didn't tell him nothing about
the wristwatch or the cuff links.

165
00:13:19,306 --> 00:13:21,600
Thank you very much, Nat.
Today you'll be glad to know...

166
00:13:21,683 --> 00:13:24,394
we can barter on a cash basis.

167
00:13:24,478 --> 00:13:26,605
- One straight rye.
- That was the idea.

168
00:14:03,684 --> 00:14:06,269
Don't wipe it away.

169
00:14:06,353 --> 00:14:08,647
Let me have my little vicious circle.

170
00:14:09,898 --> 00:14:13,068
You know, the circle
is the perfect geometric figure.

171
00:14:13,151 --> 00:14:15,612
No end, no beginning.

172
00:14:15,696 --> 00:14:18,448
- What time is it?
- A quarter of 4:00.

173
00:14:18,532 --> 00:14:20,659
Good. We have
the whole afternoon together.

174
00:14:20,742 --> 00:14:23,328
Let me know when it's a quarter
of 6:00. It's very important.

175
00:14:24,204 --> 00:14:27,165
I'm going to the country
for a weekend with my brother.

176
00:14:27,207 --> 00:14:30,460
Hello, Mr. Birnam. Happy to have you
back with the organization.

177
00:14:30,544 --> 00:14:33,672
Hello, Gloria.
I wish I could take you along, Nat.

178
00:14:33,755 --> 00:14:36,633
You and all that goes with you...

179
00:14:36,717 --> 00:14:41,138
not that I'm cutting myself off
from civilization altogether.

180
00:14:44,891 --> 00:14:48,270
Now, of course, there arises the problem
of transportation into the country.

181
00:14:48,353 --> 00:14:51,481
How to smuggle these two time bombs
past the Royal Guard.

182
00:14:51,565 --> 00:14:54,109
<i>I'll roll one bottle in a copy
of the Saturday Evening Post...</i>

183
00:14:54,192 --> 00:14:56,236
so my brother
can discover it like that.

184
00:14:56,319 --> 00:14:59,031
I want him to discover it.
It'll set his mind at ease.

185
00:14:59,114 --> 00:15:02,576
The other bottle--
Come here.

186
00:15:02,617 --> 00:15:05,704
That one I'm tucking
into my brother's suitcase.

187
00:15:05,787 --> 00:15:08,665
He shall transport it himself
without knowing it, of course.

188
00:15:08,749 --> 00:15:10,876
Then while he's greeting
the caretaker...

189
00:15:10,959 --> 00:15:15,964
I'll slide it out, hide it
in a hollow old apple tree.

190
00:15:16,048 --> 00:15:19,468
Mr. Birnam, why don't you
lay off the stuff for a while?

191
00:15:19,551 --> 00:15:22,137
I may never touch it
while I'm there, not a drop.

192
00:15:22,220 --> 00:15:25,766
What all of you don't understand is
I've got to know it's around.

193
00:15:25,849 --> 00:15:28,393
I can't be cut off completely.
That's the devil.

194
00:15:28,477 --> 00:15:30,103
That's what drives you crazy.

195
00:15:30,187 --> 00:15:32,898
Yeah, I know a lot of guys like that.

196
00:15:32,939 --> 00:15:35,233
They take a bottle
and put it on the shelf.

197
00:15:35,275 --> 00:15:39,446
All they wanna do is look at it.
They'll corkscrew it to make sure.

198
00:15:39,529 --> 00:15:43,992
Then all of the sudden, they
grab the bottle, bite off the neck.

199
00:15:44,076 --> 00:15:48,455
One more reproving word, I shall
consult our lawyer about a divorce.

200
00:15:48,497 --> 00:15:51,458
Don't forget, quarter of 6:00.
My brother must find me home...

201
00:15:51,541 --> 00:15:53,460
ready and packed.

202
00:15:55,921 --> 00:15:57,506
Shall we dance?

203
00:15:59,174 --> 00:16:01,176
You're awfully pretty, Mr. Birnam.

204
00:16:01,259 --> 00:16:02,969
I bet you tell that
to all the boys.

205
00:16:03,053 --> 00:16:05,764
Why, natch.
Only with you, it's on the level.

206
00:16:05,847 --> 00:16:08,517
- Sit down.
- No, thanks.

207
00:16:08,600 --> 00:16:11,687
Thanks a lot, but no, thanks.
There's somebody waiting.

208
00:16:12,604 --> 00:16:15,065
Him? I bet he wears arch supporters.

209
00:16:15,148 --> 00:16:17,067
He's just an old friend of the folks.

210
00:16:17,150 --> 00:16:20,112
Lovely gentleman.
He buys me scotch.

211
00:16:20,153 --> 00:16:24,199
He should buy you rubies and a villa
in Calcutta overlooking the Ganges.

212
00:16:24,282 --> 00:16:26,952
- Don't be ''ridic.''
- Gloria, please.

213
00:16:27,035 --> 00:16:30,247
Why imperil our friendship
with these loathsome abbreviations?

214
00:16:30,997 --> 00:16:34,292
I could make myself free
for later on, if you want.

215
00:16:34,334 --> 00:16:37,504
I'm going away for the weekend.
Some other time.

216
00:16:37,587 --> 00:16:39,631
Anytime.

217
00:16:39,673 --> 00:16:42,009
I'm just crazy about
the back of your hair.

218
00:16:49,433 --> 00:16:51,601
Nat, weave me another.

219
00:16:51,685 --> 00:16:53,979
- You'd better take it easy.
- Oh, don't worry about me.

220
00:16:54,062 --> 00:16:56,690
just let me know
when it's a quarter of 6:00.

221
00:16:56,773 --> 00:16:59,609
Come on,join me.
One little jigger of dreams.

222
00:16:59,693 --> 00:17:02,863
- No, thanks.
- You don't approve of drinking?

223
00:17:02,946 --> 00:17:04,865
Not the way you drink.

224
00:17:04,906 --> 00:17:07,367
It shrinks my liver, doesn't it?

225
00:17:07,409 --> 00:17:09,703
It pickles my kidneys, yes.

226
00:17:09,786 --> 00:17:12,706
But what does it do to my mind?

227
00:17:12,748 --> 00:17:16,168
It tosses the sandbags overboard
so the balloon can soar.

228
00:17:16,209 --> 00:17:19,671
Suddenly, I'm above the ordinary.
I'm confident, supremely confident.

229
00:17:19,755 --> 00:17:22,215
I'm walking a tightrope
over Niagra Falls.

230
00:17:22,299 --> 00:17:24,009
I'm one of the great ones.

231
00:17:24,092 --> 00:17:26,845
I'm Michelangelo
molding the beard of Moses.

232
00:17:26,928 --> 00:17:28,722
I'm van Gogh painting pure sunlight.

233
00:17:28,805 --> 00:17:31,933
I'm Horowitz playing
the '' Emperor Concerto.''

234
00:17:32,017 --> 00:17:34,686
I'm John Barrymore before
the movies got him by the throat.

235
00:17:34,770 --> 00:17:37,898
I'm JesseJames and his two brothers.
All three of them!

236
00:17:37,981 --> 00:17:40,525
I'm W. Shakespeare.

237
00:17:40,567 --> 00:17:42,903
And out there,
it's not 3rd Avenue any longer.

238
00:17:42,986 --> 00:17:45,322
It's the Nile...

239
00:17:45,405 --> 00:17:48,283
and down it floats
the barge of Cleopatra.

240
00:17:49,826 --> 00:17:52,454
Come here.

241
00:17:52,537 --> 00:17:56,750
'' Purple the sails, and so perfumed
that the winds were lovesick with them.

242
00:17:56,833 --> 00:17:58,543
The oars were silver...

243
00:17:58,585 --> 00:18:00,712
which to the tune of flutes
kept stroke.''

244
00:18:03,465 --> 00:18:07,386
Maybe he's at Mirandi's or Nat's Bar,
that place on 42nd Street.

245
00:18:07,469 --> 00:18:09,429
What difference does it make?

246
00:18:09,471 --> 00:18:11,890
- You're not really going?
- I certainly am.

247
00:18:11,973 --> 00:18:14,851
- You can't leave him alone four days.
- Yes, I can.

248
00:18:14,935 --> 00:18:18,021
Oh, for heaven's sake.
If he's left alone, anything can happen.

249
00:18:18,105 --> 00:18:20,774
I'm tied up at the office every minute
all Saturday, all Sunday.

250
00:18:20,816 --> 00:18:23,402
I can't look out for him.
You know how he gets.

251
00:18:23,485 --> 00:18:26,905
He'll be run over by a car.
He'll be arrested.

252
00:18:26,988 --> 00:18:29,741
A cigarette might fall from his mouth,
and he'd burn in bed.

253
00:18:29,825 --> 00:18:32,369
If it happens it happens,
and I hope it does.

254
00:18:32,452 --> 00:18:35,539
I've had six years of this.
I've had my belly full!

255
00:18:37,457 --> 00:18:40,127
- You can't mean that.
- Yes, I do.

256
00:18:40,168 --> 00:18:42,754
- It's terrible, I know, but I mean it.
- For heaven's sakes--

257
00:18:42,838 --> 00:18:46,425
Who are we fooling?
We've tried everything, haven't we?

258
00:18:46,508 --> 00:18:49,469
We've reasoned with him, babied him,
watched him like a hawk.

259
00:18:49,511 --> 00:18:52,347
We've tried trusting him.
How often have you tried?

260
00:18:52,431 --> 00:18:54,474
How often have I beaten him up?

261
00:18:54,558 --> 00:18:58,270
Scrape him out of a gutter and pump
some kind of self-respect into him...

262
00:18:58,353 --> 00:19:01,648
and back he falls,
back in every time.

263
00:19:02,858 --> 00:19:04,609
He's a sick person.

264
00:19:04,693 --> 00:19:07,654
It's as though something were wrong
with his heart or lungs.

265
00:19:07,696 --> 00:19:10,949
You wouldn't walk out on him
if he had an attack. He needs our help.

266
00:19:11,033 --> 00:19:13,785
He won't accept our help.
He hates us.

267
00:19:13,869 --> 00:19:16,371
He wants to be alone
with that bottle of his.

268
00:19:16,455 --> 00:19:18,373
It's all he gives a hang about.

269
00:19:23,378 --> 00:19:25,172
Why kid ourselves?

270
00:19:25,255 --> 00:19:28,175
He's a hopeless alcoholic.

271
00:19:28,258 --> 00:19:32,095
''The cloud-capped towers,
the gorgeous palaces--

272
00:19:34,181 --> 00:19:37,184
The solemn temples,
the great globe itself.''

273
00:19:37,267 --> 00:19:39,478
Mr. Birnam, you ought to go home.
It's late.

274
00:19:39,561 --> 00:19:41,938
''Yea, all which it inherit
shall dissolve.''

275
00:19:42,022 --> 00:19:43,940
You ought to go home
on account of your brother.

276
00:19:44,024 --> 00:19:46,485
- Who says so?
- You said you're going away somewhere.

277
00:19:46,568 --> 00:19:49,363
- Don't you remember?
- What time is it?

278
00:19:49,446 --> 00:19:51,406
- Ten past 6:00.
- Why didn't you tell me?

279
00:19:51,490 --> 00:19:53,742
What do you think I've been doing
for half an hour?

280
00:19:53,825 --> 00:19:55,869
Your change!

281
00:20:33,740 --> 00:20:36,118
Taxi! Taxi!

282
00:20:36,201 --> 00:20:38,120
I'll give you a lift
as far as Grand Central.

283
00:20:38,203 --> 00:20:41,039
- No, thanks. I'm gonna wait here.
- You're crazy.

284
00:20:41,123 --> 00:20:44,084
Because I won't give up?
Maybe I am.

285
00:20:44,126 --> 00:20:46,712
Let go of him.
Give yourself a chance.

286
00:20:46,795 --> 00:20:48,380
Good-bye, Wick.

287
00:23:49,061 --> 00:23:51,104
I thought you was
going away for the weekend.

288
00:23:56,818 --> 00:23:59,071
What are you doing?
Give me a drink.

289
00:23:59,154 --> 00:24:01,323
Be right with you.
just fixing myself some lunch.

290
00:24:01,406 --> 00:24:04,409
Stop it and give me a drink.
Come on. Come on!

291
00:24:04,493 --> 00:24:07,162
Okay.

292
00:24:07,245 --> 00:24:10,374
- Can't you hurry it up a little?
- Here you are.

293
00:24:12,000 --> 00:24:13,960
That young lady stopped in
last night looking for you.

294
00:24:16,338 --> 00:24:18,882
- What young lady?
- The one with the leopard coat.

295
00:24:18,965 --> 00:24:20,092
Yeah?

296
00:24:20,175 --> 00:24:22,469
She acted like
she just happened to drop in.

297
00:24:22,511 --> 00:24:24,471
But I know she was making
the rounds after you.

298
00:24:24,513 --> 00:24:27,265
- What did you say?
- You haven't been in for two weeks.

299
00:24:27,349 --> 00:24:30,352
That's good. I can't let her see me,
not when I'm off like this.

300
00:24:30,435 --> 00:24:34,648
- Why don't you cut it short?
- I can't cut it short.

301
00:24:34,690 --> 00:24:37,192
Get on the merry-go-round,
you gotta ride it all the way.

302
00:24:37,275 --> 00:24:39,778
'Round and 'round till that
blasted music wears itself out...

303
00:24:39,861 --> 00:24:42,155
and the thing dies down
and clunks to a stop.

304
00:24:42,239 --> 00:24:45,367
- How about you eating some of this?
- Take it away.

305
00:24:45,450 --> 00:24:47,661
You gotta eat something sometime.

306
00:24:47,744 --> 00:24:49,996
just give me another drink.

307
00:24:50,080 --> 00:24:52,457
Mr. Birnam, this is the morning.

308
00:24:52,541 --> 00:24:55,919
That's when you need it most.
Haven't you learned that yet?

309
00:24:56,003 --> 00:24:58,463
At night, the stuff's a drink.
In the morning, it's medicine.

310
00:24:58,547 --> 00:25:02,634
- Okay if I eat?
- A little to one side.

311
00:25:06,346 --> 00:25:10,350
Are you ever scared when you wake up?
So scared the sweat starts out of you?

312
00:25:10,434 --> 00:25:13,270
No, not you.
With you it's simple.

313
00:25:13,353 --> 00:25:15,313
The alarm clock goes off,
you open your eyes...

314
00:25:15,397 --> 00:25:18,608
<i>brush your teeth
and read the Daily Mirror.</i>

315
00:25:18,692 --> 00:25:21,361
You ever lie in your bed,
looking at the window?

316
00:25:21,403 --> 00:25:24,239
A little daylight's coming through,
and you start to wonder.

317
00:25:24,322 --> 00:25:26,408
Is it getting lighter?
Is it getting darker?

318
00:25:26,491 --> 00:25:30,287
Is it dawn or is it dusk?
That's a terrifying problem.

319
00:25:30,370 --> 00:25:32,456
Because if it's dawn, you're dead.

320
00:25:32,539 --> 00:25:35,208
The bars are closed,
the liquor stores don't open until 9:00.

321
00:25:35,250 --> 00:25:37,210
You can't last until 9:00!

322
00:25:38,545 --> 00:25:42,215
Or it may be Sunday.
That's the worst.

323
00:25:42,257 --> 00:25:46,303
No liquor stores at all, and you guys
wouldn't open a bar until 1 :00. Why?

324
00:25:46,386 --> 00:25:48,972
Because we gotta go to church
once in a while.

325
00:25:49,056 --> 00:25:51,516
Yeah, when a guy needs it most.

326
00:25:52,768 --> 00:25:56,188
What happened to those two quarts?
Did you polish them off last night?

327
00:25:56,271 --> 00:25:58,690
- What two quarts?
- The two bottles you had.

328
00:26:00,442 --> 00:26:03,028
That's right,
I did have two bottles, didn't I?

329
00:26:03,111 --> 00:26:05,864
I hid one of them.
I've still got it.

330
00:26:05,947 --> 00:26:09,826
I'm a capitalist.
I've got untapped reserves. I'm rich!

331
00:26:11,536 --> 00:26:13,663
If you had enough money,
you'd kill yourself in a month.

332
00:26:13,747 --> 00:26:16,708
Nat, was there a gentleman here--
Hello, Mr. Birnam.

333
00:26:16,792 --> 00:26:19,503
- Didn't you go away for the weekend?
- Apparently not.

334
00:26:19,586 --> 00:26:22,297
- Was there a gentleman asking for me?
- Not to my knowledge.

335
00:26:22,381 --> 00:26:24,716
He was supposed to come around 1 1 :00.
He's from Albany.

336
00:26:24,800 --> 00:26:28,261
-Another friend of the folks?
-More a friend of a friend of the folks.

337
00:26:28,345 --> 00:26:30,847
A fellow called me up about him.
Wants me to show him the town.

338
00:26:30,931 --> 00:26:33,266
- Like Grant's tomb, for instance?
- But ''def.''

339
00:26:34,768 --> 00:26:38,188
Ain't it amazing how many guys
come from Albany to see Grant's tomb?

340
00:26:40,982 --> 00:26:43,235
Sometimes, I wish
you came from Albany.

341
00:26:43,276 --> 00:26:45,278
Yeah? Where would you take me?

342
00:26:45,320 --> 00:26:48,657
<i>Lots of places. Music Hall,
the New Yorker roof, maybe.</i>

343
00:26:48,740 --> 00:26:51,660
There is now being presented
at a theater on 44th Street...

344
00:26:51,743 --> 00:26:53,662
<i>the uncut version of Hamlet.</i>

345
00:26:53,745 --> 00:26:55,664
I see us as setting out for that.

346
00:26:55,747 --> 00:26:58,125
<i>- Do you know Hamlet?
- I know 44th Street.</i>

347
00:26:58,208 --> 00:27:01,420
I would like to get your interpretation
of Hamlet's character.

348
00:27:01,503 --> 00:27:02,921
I'd like to give it to you.

349
00:27:02,963 --> 00:27:04,923
Dinner later, I think.
Nothing before.

350
00:27:04,965 --> 00:27:07,759
One should always see Shakespeare
on an empty stomach.

351
00:27:07,843 --> 00:27:11,388
- Not even a pretzel?
- Can I have a glass of water?

352
00:27:11,471 --> 00:27:13,849
Why, sure.
What'll it be for a chaser?

353
00:27:13,932 --> 00:27:17,602
- This is Nat's bar, isn't it?
- That's what the man said.

354
00:27:17,644 --> 00:27:20,939
I'm looking for a young lady,
name of Gloria.

355
00:27:25,068 --> 00:27:27,946
- Are you Miss Gloria?
- Me? No, I'm not.

356
00:27:27,988 --> 00:27:29,990
I just live with Gloria.
She's not here.

357
00:27:30,032 --> 00:27:32,159
- She isn't?
- She's sick. She went to the hospital.

358
00:27:32,242 --> 00:27:34,286
Ruptured appendix,
middle of last night.

359
00:27:34,327 --> 00:27:36,955
Went like that.
Scared the life out of me.

360
00:27:36,997 --> 00:27:38,874
Oh, that's terrible.

361
00:27:38,957 --> 00:27:41,710
- Good-bye.
- Good-bye.

362
00:27:46,840 --> 00:27:48,800
Could I have a word with you?

363
00:27:48,842 --> 00:27:51,803
No, thanks.
Thanks a lot, but no, thanks.

364
00:27:51,845 --> 00:27:54,306
- You're welcome.
- Don't ''mench.''

365
00:28:04,358 --> 00:28:08,070
Now, wasn't it rather rude to send that
nice man all alone to Grant's tomb?

366
00:28:08,153 --> 00:28:10,113
When I've got a chance
to go out with you?

367
00:28:10,197 --> 00:28:13,325
- Don't be ''ridic.''
- Is our engagement definite?

368
00:28:13,367 --> 00:28:16,411
- You meant it, didn't you?
- Surely, surely.

369
00:28:16,495 --> 00:28:19,164
I've gotta get a facial, a finger wave,
the works, right now.

370
00:28:19,206 --> 00:28:22,167
- You're gonna call for me, aren't you?
- What time do you suggest?

371
00:28:22,209 --> 00:28:23,502
- How's 8:00?
- 8:00's fine.

372
00:28:23,585 --> 00:28:26,171
I live right in the corner house
where the antique shop is...

373
00:28:26,213 --> 00:28:28,173
the one with
the wooden Indian outside.

374
00:28:28,215 --> 00:28:30,509
- ''I got the Indian sign in me,'' I say.
- I'll be there.

375
00:28:30,550 --> 00:28:32,719
Second floor, front.

376
00:28:32,803 --> 00:28:35,681
Mr. Birnam,
all I got is a semiformal.

377
00:28:35,764 --> 00:28:38,058
- Will that be all right?
- That'll be fine.

378
00:28:38,141 --> 00:28:39,518
So long, Nat.

379
00:28:40,310 --> 00:28:41,687
One last one.

380
00:28:41,770 --> 00:28:44,898
Pour it softly, pour it gently
and pour it to the brim.

381
00:28:44,981 --> 00:28:47,567
Look, there are a lot of bars
on 3rd Avenue.

382
00:28:47,651 --> 00:28:49,820
Do me a favor, will you?
Buy it somewhere else.

383
00:28:49,903 --> 00:28:52,322
- What's the matter?
- What's the idea of pulling her leg?

384
00:28:52,406 --> 00:28:54,324
- You're not gonna take her out.
- Who says I'm not?

385
00:28:54,408 --> 00:28:56,410
You're drunk and just
making with the mouth.

386
00:28:56,493 --> 00:28:58,995
- Give me a drink.
- That other dame-- the lady, I mean--

387
00:28:59,079 --> 00:29:01,707
- I don't like what you're doing to her.
- Oh, shut up.

388
00:29:01,748 --> 00:29:03,709
You should've seen her last night
looking for you...

389
00:29:03,750 --> 00:29:06,003
her eyes all rainy
and the mascara all washed away.

390
00:29:06,086 --> 00:29:08,880
- Give me a drink!
- That's an awful high-class young lady.

391
00:29:08,922 --> 00:29:11,466
- You bet she is.
- How did she get mixed up with a guy...

392
00:29:11,550 --> 00:29:14,386
- who sops it up like you do?
- It's a problem, isn't it?

393
00:29:14,469 --> 00:29:16,722
That nice young man who drinks
and the high-class young lady.

394
00:29:16,763 --> 00:29:19,933
How did she get mixed up with him?
Why does he drink? Why doesn't he stop?

395
00:29:19,933 --> 00:29:20,475
How did she get mixed up with him?
Why does he drink? Why doesn't he stop?

396
00:29:20,559 --> 00:29:22,477
That's my novel.

397
00:29:22,561 --> 00:29:24,813
I oughta start writing it
out in the country.

398
00:29:24,896 --> 00:29:27,399
Morbid stuff.
Nothing for the Book of the Month club.

399
00:29:27,441 --> 00:29:29,067
A horror story.

400
00:29:29,109 --> 00:29:33,030
<i>The Confessions of a Booze Addict.:
The Long Book of an Alcoholic.</i>

401
00:29:33,113 --> 00:29:35,449
Oh, come on.
Break down, will ya?

402
00:29:36,700 --> 00:29:39,202
<i>You know what I'm gonna call my novel?
The Bottle.</i>

403
00:29:39,286 --> 00:29:42,039
<i>That's all.
Very simply The Bottle.</i>

404
00:29:44,124 --> 00:29:46,043
I've got it all here in my mind.

405
00:29:46,126 --> 00:29:48,378
Let me tell you the first chapter.

406
00:29:48,462 --> 00:29:51,840
It all starts one wet afternoon
about three years ago.

407
00:29:51,923 --> 00:29:54,384
<i>There was a matinee of La Traviata
at the Metropolitan.</i>

408
00:30:13,320 --> 00:30:15,238
Check your hat and coat, sir.

409
00:33:14,835 --> 00:33:17,045
- Here.
- Did you forget something?

410
00:33:17,129 --> 00:33:19,423
No,just going home
if it's all right with you.

411
00:33:27,264 --> 00:33:29,516
- This isn't yours, is it?
- It certainly isn't.

412
00:33:29,599 --> 00:33:31,977
- That's what is says-- 41 7.
- I don't care what it says.

413
00:33:32,019 --> 00:33:34,146
- The checks must've gotten mixed up.
- Maybe they did.

414
00:33:34,229 --> 00:33:36,815
Find my coat.
It's a plain men's raincoat and a derby.

415
00:33:36,857 --> 00:33:40,444
Do you know how many plain men's
raincoats we have on a day like this?

416
00:33:40,527 --> 00:33:42,654
- About a thousand.
- I can find it.

417
00:33:42,738 --> 00:33:44,156
That's against regulations, sir.

418
00:33:44,197 --> 00:33:46,491
I am not gonna wait here
until the end of the performance.

419
00:33:46,533 --> 00:33:48,910
- You can get your coat tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?

420
00:33:48,994 --> 00:33:51,455
Look, there's something in the pocket
of that coat that I--

421
00:33:51,538 --> 00:33:55,208
Well, it so happens I found myself
without any money. I need that coat now!

422
00:33:55,292 --> 00:33:57,836
Listen, if everybody went
diggin' in through those coats--

423
00:33:57,919 --> 00:34:01,548
There's regulations.
There's got to be regulations!

424
00:34:01,631 --> 00:34:03,842
Then what do you suggest?

425
00:34:03,884 --> 00:34:05,886
Wait till the other party arrives
and swap.

426
00:34:05,927 --> 00:34:07,304
I want my coat!

427
00:34:07,387 --> 00:34:11,558
As far as I'm concerned, mister,
that's your coat.

428
00:34:12,684 --> 00:34:14,603
You're a great help.

429
00:35:02,359 --> 00:35:04,528
- That's my coat you've got.
- And that's mine, thank heaven.

430
00:35:04,611 --> 00:35:07,072
- They mixed up the checks.
- I thought you'd never come.

431
00:35:07,155 --> 00:35:11,243
- You couldn't have waited so long.
- Since the first aria of the first act.

432
00:35:11,326 --> 00:35:13,787
Do you always drop in
just for the overture?

433
00:35:14,746 --> 00:35:16,331
just a minute.

434
00:35:21,294 --> 00:35:23,255
My umbrella, if you don't mind.

435
00:35:24,840 --> 00:35:28,301
- Catch.
- Thank you very much.

436
00:35:32,389 --> 00:35:34,266
I'm terribly sorry.

437
00:35:34,307 --> 00:35:37,144
You're the rudest person I've ever seen.
What's the matter with you?

438
00:35:37,227 --> 00:35:40,147
-Just rude, I guess.
- Somebody should talk to your mother.

439
00:35:40,188 --> 00:35:43,275
- They tried, Miss St.John.
- My name's not St.John.

440
00:35:43,316 --> 00:35:45,652
- St.Joseph, then.
- St.James.

441
00:35:45,736 --> 00:35:48,655
First name Hilda or Helen
or Harriet, maybe.

442
00:35:48,697 --> 00:35:51,116
- Helen.
- All right, Helen.

443
00:35:56,413 --> 00:35:59,499
-I also know you come from Toledo, Ohio.
-You do? How?

444
00:35:59,583 --> 00:36:02,544
I've had three long acts
to work you out from that coat of yours.

445
00:36:02,627 --> 00:36:06,923
Initials, label.
Alfred Spitzer Fine Furs, Toledo, Ohio.

446
00:36:07,007 --> 00:36:09,092
Maybe I should've explored
your coat.

447
00:36:09,176 --> 00:36:11,470
- But you didn't, though?
- Didn't have time.

448
00:36:11,511 --> 00:36:13,805
Good. My name is Don Birnam.

449
00:36:13,847 --> 00:36:16,391
How do you do?

450
00:36:16,475 --> 00:36:18,935
- Well, how do you like New York?
- Love it.

451
00:36:19,019 --> 00:36:22,314
- You intend to stay long?
- Oh, 60 years, perhaps.

452
00:36:22,397 --> 00:36:24,691
- I live here now. I have a job.
- Doing what?

453
00:36:24,775 --> 00:36:28,028
<i>- Time Magazine.
- Perhaps you can do something for me.</i>

454
00:36:28,111 --> 00:36:30,906
- Yes?
- Help me become '' Man of the Year''?

455
00:36:30,989 --> 00:36:33,575
- Delighted. What do you do?
- Yes, what do I do?

456
00:36:33,658 --> 00:36:35,577
I'm a writer.
I've just started a novel.

457
00:36:35,660 --> 00:36:38,080
As a matter of fact I've started
several, but I never seem to finish one.

458
00:36:38,163 --> 00:36:40,082
In that case,
why don't you write short stories?

459
00:36:40,165 --> 00:36:42,501
I have some of those--
first paragraph.

460
00:36:42,542 --> 00:36:44,503
Then there's one half
of the opening scene of a play...

461
00:36:44,544 --> 00:36:46,505
which takes place in
the Leaning Tower of Pisa.

462
00:36:46,546 --> 00:36:51,176
It attempts to explain why it leans and
why all sensible buildings should lean.

463
00:36:51,259 --> 00:36:53,553
- They'll love that in Toledo.
- Oh, by the way.

464
00:36:53,637 --> 00:36:56,556
<i>- Are you coming to here Lohengrin?
- I don't know.</i>

465
00:36:56,598 --> 00:36:59,184
Because if you are, I'm not letting
this coat out of my hands.

466
00:36:59,226 --> 00:37:01,269
- Don't worry.
- But I do.

467
00:37:01,353 --> 00:37:04,398
To be really safe,
we should go together.

468
00:37:04,481 --> 00:37:05,691
We could.

469
00:37:05,732 --> 00:37:07,943
Are you in the phone book?

470
00:37:08,026 --> 00:37:11,279
- Yes, but I'm not home very much.
- I'd call you at your office.

471
00:37:12,572 --> 00:37:15,033
Editorial research.
If Henry Luce answers, hang up.

472
00:37:15,075 --> 00:37:16,702
All right.

473
00:37:19,913 --> 00:37:21,790
- Would you like a taxi?
- No, thanks, I'm taking the subway.

474
00:37:21,873 --> 00:37:23,792
- Very sensible.
- As a matter of fact...

475
00:37:23,875 --> 00:37:27,462
I'm going to an extremely crazy party
on Washington Square.

476
00:37:27,546 --> 00:37:30,007
If you like, I'll take you along.

477
00:37:30,090 --> 00:37:33,552
Thank you very much,
but I have to see a friend uptown.

478
00:37:35,303 --> 00:37:37,264
- Good-bye, Mr. Birnam.
- Good-bye.

479
00:37:50,444 --> 00:37:53,113
- Who threw that?
- It fell out of my pocket.

480
00:37:53,196 --> 00:37:55,407
- Do you always carry those things?
- Well, no.

481
00:37:55,490 --> 00:37:57,951
That friend of mine uptown,
he has a slight cold.

482
00:37:58,035 --> 00:38:00,579
I thought I'd take this along
and make him a hot toddy.

483
00:38:00,662 --> 00:38:02,622
See that he gets hot lemonade
and some aspirin.

484
00:38:02,664 --> 00:38:04,458
- I shall.
- Good-bye.

485
00:38:08,211 --> 00:38:09,629
Oh, Miss St.James.

486
00:38:11,131 --> 00:38:14,092
- Yes?
- What kind of party did you ask me to?

487
00:38:14,176 --> 00:38:16,887
- A cocktail party.
- Does the invitation still stand?

488
00:38:16,970 --> 00:38:18,889
Of course. Come on.

489
00:38:26,605 --> 00:38:29,941
So they go to that party, he gets
stinko and falls flat on his face.

490
00:38:30,025 --> 00:38:33,570
He does not. By this time,
he's crazy about the girl.

491
00:38:33,653 --> 00:38:36,698
He drinks tomato juice.
Doesn't touch liquor that whole week.

492
00:38:36,782 --> 00:38:38,825
- For two weeks, for six weeks.
- In love, huh?

493
00:38:40,952 --> 00:38:43,163
That's what's gonna be
so hard to write.

494
00:38:43,246 --> 00:38:46,083
Love is the hardest thing
in the world to write about.

495
00:38:46,166 --> 00:38:49,586
It's so simple.
You gotta catch it through details...

496
00:38:49,670 --> 00:38:51,963
like the early morning sunlight
hitting the gray tin...

497
00:38:52,047 --> 00:38:54,383
of the rain spout
in front of her house.

498
00:38:54,466 --> 00:38:58,387
The ringing of a telephone that
sounds like Beethoven's '' Pastoral.''

499
00:38:58,470 --> 00:39:01,348
A letter scribbled on her office
stationary you carry in your pocket...

500
00:39:01,431 --> 00:39:05,143
because it smells like
all the lilacs in Ohio.

501
00:39:05,227 --> 00:39:06,812
Pour it, Nat.

502
00:39:09,648 --> 00:39:12,025
He thinks he's cured.

503
00:39:12,109 --> 00:39:15,529
If he could only get a job,
they'd be married and that's that.

504
00:39:15,612 --> 00:39:18,156
But it's not, Nat.
Not quite.

505
00:39:18,240 --> 00:39:20,992
Because one day, one terrible day--

506
00:39:21,034 --> 00:39:22,703
Go on.

507
00:39:25,038 --> 00:39:28,083
You see, this girl has been writing
to her people in Toledo.

508
00:39:28,166 --> 00:39:31,336
They wanna meet the young man,
so they come to New York.

509
00:39:31,378 --> 00:39:33,505
They stay at the Hotel Manhattan.

510
00:39:33,588 --> 00:39:37,134
Their very first day,
she's to introduce him to her parents.

511
00:39:37,217 --> 00:39:39,845
One o'clock, lobby of the hotel.

512
00:39:57,904 --> 00:39:59,990
That wasn't enough,
not for New York.

513
00:40:00,073 --> 00:40:03,410
He gave me a shampoo, scalp massage
and a manicure.

514
00:40:03,493 --> 00:40:07,289
I thought they were going to tear off
my shoes and paint my toenails.

515
00:40:07,372 --> 00:40:10,417
I had a lovely morning.
just did a little window shopping.

516
00:40:10,500 --> 00:40:13,462
- Didn't want to get all tired out.
- On account of meeting that young man?

517
00:40:13,545 --> 00:40:16,715
- Now, Mother.
- Who did you get that haircut for?

518
00:40:17,591 --> 00:40:20,135
- I wonder what's keeping Helen.
- She'll be here.

519
00:40:20,218 --> 00:40:22,137
This Birnam fellow
went to Cornell, didn't he?

520
00:40:22,220 --> 00:40:25,974
- I believe so.
- He never graduated. I wonder why.

521
00:40:26,058 --> 00:40:27,559
- How old is he?
- Thirty-three.

522
00:40:27,601 --> 00:40:31,188
He has no job. As far as
I can find out, he never had one.

523
00:40:31,271 --> 00:40:33,231
I wish Helen wasn't so vague.

524
00:40:33,273 --> 00:40:36,276
Maybe he has a little money.
Some people do you know, Father.

525
00:40:36,318 --> 00:40:39,029
- He ought to have a job anyway.
- He's a writer.

526
00:40:39,112 --> 00:40:41,239
What did he write?
I never heard his name.

527
00:40:41,281 --> 00:40:44,910
Father, relax.
You always expect the worst.

528
00:40:44,951 --> 00:40:47,579
I hope he realizes
that Helen's our only daughter.

529
00:40:47,662 --> 00:40:49,623
We ought to know
a few things about him.

530
00:40:49,664 --> 00:40:53,377
It'll all come out--
his background, his prospects...

531
00:40:53,460 --> 00:40:55,379
his church affiliation.

532
00:41:36,086 --> 00:41:39,047
Hotel Manhattan?
Could you page Miss Helen St.James.

533
00:41:39,131 --> 00:41:41,550
St.James.
Yes, she's in the lobby.

534
00:41:57,816 --> 00:41:59,484
Helen? Don.

535
00:41:59,526 --> 00:42:02,654
I'm terribly sorry, but I won't
be able to get there for awhile.

536
00:42:02,696 --> 00:42:06,825
Go ahead and have your lunch
and apologize to your parents.

537
00:42:06,867 --> 00:42:09,202
Oh, nothing serious.
I'll be there.

538
00:42:09,244 --> 00:42:10,829
Good-bye.

539
00:42:32,351 --> 00:42:34,978
Turn off that light.

540
00:42:35,062 --> 00:42:37,939
- Turn it off!.
- For heaven's sake.

541
00:42:41,068 --> 00:42:44,279
I thought you were with Helen
and her father and mother.

542
00:42:44,363 --> 00:42:45,947
What happened?

543
00:42:49,284 --> 00:42:51,536
- Come on.
- I couldn't face it.

544
00:42:51,620 --> 00:42:53,580
Couldn't face what?
Didn't you go to see them?

545
00:42:53,622 --> 00:42:56,291
Certainly I went, 1 :00 sharp.

546
00:42:56,375 --> 00:42:59,378
I saw them, all right,
only they didn't see me.

547
00:42:59,461 --> 00:43:02,714
- How was that?
- Such nice, respectable people.

548
00:43:02,756 --> 00:43:05,467
I couldn't face them.
And all the questions they'd ask me?

549
00:43:05,550 --> 00:43:07,678
I just couldn't do it, not cold.

550
00:43:07,761 --> 00:43:11,890
I had to have a drink first,just one,
only the one didn't do anything to me.

551
00:43:11,973 --> 00:43:15,227
So you had another and another.
You poor idiot.

552
00:43:15,310 --> 00:43:17,562
Won't you ever learn that with you,
it's like stepping off a roof...

553
00:43:17,646 --> 00:43:19,606
and expecting to fall just one floor?

554
00:43:19,648 --> 00:43:21,608
Will you call her?

555
00:43:21,692 --> 00:43:24,736
Tell her something.
Tell her I'm sick, tell her I'm dead.

556
00:43:24,778 --> 00:43:27,364
- Will you call?
- Yes, I'll call.

557
00:43:27,447 --> 00:43:30,784
She must've written them
a lot of nice things about me.

558
00:43:30,826 --> 00:43:33,245
What a gentleman I am,
a prince.

559
00:43:33,286 --> 00:43:35,664
- Which hotel is it?
- The Manhattan.

560
00:43:35,747 --> 00:43:39,626
Mr. and Mrs. Charles St.James
ofToledo, Ohio.

561
00:43:47,134 --> 00:43:48,719
Get up!

562
00:43:58,937 --> 00:44:00,856
just a minute, Helen.

563
00:44:13,326 --> 00:44:15,829
- Hello, Wick. Is Don here?
- Don? No.

564
00:44:15,912 --> 00:44:19,082
- Any idea where he could be?
- Wasn't he meeting you?

565
00:44:19,166 --> 00:44:22,252
He was supposed to meet us for lunch.
He telephoned he'd be late.

566
00:44:22,336 --> 00:44:25,464
Mother's beginning to think
I just made him up.

567
00:44:25,505 --> 00:44:27,466
Do you suppose
something happened to him?

568
00:44:27,507 --> 00:44:28,884
Nonsense.

569
00:44:28,967 --> 00:44:31,261
But surely he'd have called back
if he were all right.

570
00:44:31,345 --> 00:44:33,263
- Where did he call you from?
- I don't know.

571
00:44:33,347 --> 00:44:35,932
I think I have an idea.
He called you from out of town.

572
00:44:36,016 --> 00:44:37,851
- Where?
- Philadelphia.

573
00:44:37,934 --> 00:44:41,021
<i>- What's he doing there?
- There's an opening at the Enquirer.</i>

574
00:44:41,104 --> 00:44:45,776
Don wrote them, wired them, and I think
this morning took an early train.

575
00:44:47,402 --> 00:44:49,863
He didn't tell me a word about it.

576
00:44:49,905 --> 00:44:52,657
I'm not supposed to tell you either.
He wanted it to be a surprise.

577
00:44:52,741 --> 00:44:54,159
- He did?
- Yes.

578
00:44:54,201 --> 00:44:57,662
He probably couldn't meet the right
people right away. You know how it is.

579
00:44:57,746 --> 00:45:01,083
It would be wonderful if he got the job
and started working.

580
00:45:03,460 --> 00:45:04,878
Or would it?

581
00:45:04,920 --> 00:45:07,130
With him in Philadelphia
and me in New York.

582
00:45:07,214 --> 00:45:09,800
Don't ever tell him
I said that though, will you?

583
00:45:09,883 --> 00:45:12,302
- Of course not.
- I could never understand...

584
00:45:12,386 --> 00:45:14,971
why somebody like Don,
a person with such talent...

585
00:45:15,055 --> 00:45:17,724
such flashes of real brilliance--

586
00:45:17,808 --> 00:45:22,187
Maybe I'm a bit prejudiced.
What are you doing?

587
00:45:22,979 --> 00:45:25,357
- Nothing.
- Where did that bottle come from?

588
00:45:25,399 --> 00:45:27,901
- It just rolled out.
- From under the couch?

589
00:45:27,984 --> 00:45:30,404
Yes.

590
00:45:30,445 --> 00:45:32,656
You know, it's my guess
Don caught an early train and--

591
00:45:32,739 --> 00:45:35,534
- Is that Don's bottle?
- What makes you think that?

592
00:45:35,575 --> 00:45:38,787
There was a bottle
the first time we met.

593
00:45:38,870 --> 00:45:42,040
- There was?
- Fell out of Don's pocket.

594
00:45:42,082 --> 00:45:45,836
That was for me.
This one's mine too.

595
00:45:45,919 --> 00:45:49,381
You might as well hear
the family scandal. I drink.

596
00:45:49,423 --> 00:45:51,842
Don thinks I drink too much.
I promised to go on the wagon.

597
00:45:51,925 --> 00:45:53,844
I hid the bottle
so he wouldn't see it.

598
00:45:53,927 --> 00:45:56,263
I'm sorry.

599
00:45:56,304 --> 00:45:58,807
I shouldn't have started
asking questions.

600
00:45:58,890 --> 00:46:01,101
It's really none of my business.

601
00:46:01,184 --> 00:46:03,020
Forget it.

602
00:46:03,103 --> 00:46:05,022
I better be getting back
to the hotel.

603
00:46:05,105 --> 00:46:07,441
Don's probably there already.

604
00:46:07,482 --> 00:46:09,651
And don't worry.
I won't mention a word of it to him.

605
00:46:09,735 --> 00:46:11,028
- Thank you.
- Good-bye.

606
00:46:15,949 --> 00:46:19,786
I'm sorry.
I can't let you go, not like this.

607
00:46:19,870 --> 00:46:21,913
Shut your mouth, Don.
I'll take you downstairs.

608
00:46:21,955 --> 00:46:24,624
Thanks very much
for your Philadelphia story.

609
00:46:24,708 --> 00:46:26,376
Nice try.

610
00:46:26,460 --> 00:46:29,212
- That looks so silly on you.
- Don't listen to him.

611
00:46:29,296 --> 00:46:31,548
She doesn't have to.
just look at the two of us.

612
00:46:31,631 --> 00:46:33,800
What is all this covering up?

613
00:46:33,884 --> 00:46:37,971
Don was nervous at the idea of meeting
your parents, so he had a couple drinks.

614
00:46:38,055 --> 00:46:40,766
Come on. She'd have found out
sooner or later.

615
00:46:40,807 --> 00:46:42,434
Stop it, both of you.

616
00:46:43,935 --> 00:46:45,979
Don's a little tight.
Most people drink a little.

617
00:46:46,063 --> 00:46:48,065
A lot of them get tight
once in a while.

618
00:46:48,148 --> 00:46:50,567
Sure, the lucky ones,
who can take it or leave it.

619
00:46:50,650 --> 00:46:54,237
But then there are the ones who can't
take it and can't leave it either.

620
00:46:54,321 --> 00:46:56,823
What I'm trying to say is,
I'm not a drinker.

621
00:46:56,907 --> 00:46:59,701
I'm a drunk.
They had to put me away once.

622
00:46:59,785 --> 00:47:02,454
- He went to a cure.
- Which didn't take.

623
00:47:02,496 --> 00:47:05,082
You see, that first time we met,
I should've had the decency...

624
00:47:05,165 --> 00:47:07,084
to get drunk
just for your sake.

625
00:47:07,167 --> 00:47:10,295
For my sake?
We're talking about you.

626
00:47:10,337 --> 00:47:13,465
- Is it really that bad?
- Yes, it is.

627
00:47:13,548 --> 00:47:15,967
Can't we go over this tomorrow
when you're feeling more like yourself?

628
00:47:16,009 --> 00:47:19,513
Helen's heard the facts.
That's all there is to it.

629
00:47:19,596 --> 00:47:22,140
Yes, I've heard them,
and they're not too pleasant.

630
00:47:22,182 --> 00:47:25,394
They could be worse. After all,
you're not an embezzler or a murderer.

631
00:47:25,477 --> 00:47:27,396
You drink too much,
and that's not fatal.

632
00:47:27,479 --> 00:47:29,439
One cure didn't take.
There are others.

633
00:47:29,523 --> 00:47:32,651
- Of course there are.
- This has a familiar ring.

634
00:47:32,734 --> 00:47:34,695
But there must be a reason
why you drink.

635
00:47:34,736 --> 00:47:37,823
- The right doctor could find it.
- I'm way ahead of the right doctor.

636
00:47:37,906 --> 00:47:41,326
I know the reason.
The reason is me, what I am.

637
00:47:41,368 --> 00:47:45,122
Or rather, what I'm not--
what I wanted to become and didn't.

638
00:47:45,205 --> 00:47:47,833
What is it you wanna be so much
that you're not?

639
00:47:49,543 --> 00:47:51,795
A writer.

640
00:47:51,878 --> 00:47:53,463
Silly, isn't it?

641
00:47:55,716 --> 00:47:58,093
In college, I passed for a genius.

642
00:47:58,176 --> 00:48:01,430
They couldn't get out the college
magazine without one of my stories.

643
00:48:01,513 --> 00:48:04,933
Boy, was I hot.
Hemingway stuff.

644
00:48:05,017 --> 00:48:07,519
I reached my peak when I was 1 9.

645
00:48:07,602 --> 00:48:11,815
<i>Sold a piece to the Atlantic Monthly,
reprinted in the Reader's Digest.</i>

646
00:48:11,898 --> 00:48:15,527
Who wants to stay in college
when he's Hemingway?

647
00:48:15,569 --> 00:48:18,071
My mother bought me
a brand-new typewriter.

648
00:48:18,113 --> 00:48:20,323
I moved right in on New York.

649
00:48:20,407 --> 00:48:23,994
Well, the first thing I wrote,
that didn't quite come off.

650
00:48:24,077 --> 00:48:27,873
And the second, I dropped.
The public wasn't ready for that one.

651
00:48:27,914 --> 00:48:31,376
I started a third and a forth.

652
00:48:31,460 --> 00:48:36,214
Only by then, somebody began
to look over my shoulder and whisper...

653
00:48:36,298 --> 00:48:40,886
in a thin, clear voice
like the E string on a violin.

654
00:48:40,927 --> 00:48:43,930
'' Don Birnam,'' he'd whisper.

655
00:48:44,014 --> 00:48:47,559
''It's not good enough,
not that way.

656
00:48:49,019 --> 00:48:52,230
How about a couple of drinks,
just to set it on its feet?''

657
00:48:53,482 --> 00:48:57,069
So I had a couple.
What a great idea that was.

658
00:48:57,152 --> 00:49:00,072
That made all the difference.
Suddenly, I could see the whole thing.

659
00:49:00,113 --> 00:49:04,493
The tragic sweep of the great novel,
beautifully proportioned.

660
00:49:04,576 --> 00:49:07,454
But before I could really grab it
and throw it down on paper...

661
00:49:07,496 --> 00:49:09,664
the drinks would wear off
and everything would be gone...

662
00:49:09,748 --> 00:49:11,708
like a mirage.

663
00:49:11,792 --> 00:49:15,253
Then there was despair.
I'd drink to counterbalance despair.

664
00:49:15,295 --> 00:49:18,048
And then one to counterbalance
the counterbalance.

665
00:49:19,132 --> 00:49:22,177
I'd sit in front of that typewriter,
trying to squeeze out...

666
00:49:22,260 --> 00:49:24,513
one page that was halfway decent.

667
00:49:25,472 --> 00:49:28,058
And that guy would pop up again.

668
00:49:28,141 --> 00:49:30,060
What guy?
Who are you talking about?

669
00:49:30,143 --> 00:49:33,397
The other Don Birnam.
There are two of us, you know--

670
00:49:33,480 --> 00:49:36,441
Don the Drunk
and Don the Writer.

671
00:49:36,525 --> 00:49:38,485
The drunk would say to the writer...

672
00:49:38,568 --> 00:49:41,780
''Come on, you idiot. Let's get
some good out of that portable.

673
00:49:41,863 --> 00:49:45,659
Let's hock it. Let's take it
to that pawn shop on 3rd Avenue.

674
00:49:45,701 --> 00:49:47,828
It's always good for ten dollars.

675
00:49:47,911 --> 00:49:52,666
Another drink, another binge,
another bender, another spree.''

676
00:49:52,749 --> 00:49:54,960
Such humorous words.

677
00:49:55,002 --> 00:49:58,338
I've tried to break away
from that guy a lot of times...

678
00:49:58,422 --> 00:50:00,549
but to no good.

679
00:50:01,383 --> 00:50:05,137
You know, once I even got myself
a gun and some bullets.

680
00:50:05,220 --> 00:50:08,181
I was gonna do it
on my 30th birthday.

681
00:50:09,266 --> 00:50:13,645
Here are the bullets. The gun
went for three quarts of whiskey.

682
00:50:13,687 --> 00:50:16,398
The other Don wanted us
to have a drink first.

683
00:50:16,481 --> 00:50:19,985
He always wants us
to have a drink first.

684
00:50:20,068 --> 00:50:22,404
The flop suicide
of a flop writer.

685
00:50:22,487 --> 00:50:24,906
All right, maybe you're not a writer.
Why don't you do something else?

686
00:50:24,990 --> 00:50:27,159
Sure, take a nice job.

687
00:50:27,242 --> 00:50:29,995
Public accountant,
real estate salesman.

688
00:50:30,078 --> 00:50:32,039
I haven't the guts.

689
00:50:32,080 --> 00:50:34,666
Most men lead lives
of quiet desperation.

690
00:50:34,750 --> 00:50:37,336
- I can't take quiet desperation!
- But you are a writer.

691
00:50:37,419 --> 00:50:40,922
You have every quality for it--
imagination, wit, pity.

692
00:50:41,006 --> 00:50:43,008
Come on.
Let's face reality.

693
00:50:43,050 --> 00:50:45,844
I'm 33. I'm living
on the charity of my brother.

694
00:50:45,927 --> 00:50:48,388
Room and board free...

695
00:50:48,430 --> 00:50:50,265
fifty cents a week for cigarettes...

696
00:50:50,349 --> 00:50:52,893
an occasional ticket
to a show or a concert.

697
00:50:52,976 --> 00:50:55,395
All out of
the bigness of his heart.

698
00:50:55,479 --> 00:50:57,481
And it is a big heart
and a patient one.

699
00:50:57,564 --> 00:50:59,358
I've only been
carrying you along for--

700
00:50:59,399 --> 00:51:01,693
Shut up!
I've never done anything.

701
00:51:01,735 --> 00:51:04,279
I'm not doing anything.
I never will do anything!

702
00:51:04,363 --> 00:51:06,615
- Zero, zero, zero.
- Now you shut up.

703
00:51:06,698 --> 00:51:09,242
- We'll straighten it out.
- Look.

704
00:51:09,326 --> 00:51:11,620
Wick has the misfortune
of being my brother.

705
00:51:11,703 --> 00:51:13,705
You just happened
to walk in on this.

706
00:51:13,747 --> 00:51:16,750
If you know what's good for you,
turn around and walk out.

707
00:51:16,792 --> 00:51:19,461
And walk fast,
and don't turn back.

708
00:51:24,716 --> 00:51:27,803
Why don't you make some coffee?
Strong, three cups.

709
00:51:27,886 --> 00:51:31,515
Look, do yourself a favor.
Go on. Clear out.

710
00:51:31,598 --> 00:51:35,227
Because I've got a rival?
Because you're in love with this?

711
00:51:35,268 --> 00:51:39,272
You don't know me.
I'm gonna fight and fight and fight.

712
00:51:39,356 --> 00:51:40,399
Bend down.

713
00:51:47,656 --> 00:51:49,408
All right.

714
00:51:56,998 --> 00:51:59,001
That was three years ago.

715
00:51:59,084 --> 00:52:01,670
That's a long time
to keep fighting, to keep believing.

716
00:52:01,753 --> 00:52:05,007
She knows she's clutching a razor blade,
but she won't let go.

717
00:52:05,090 --> 00:52:08,135
- Three years of it.
- And what?

718
00:52:08,218 --> 00:52:11,346
- How's it come out?
- I haven't figured that far.

719
00:52:11,430 --> 00:52:13,807
Want me to tell you?

720
00:52:13,849 --> 00:52:17,102
One day, a guy gets wise to himself,
he gets back that gun.

721
00:52:17,185 --> 00:52:21,023
If he's only got $1 .1 0, he goes
to the top of the Empire State Building.

722
00:52:21,106 --> 00:52:22,899
And then--

723
00:52:22,983 --> 00:52:25,610
Or you can do it for a nickel
in the subway under a train.

724
00:52:25,652 --> 00:52:27,571
You think so?

725
00:52:27,654 --> 00:52:30,532
What if Helen's right, and this guy
sits down and turns out something good?

726
00:52:30,615 --> 00:52:32,534
And that pulls him up
and snaps him out of it.

727
00:52:32,617 --> 00:52:34,870
This guy?
Not from where I sit.

728
00:52:34,953 --> 00:52:38,540
Oh, shut up! I wanna do it now!
It's all there. You heard it.

729
00:52:38,623 --> 00:52:41,501
- Yes, Mr. Birnam.
- That's why I didn't go away.

730
00:52:41,585 --> 00:52:43,962
I can be all alone up there
and sit down at my typewriter.

731
00:52:44,004 --> 00:52:46,131
This time, I'm gonna do it!

732
00:52:46,173 --> 00:52:48,425
- Maybe you will.
- Thank you.

733
00:52:48,508 --> 00:52:51,136
- Am I all paid up?
- Yes, Mr. Birnam.

734
00:52:51,178 --> 00:52:52,971
Good-bye. I'm going home.

735
00:52:53,055 --> 00:52:55,265
This time, I've got it.
I'm gonna write!

736
00:52:58,185 --> 00:53:00,145
Good luck to you.

737
00:54:27,566 --> 00:54:29,484
You had another bottle.
You know you did.

738
00:54:29,568 --> 00:54:32,154
Where did you put it?
You're not crazy. Where did you put it?

739
00:55:52,317 --> 00:55:55,320
<i>It was so beautiful, so wonderful</i>

740
00:55:55,404 --> 00:55:58,240
<i>The stars above us shone</i>

741
00:55:58,323 --> 00:55:59,866
<i>We were alone</i>

742
00:56:01,910 --> 00:56:04,329
- Check, please.
- Right here, sir.

743
00:56:25,809 --> 00:56:29,187
- Yes, sir?
- Another gin vermouth, please.

744
00:56:29,271 --> 00:56:30,689
Yes, sir.

745
00:57:39,841 --> 00:57:41,468
Thank you.

746
00:57:42,969 --> 00:57:45,806
- Where is your washroom?
- Over there, sir.

747
00:57:53,021 --> 00:57:55,065
How's about a carnation
for your buttonhole?

748
00:57:55,148 --> 00:57:56,608
No, thank you.

749
00:57:57,693 --> 00:57:59,820
Thank you, sir.

750
00:57:59,861 --> 00:58:01,321
- Wash your hands?
- Thank you.

751
00:58:01,363 --> 00:58:03,073
All righty, sir.

752
00:58:05,534 --> 00:58:08,328
- Would you wipe my shoes?
- Yes, sir.

753
00:58:27,806 --> 00:58:30,726
- Carnation, sir?
- I already took one.

754
00:58:30,809 --> 00:58:34,062
- You did?
- For a very kind lady.

755
00:58:34,146 --> 00:58:35,731
Yes, sir.

756
00:58:38,150 --> 00:58:40,277
- Thank you.
- Thank you, sir.

757
00:59:02,382 --> 00:59:05,886
- That's him! That's the man!
- You were sitting here, sir?

758
00:59:05,969 --> 00:59:07,929
I beg your pardon?

759
00:59:12,142 --> 00:59:15,145
You took this lady's bag,
didn't you? Let's have it.

760
00:59:17,230 --> 00:59:19,441
- Of course.
- Somebody call a cop!

761
00:59:19,524 --> 00:59:21,943
No, George. It doesn't matter
as long as I have the bag.

762
00:59:21,985 --> 00:59:24,404
Look in it.
Maybe he took something.

763
00:59:24,446 --> 00:59:27,657
- Ten dollars, to be exact.
- I oughta kick your teeth in.

764
00:59:27,741 --> 00:59:30,160
- He's drunk.
- Come on. Get out of here.

765
00:59:30,243 --> 00:59:33,246
- How about the check?
- That's why I borrowed from the lady.

766
00:59:33,330 --> 00:59:36,083
I didn't have enough.
I'll come back and pay the rest.

767
00:59:36,166 --> 00:59:38,543
Don't you show your face
in here again ever! Mike!

768
00:59:39,252 --> 00:59:42,339
<i>- Take him out of here.
- Somebody stole a purse</i>

769
00:59:42,422 --> 00:59:44,383
Everybody!

770
00:59:44,466 --> 00:59:47,094
I assure you, I'm not a thief!.
I'm not a thief!.

771
01:02:34,094 --> 01:02:36,013
Stop it, Helen.
Stop it.

772
01:02:38,348 --> 01:02:40,851
I'm all right.
I just can't talk.

773
01:02:42,728 --> 01:02:44,521
Please stop it!

774
01:03:52,547 --> 01:03:54,591
You'll never make it.

775
01:03:54,675 --> 01:03:57,928
You'll never make that hock shop.
It's a block and a half away.

776
01:04:49,479 --> 01:04:51,815
- This isn't Sunday, is it?
- Huh?

777
01:04:51,857 --> 01:04:54,609
- I asked, ''Is this Sunday?''
- No. Saturday. Why?

778
01:04:54,651 --> 01:04:57,154
But it's closed.
Nothing else is closed.

779
01:04:57,237 --> 01:04:59,489
Somebody passed away,
most likely.

780
01:06:54,980 --> 01:06:58,984
- What's the matter with you?
- Why are they all closed?

781
01:06:59,067 --> 01:07:01,111
They're all closed,
every one of'em.

782
01:07:01,194 --> 01:07:03,697
- Sure they are. It's Yom Kippur.
- It's what?

783
01:07:03,780 --> 01:07:06,825
- It's Yom Kippur, a Jewish holiday.
- It is?

784
01:07:06,908 --> 01:07:09,036
And what about Kelly's
and Gallagher's?

785
01:07:09,119 --> 01:07:11,455
They're closed too.
We've got an agreement.

786
01:07:11,538 --> 01:07:14,583
They keep closed on Yom Kippur,
and we don't open on St. Patrick's.

787
01:07:15,709 --> 01:07:19,629
That's a good joke.
That's funny. That's very funny.

788
01:07:58,835 --> 01:08:00,629
Yeah, Mr. Birnam?

789
01:08:01,713 --> 01:08:03,674
What do you want?

790
01:08:07,344 --> 01:08:11,723
Let me have one, Nat.
I'm dying.Just one.

791
01:08:11,807 --> 01:08:14,184
I thought you was home
writing that book.

792
01:08:14,267 --> 01:08:19,439
They're playing a trick on me,
a dirty trick, Nat. Give me one.

793
01:08:19,523 --> 01:08:22,693
I'll pay you when I can,
only just don't let me die here.

794
01:08:22,776 --> 01:08:24,945
No credit,
and you know it.

795
01:08:25,028 --> 01:08:28,323
All right. It's charity.
I'm begging you. Give me one.

796
01:08:29,366 --> 01:08:31,118
Yeah. One.

797
01:08:31,201 --> 01:08:34,162
One's too many,
and a hundred's not enough.

798
01:08:45,340 --> 01:08:46,758
That's all.

799
01:08:47,884 --> 01:08:52,014
Come on, Nat.
I'll let you have my typewriter.

800
01:08:52,097 --> 01:08:54,391
I'm no writer.
You're the writer.

801
01:08:55,225 --> 01:08:57,060
- Please.
- Go. Go away.

802
01:08:57,102 --> 01:08:59,896
- Please.
- I mean it. Get out of here.

803
01:09:57,329 --> 01:09:58,914
Who is it?

804
01:10:02,167 --> 01:10:03,627
It's me.

805
01:10:05,629 --> 01:10:08,548
Mr. Don Birnam,
as I live and breathe.

806
01:10:08,632 --> 01:10:11,259
Only, if you're coming for our date,
you're a little late, aren't you?

807
01:10:11,343 --> 01:10:15,180
If you're coming to apologize,
no, thanks. Thanks, but no, thanks.

808
01:10:15,263 --> 01:10:18,975
Save your saliva. I've had enough
of you. Deaf, but deaf.

809
01:10:19,017 --> 01:10:21,478
What do you think I am?
I break a business date.

810
01:10:21,520 --> 01:10:24,106
I buy me an evening purse,
a facial, a new hairdo.

811
01:10:24,189 --> 01:10:26,274
You can do that to your ritzy
friends, but you can't to me.

812
01:10:26,358 --> 01:10:28,193
- Understand?
- Gloria.

813
01:10:28,276 --> 01:10:31,988
Okay, what do you want,
Mr. Don Birnam, Esquire?

814
01:10:33,115 --> 01:10:35,283
I need some money.

815
01:10:35,325 --> 01:10:38,161
- You what?
- Could you let me have some money?

816
01:10:38,245 --> 01:10:41,707
Say, you out of your mind?
Don't be ''ridic.''

817
01:10:41,790 --> 01:10:44,459
Get out of here.
Make with those stairs. Go on.

818
01:10:54,177 --> 01:10:57,848
I waited half the night, like
it was the first date I ever had.

819
01:10:59,391 --> 01:11:01,685
The other half I was crying.

820
01:11:04,730 --> 01:11:09,568
- How much money?
- Could you let me have ten or five?

821
01:11:09,651 --> 01:11:11,194
I'll see.

822
01:11:22,789 --> 01:11:26,752
You look awfully sick, Mr. Birnam.
Have you got a fever or something?

823
01:11:26,835 --> 01:11:28,754
I'm all right now.

824
01:11:30,213 --> 01:11:33,759
Thank you a lot.
You do like me a little, don't you?

825
01:11:33,842 --> 01:11:35,927
Why, natch, Gloria.
Natch.

826
01:11:38,430 --> 01:11:40,557
Gloria,
who have you got out there?

827
01:11:40,640 --> 01:11:42,059
Coming.

828
01:11:43,268 --> 01:11:46,104
<i>It's a hap-hap-happy day</i>

829
01:12:47,874 --> 01:12:50,127
What's this place?

830
01:12:51,169 --> 01:12:54,464
Hey, what is this place?

831
01:12:55,340 --> 01:12:57,801
I'm talking to you.

832
01:13:01,096 --> 01:13:04,016
Good morning, Merry Sunshine.
How's your head?

833
01:13:04,099 --> 01:13:06,101
Where am I?
What is this place?

834
01:13:06,184 --> 01:13:08,103
This? This is Hangover Plaza.

835
01:13:08,186 --> 01:13:10,564
- What hospital is this?
- Alcoholic ward.

836
01:13:10,647 --> 01:13:12,733
- How's your head?
- It aches.

837
01:13:12,816 --> 01:13:14,901
Thought you had a fracture
till we looked at the X rays.

838
01:13:14,985 --> 01:13:17,779
Everything in one piece.
just a slight concussion.

839
01:13:17,863 --> 01:13:19,698
Why'd they put me
in the alcoholic ward?

840
01:13:19,781 --> 01:13:22,576
Are you kidding? We got a peek
at your blood. Straight applejack.

841
01:13:22,659 --> 01:13:24,161
96 proof.

842
01:13:24,202 --> 01:13:26,872
- What day is it?
- Sunday. Are these yours?

843
01:13:26,955 --> 01:13:29,332
You and the colored fellow
were being undressed at the same time.

844
01:13:29,374 --> 01:13:33,378
- They fell out of somebody's pants.
- They're mine. You a doctor?

845
01:13:33,462 --> 01:13:37,299
I'm a nurse, name of Nolan.
They call me Bim.

846
01:13:37,382 --> 01:13:41,636
- Call me Bim. What's your name?
- Birnam.

847
01:13:41,720 --> 01:13:44,306
- What kind of Birnam?
- Don Birnam.

848
01:13:44,389 --> 01:13:47,726
- Where do you live?
- 209 East Vir--

849
01:13:47,768 --> 01:13:51,063
- What do you need that for?
- For the postcard.

850
01:13:51,146 --> 01:13:53,065
- What postcard?
- To your folks, so they know...

851
01:13:53,106 --> 01:13:56,276
where honey boy is and can pick
him up when he's feeling better.

852
01:13:56,360 --> 01:13:58,195
No address.

853
01:13:58,278 --> 01:14:02,282
We'll get it out of the phone book
or the directory or your wallet.

854
01:14:02,366 --> 01:14:04,910
Look. No postcard,
understand?

855
01:14:04,993 --> 01:14:08,413
- Nobody's gonna pick me up.
- The management insists.

856
01:14:08,455 --> 01:14:11,083
If we let you guys go home alone,
a lot of you don't go home.

857
01:14:11,166 --> 01:14:14,169
You just hit the nearest bar
and bounce right back again--

858
01:14:14,252 --> 01:14:16,546
what we call the ''quick ricochet.''

859
01:14:16,630 --> 01:14:19,466
I'm as well as you are.
I can get out of here right now.

860
01:14:19,549 --> 01:14:21,218
- Think so?
- Where are my clothes?

861
01:14:21,259 --> 01:14:23,845
- Downstairs.
- How do I get out?

862
01:14:23,929 --> 01:14:25,847
Right through there.

863
01:14:40,862 --> 01:14:43,990
- Where do you think you're going?
- To get my clothes.

864
01:14:44,074 --> 01:14:46,743
- Got your discharge?
- My what?

865
01:14:46,785 --> 01:14:49,705
- Your release.
- I'm all right. Let me out.

866
01:14:50,872 --> 01:14:53,917
- Get back there. Go on.
- Keep your hands off me!

867
01:14:58,922 --> 01:15:00,841
Come here, Birnam.

868
01:15:02,467 --> 01:15:07,431
- Is this a jail?
- Halfway hospital, halfway jail.

869
01:15:07,472 --> 01:15:09,725
Listen, Bim. In my clothes,
there's five dollars.

870
01:15:09,808 --> 01:15:12,561
That's all for you, if only
you won't send that postcard.

871
01:15:12,644 --> 01:15:15,022
- Nothing doing.
- I don't want anybody to know.

872
01:15:15,105 --> 01:15:17,315
Your folks might as well
get used to our little postcards.

873
01:15:17,399 --> 01:15:19,818
- What are you talking about?
- There'll be more of'em.

874
01:15:19,901 --> 01:15:22,112
- You'll be back.
- Oh, shut up!

875
01:15:23,697 --> 01:15:26,241
Listen. I can pick an alkie
with one eye shut.

876
01:15:26,324 --> 01:15:29,953
You're an alkie.
You'll come back. They all do.

877
01:15:30,037 --> 01:15:34,124
Him, for instance. Shows up
every month,just like the gas bill.

878
01:15:34,166 --> 01:15:38,378
And the one with the glasses.
Another repeater. His 45th trip.

879
01:15:38,462 --> 01:15:40,630
Big executive
in the advertising business.

880
01:15:40,672 --> 01:15:44,468
Lovely fellow.
Been coming here since 1 927.

881
01:15:44,509 --> 01:15:48,388
Good old Prohibition days.
You should've seen the joint then.

882
01:15:48,472 --> 01:15:51,475
This is nothing. Back then,
we really had a turnover.

883
01:15:51,558 --> 01:15:53,268
Standing room only.

884
01:15:53,352 --> 01:15:56,605
Prohibition: That's what
started most of these guys off.

885
01:15:56,688 --> 01:15:58,899
Now, be a good boy
and drink this.

886
01:15:58,982 --> 01:16:01,401
- I don't want it.
- Better take it.

887
01:16:01,485 --> 01:16:03,945
Liable to be a little floor show
later on around here.

888
01:16:04,029 --> 01:16:06,823
- Might get on your nerves.
- Floor show?

889
01:16:06,865 --> 01:16:08,867
- Ever have the D.T.'s?
- No.

890
01:16:08,950 --> 01:16:10,869
- You will, brother.
- Not me.

891
01:16:10,952 --> 01:16:14,039
Like to make a little bet?
After all, you're just a freshman.

892
01:16:14,122 --> 01:16:17,626
Wait till you're a sophomore. That's
when you start seeing animals.

893
01:16:17,709 --> 01:16:21,046
You know that stuff
about pink elephants? That's bunk.

894
01:16:21,088 --> 01:16:25,258
It's little animals,
little turkeys in straw hats.

895
01:16:25,342 --> 01:16:28,637
Midget monkeys
coming through the keyholes.

896
01:16:28,720 --> 01:16:32,432
See that guy over there?
With him, it's beetles.

897
01:16:32,516 --> 01:16:35,644
Come the night, he sees beetles
crawling all over him.

898
01:16:36,728 --> 01:16:38,689
Has to be dark, though.

899
01:16:38,730 --> 01:16:41,441
It's like the doctor
was just telling me:

900
01:16:41,525 --> 01:16:44,277
Delirium is a disease
of the night.

901
01:16:45,362 --> 01:16:46,947
Good night.

902
01:17:50,677 --> 01:17:52,471
Get the restraints and the doctor!

903
01:18:24,461 --> 01:18:26,546
Get him up
to the violent ward.

904
01:18:30,050 --> 01:18:31,802
Over here, Doctor.

905
01:18:53,198 --> 01:18:55,283
Violent ward.
Get the elevator.

906
01:20:56,196 --> 01:20:58,115
- Good morning.
- Shh.

907
01:21:02,786 --> 01:21:06,748
Anything wrong up there?
Anything wrong?

908
01:21:08,917 --> 01:21:11,837
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine, thank you.

909
01:21:11,878 --> 01:21:15,757
- Have you been there all night?
- I've been waiting for Mr. Birnam.

910
01:21:15,841 --> 01:21:17,843
I suppose he stayed overnight
with friends.

911
01:21:17,884 --> 01:21:21,888
- He has friends in Long Island.
- What kind of story's that?

912
01:21:21,972 --> 01:21:24,349
- I beg your pardon?
- I'm his landlady.

913
01:21:24,391 --> 01:21:27,102
I know what goes on in this house.
I know Mr. Don Birnam.

914
01:21:27,185 --> 01:21:30,939
I knew all about him the first week
they moved here five years ago.

915
01:21:31,023 --> 01:21:33,233
Heard those bottles
rattle in the garbage can.

916
01:21:33,316 --> 01:21:36,153
I know all about you.
You're Helen St.James.

917
01:21:36,236 --> 01:21:39,281
<i>You're working on Time magazine,
and you're his best girl.</i>

918
01:21:39,364 --> 01:21:43,076
I also know he's not staying
with any friends in Long Island.

919
01:21:43,160 --> 01:21:45,829
He's off on another toot,
and you know I'm darned right.

920
01:21:45,912 --> 01:21:47,831
Now, come on down,
and I'll make you some breakfast.

921
01:21:47,914 --> 01:21:52,336
I don't care for breakfast nor that
talk, even supposing you're right.

922
01:21:52,419 --> 01:21:55,380
Which I am. I could've
kicked him out 50 times--

923
01:21:55,464 --> 01:21:58,133
the last when two taxi drivers
dumped him into the entrance hall...

924
01:21:58,216 --> 01:22:01,595
out cold on the floor with
all my tenants going in and out...

925
01:22:01,678 --> 01:22:03,180
and children leaving
for school!

926
01:22:03,263 --> 01:22:05,390
- Please!
- Well, I didn't put him out...

927
01:22:05,474 --> 01:22:07,476
not as long as his brother
could pay the rent.

928
01:22:07,559 --> 01:22:09,978
You couldn't help liking him anyway,
he was so good looking.

929
01:22:10,062 --> 01:22:13,023
He had such nice manners.
He always had a little joke.

930
01:22:13,106 --> 01:22:15,192
Stop talking about him
as if he were dead.

931
01:22:16,651 --> 01:22:18,653
Best thing for you
if he was!

932
01:23:18,922 --> 01:23:20,424
Quarter rye, quick.

933
01:23:20,507 --> 01:23:22,509
- Okay if I take off my coat?
- No!

934
01:23:25,762 --> 01:23:28,473
No cracks. No questions.
just a quarter rye.

935
01:23:38,692 --> 01:23:41,987
- Be 2.1 5.
- Come on. I need that liquor.

936
01:23:42,029 --> 01:23:44,865
I want it, and I'm going to get it,
understand?

937
01:23:44,948 --> 01:23:48,326
I'm going to walk out with that
quarter rye, one way or another.

938
01:26:22,147 --> 01:26:25,317
Miss St.James?
He's back. He's upstairs.

939
01:26:25,400 --> 01:26:28,945
This is Mrs. Deveridge.
Yes, he's back up in his apartment.

940
01:26:29,029 --> 01:26:30,614
I heard him yelling.

941
01:26:43,460 --> 01:26:45,379
Open the door. Please.

942
01:26:48,131 --> 01:26:51,134
Don, won't you let me in? I know
you're there. Please open the door.

943
01:26:53,679 --> 01:26:55,972
Don, don't you hear me?
I want to help you.

944
01:26:58,100 --> 01:27:00,602
Don, I won't go away.
Do I have to go down...

945
01:27:00,644 --> 01:27:02,979
and get the janitor
with the passkey to let me in?

946
01:27:08,235 --> 01:27:09,528
Dave?

947
01:27:10,612 --> 01:27:13,073
- Yes, Mrs. Deveridge?
- Come on up with the passkey.

948
01:27:13,156 --> 01:27:14,616
Come on.

949
01:28:07,210 --> 01:28:09,171
- Thank you very much.
- You'd better let us come too.

950
01:28:09,212 --> 01:28:12,632
- You can't go in there alone.
- I'll be all right. Thank you.

951
01:28:12,674 --> 01:28:14,760
Come, Sophie. Let's go.

952
01:28:23,852 --> 01:28:26,104
- Don, darling.
- Go away, Helen.

953
01:28:26,188 --> 01:28:29,232
- I'm here to help you, darling.
- No, no.

954
01:28:30,484 --> 01:28:35,655
Look at you. You want to get up,
Don. Put your arm on my shoulder.

955
01:28:51,171 --> 01:28:53,548
You'll have a bath,
and I'll help you shave...

956
01:28:53,632 --> 01:28:55,634
and you'll eat and sleep...

957
01:28:55,717 --> 01:28:58,929
and when Wick comes back,
everything'll be all right.

958
01:28:59,012 --> 01:29:00,764
No! Don't!

959
01:29:00,847 --> 01:29:03,558
- What's the matter?
- That wall.

960
01:29:03,642 --> 01:29:06,353
- What wall?
- The mouse and the bat.

961
01:29:06,436 --> 01:29:09,898
- ''The mouse and the bat''?
- That hole in the wall behind you.

962
01:29:13,151 --> 01:29:15,404
- There's no hole in the wall.
- Yes, there is.

963
01:29:15,487 --> 01:29:20,325
There isn't. Don,
please look for yourself. Come on.

964
01:29:20,409 --> 01:29:22,536
Come on, Don. Please look.

965
01:29:35,757 --> 01:29:37,259
See?

966
01:29:41,596 --> 01:29:43,932
Everything's going to be all right.
I'll stay right with you.

967
01:29:43,974 --> 01:29:49,479
It's little animals,
always little animals, Bim said.

968
01:29:50,856 --> 01:29:53,233
You're not
making much sense, Don.

969
01:29:53,275 --> 01:29:55,777
You know what Nat
said about the ending?

970
01:29:57,154 --> 01:29:59,239
Like this...

971
01:29:59,281 --> 01:30:01,742
or like that.

972
01:30:01,783 --> 01:30:04,619
Like this or like that.

973
01:30:43,617 --> 01:30:46,244
Where are you going,
Don? Don?

974
01:31:05,681 --> 01:31:08,016
- Give me the pawn ticket.
- No scene, please.

975
01:31:08,100 --> 01:31:09,726
just give me the ticket.

976
01:31:09,810 --> 01:31:12,145
I don't want you to go in and
claim it now. It would look queer.

977
01:31:12,187 --> 01:31:14,106
You're ashamed of what
the pawnbroker thinks, is that it?

978
01:31:14,147 --> 01:31:16,608
- It doesn't matter what I think.
- Wick'll get you back your coat.

979
01:31:16,650 --> 01:31:20,112
You couldn't have taken my bracelet
or my paycheck? It had to be that!

980
01:31:20,195 --> 01:31:23,323
The one that brought us together?
Stop being sentimental.

981
01:31:23,407 --> 01:31:26,576
I have, Don. I assure you.
It's finished. It's dead.

982
01:31:26,660 --> 01:31:28,495
For three years,
they couldn't talk me out of you.

983
01:31:28,578 --> 01:31:30,622
I was the only one
that really understood you.

984
01:31:30,664 --> 01:31:33,291
I knew there was a core
of something. Well, there is.

985
01:31:33,375 --> 01:31:35,836
And now I know
what it is: a sponge.

986
01:31:35,919 --> 01:31:39,089
To soak it full, you'll do anything
that's ruthless, selfish, dishonest.

987
01:31:39,172 --> 01:31:41,299
- I asked you not to make a scene.
- Then give me the ticket.

988
01:31:41,383 --> 01:31:43,385
- Not now. Please.
- I don't want the money!

989
01:31:43,468 --> 01:31:45,762
You can get as drunk as you like
for all I care!

990
01:31:46,763 --> 01:31:48,348
Thank you.

991
01:31:59,651 --> 01:32:02,362
A gentleman came in a while ago.
How much did you give him for that?

992
01:32:02,446 --> 01:32:04,489
- Why?
- I want it back. It's my coat.

993
01:32:04,573 --> 01:32:06,324
- It's your coat?
- It's all right. He had permission.

994
01:32:06,366 --> 01:32:08,368
- How much did you give him?
- He didn't want any money.

995
01:32:08,452 --> 01:32:10,829
- He wanted to swap it.
- Swap it? For what?

996
01:32:10,871 --> 01:32:13,206
Something he hocked here
a long while back.

997
01:32:13,290 --> 01:32:15,292
- What?
- A gun.

998
01:32:18,211 --> 01:32:19,671
A gun.

999
01:32:21,715 --> 01:32:23,842
Now, if you want the coat back,
I can--

1000
01:33:24,903 --> 01:33:26,822
What is it, Helen?

1001
01:33:29,324 --> 01:33:31,284
What's the matter?

1002
01:33:33,787 --> 01:33:35,247
Nothing.

1003
01:33:36,373 --> 01:33:38,375
Dave gave me the keys.
I didn't think you were here.

1004
01:33:41,878 --> 01:33:46,008
- What do you want here?
- I couldn't get a taxi.

1005
01:33:46,091 --> 01:33:49,928
I thought I could borrow a coat
under the circumstances.

1006
01:33:49,970 --> 01:33:52,472
Sure. How about my raincoat?

1007
01:33:58,437 --> 01:34:01,815
Funny that we should wind up after
all these years just as we met.

1008
01:34:01,898 --> 01:34:04,526
- I with your raincoat.
- And I with your leopard coat.

1009
01:34:05,610 --> 01:34:08,155
I always get the best
of the bargain.

1010
01:34:08,238 --> 01:34:09,823
Good-bye, Helen.

1011
01:34:12,534 --> 01:34:15,370
- What are you looking for?
- I thought perhaps...

1012
01:34:15,454 --> 01:34:17,581
maybe you might
have something for my hair.

1013
01:34:17,664 --> 01:34:21,418
- Would you care to wear my derby?
- Any old thing. Any old scarf.

1014
01:34:21,501 --> 01:34:22,919
All right.

1015
01:34:39,311 --> 01:34:41,563
- Here you are.
- Thank you.

1016
01:34:41,646 --> 01:34:43,065
So long.

1017
01:34:44,524 --> 01:34:47,652
There was some whiskey left
in the bottle after I cleaned up.

1018
01:34:47,736 --> 01:34:51,490
- Was there?
- Like to know where I put it?

1019
01:34:51,531 --> 01:34:53,784
- Don't you want a drink, Don?
- No.

1020
01:34:57,204 --> 01:35:01,708
Here it is. Right here.
Why don't you have one? Just one.

1021
01:35:01,792 --> 01:35:05,003
- What are you up to?
- Nothing.

1022
01:35:05,045 --> 01:35:06,922
I'm just ashamed of the way
I talked to you--

1023
01:35:07,005 --> 01:35:10,384
like a narrow-minded, insensitive
small-town teetotaler.

1024
01:35:10,467 --> 01:35:12,427
I told you I don't feel
like a drink. Not now.

1025
01:35:12,511 --> 01:35:14,888
Come on, Don.Just one.
I'll have one with you.

1026
01:35:14,971 --> 01:35:17,057
I'm in no hurry.
This is my easy day at the office.

1027
01:35:17,140 --> 01:35:20,435
Helen, there are a few things I want
to put in order before Wick comes.

1028
01:35:20,519 --> 01:35:23,021
Let me stay. Please.

1029
01:35:26,483 --> 01:35:29,236
I don't want to sound rude,
but I'm afraid you'll have to leave.

1030
01:35:30,654 --> 01:35:34,491
- Here, Don.
- You're very sweet.

1031
01:35:37,077 --> 01:35:38,537
Good-bye.

1032
01:35:40,956 --> 01:35:43,583
- Don't let me bend for nothing.
- You need this, Don. Drink it.

1033
01:35:43,667 --> 01:35:47,087
I want you to drink it. I'll get you
more. I'll get you all you want.

1034
01:35:47,170 --> 01:35:51,925
- What kind of talk is that?
- I'd rather you be drunk than dead.

1035
01:35:54,469 --> 01:35:57,556
- Who wants to be dead?
- Stop lying to me.

1036
01:36:01,226 --> 01:36:03,145
Give it to me!

1037
01:36:08,108 --> 01:36:10,068
All right. Now, go.
No fuss, please.

1038
01:36:10,152 --> 01:36:12,571
And don't call the neighbors.
It won't do any good, I promise.

1039
01:36:12,612 --> 01:36:15,198
I won't.
You've made up your mind.

1040
01:36:15,282 --> 01:36:17,200
But could you tell me why? Why?

1041
01:36:17,284 --> 01:36:19,661
'Cause it's best for everybody:
for you, Wick and for me.

1042
01:36:19,745 --> 01:36:24,624
- That's not true. We love you.
- Then for me. Selfish again.

1043
01:36:24,708 --> 01:36:27,127
- That's a sad final word, Don.
- Look at it this way:

1044
01:36:27,210 --> 01:36:29,880
This business is a formality.
Don Birnam is dead already.

1045
01:36:29,963 --> 01:36:32,966
- He died over this weekend.
- Did he? What did he die of?

1046
01:36:33,050 --> 01:36:36,094
A lot of things. Of alcohol.
Of moral anemia.

1047
01:36:36,178 --> 01:36:40,932
- Of fear, shame, D.T.'s!
- Oh, that Don Birnam!

1048
01:36:40,974 --> 01:36:43,101
-And now you want to kill the other?
-What other?

1049
01:36:43,185 --> 01:36:46,188
There were two Dons. You told me:
Don the drunk and Don the writer.

1050
01:36:46,855 --> 01:36:51,443
Let's not go back to a fancy figure
of speech. There's only one Don.

1051
01:36:51,526 --> 01:36:53,570
He's through.

1052
01:36:53,653 --> 01:36:55,989
I'm all right.
I still have enough strength left.

1053
01:36:56,073 --> 01:36:59,701
I know you have. I can see it.
Don't waste it by pulling a trigger.

1054
01:36:59,785 --> 01:37:03,413
Let me get it over. You want me to
give another promise I can't keep?

1055
01:37:03,497 --> 01:37:05,791
I don't want your promise. I don't
want you to give your promise...

1056
01:37:05,832 --> 01:37:07,417
to anybody but Don Birnam.

1057
01:37:07,501 --> 01:37:09,628
It's too late!
I wouldn't know how to start!

1058
01:37:09,711 --> 01:37:13,965
The only way to start is to stop.
There is no cure besides stopping.

1059
01:37:14,007 --> 01:37:16,134
- Can't be done.
- Other people have stopped.

1060
01:37:16,218 --> 01:37:18,345
People with a purpose,
with something to do!

1061
01:37:18,428 --> 01:37:21,264
-But you've got talent and ambition!
-Talent! Ambition!

1062
01:37:21,348 --> 01:37:23,600
That's dead long ago.
That's drowned.

1063
01:37:23,684 --> 01:37:26,561
That's drifting around with a
bloated belly in a lake of alcohol.

1064
01:37:26,645 --> 01:37:28,605
No, it isn't.
You still have it.

1065
01:37:28,689 --> 01:37:30,691
Quit trying to stall me, Helen.
It's too late.

1066
01:37:30,774 --> 01:37:33,360
There's no more writing left in me.
What do you expect? A miracle?

1067
01:37:33,443 --> 01:37:36,196
Yes! If I could
just make you un--

1068
01:37:36,196 --> 01:37:36,446
Yes! If I could
just make you un--

1069
01:37:36,530 --> 01:37:38,699
- Who is it?
- It's me, Mr. Birnam.

1070
01:37:38,782 --> 01:37:42,619
- What is it, Nat?
- I got something for you.

1071
01:37:45,664 --> 01:37:47,457
- I hope I ain't intrudin'.
- What is it?

1072
01:37:48,166 --> 01:37:50,961
You know when you had that accident?
Afterward, I found this floating...

1073
01:37:51,044 --> 01:37:52,713
around on the Nile.

1074
01:37:52,796 --> 01:37:54,673
She writes good.
I oiled her up a little.

1075
01:37:54,715 --> 01:37:57,509
And I didn't oil her up
so you can hock her.

1076
01:37:59,261 --> 01:38:01,430
- I'll take it, Nat.
- Hello, miss.

1077
01:38:03,181 --> 01:38:06,643
- Thank you, Nat.
- How are them lilacs in Ohio?

1078
01:38:10,147 --> 01:38:12,524
Well, Don, here it is.
What do you say now?

1079
01:38:12,566 --> 01:38:14,568
- Say about what?
- This.

1080
01:38:14,609 --> 01:38:17,404
Someone somewhere sent it back. Why?
Because he means you to stay alive.

1081
01:38:17,487 --> 01:38:20,407
Because he wants you to write.
I didn't ask for a big miracle.

1082
01:38:20,449 --> 01:38:23,035
Write with these hands
and a brain all out of focus?

1083
01:38:23,076 --> 01:38:24,661
It'll clear up again.

1084
01:38:24,745 --> 01:38:27,372
And I'll be sitting there staring
at that white sheet, scared.

1085
01:38:27,414 --> 01:38:30,250
No, you won't. You've forgotten
what it feels like to be well.

1086
01:38:30,334 --> 01:38:33,879
- What am I going to write about?
- What you've always wanted.

1087
01:38:33,962 --> 01:38:38,884
<i>- Where was the page I found?
- The Bottle. A novel by Don Birnam.</i>

1088
01:38:38,925 --> 01:38:41,178
- What was that to be?
- About a messed-up life.

1089
01:38:41,261 --> 01:38:43,180
About a man and a woman
and a bottle.

1090
01:38:43,263 --> 01:38:45,390
About nightmares, horrors,
humiliations--

1091
01:38:45,432 --> 01:38:47,184
all the things
I want to forget.

1092
01:38:47,267 --> 01:38:49,311
Put it all down on paper.
Get rid of it that way.

1093
01:38:49,394 --> 01:38:51,355
Tell it all:
''To whom it may concern.''

1094
01:38:51,438 --> 01:38:54,858
- And it concerns so many.
- Yeah.

1095
01:38:55,942 --> 01:38:58,195
I'll fix us some breakfast.

1096
01:38:59,738 --> 01:39:01,656
We have quite a supply
of milk.

1097
01:39:04,201 --> 01:39:07,412
You'll notice
I didn't even find the first line.

1098
01:39:07,496 --> 01:39:10,540
You couldn't write the beginning
because you didn't know the ending.

1099
01:39:10,624 --> 01:39:12,542
Only, now--

1100
01:39:28,809 --> 01:39:30,727
Only, now you know the ending.

1101
01:39:33,772 --> 01:39:35,857
I'm going to send one copy
to Bim...

1102
01:39:35,941 --> 01:39:37,943
one to the doctor
who loaned me his coat...

1103
01:39:38,026 --> 01:39:40,487
and one to Nat.

1104
01:39:40,570 --> 01:39:43,407
Imagine Wick
standing in front of a bookstore.

1105
01:39:43,448 --> 01:39:48,328
Great, big pyramid of books,
and a novel by Don Birnam.

1106
01:39:48,412 --> 01:39:51,164
- ''That's by my brother, you know.''
- ''That's by my fellow.

1107
01:39:51,248 --> 01:39:55,961
- Didn't I always tell you?''
- I'm gonna put this weekend down.

1108
01:39:56,044 --> 01:40:00,465
- Why not?
- The way I stood in there, packing.

1109
01:40:00,549 --> 01:40:03,051
Only, my mind wasn't
on the suitcase.

1110
01:40:03,135 --> 01:40:05,262
It wasn't on the weekend.

1111
01:40:05,345 --> 01:40:08,306
<i>Nor was it on the shirts I was
putting in the suitcase, either.</i>

1112
01:40:09,599 --> 01:40:12,436
<i>My mind was hanging
outside the window.</i>

1113
01:40:12,477 --> 01:40:15,731
<i>It was suspended
just about 1 8 inches below.</i>

1114
01:40:17,399 --> 01:40:20,110
<i>And out there in that
great, big concrete jungle...</i>

1115
01:40:20,193 --> 01:40:23,238
<i>I wonder how many others
there are like me--</i>

1116
01:40:23,321 --> 01:40:27,284
<i>poor, bedeviled guys
on fire with thirst--</i>

1117
01:40:27,325 --> 01:40:29,453
<i>such comical figures
to the rest of the world...</i>

1118
01:40:29,494 --> 01:40:32,497
<i>as they stagger blindly
towards another binge...</i>

1119
01:40:32,539 --> 01:40:35,625
<i>another bender,
another spree.</i>

