Hello.
My name's Forrest. Forrest Gump.
Do you want a chocolate?
I could eat about
a million and a half of these.
My mama always said
life was like a box of chocolates.
You never know what you're gonna get.
Those must be comfortable shoes.
I'll bet you could walk all day
in shoes like that and not feel a thing.
I wish I had shoes like that.
My feet hurt.
Mama always said there's an awful lot
you could tell about a person
by their shoes:
where they're going,
where they've been.
I've worn lots of shoes.
I bet if I think about it real hard,
I could remember my first pair of shoes.
Mama said they'd take me anywhere.
She said they was my magic shoes.
All right, Forrest,
you can open your eyes now.
Let's take a little walk around.
How do those feel?
His legs are strong, Mrs. Gump,
as strong as I've ever seen,
but his back is as crooked
as a politician.
But we're gonna straighten him right up,
now, aren't we, Forrest?
Forrest!
Now, when I was a baby,
Mama named me after
the great Civil War hero,
General Nathan Bedford Forrest.
She said we was related to him
in some way.
And what he did was,
he started up this club called
the Ku Klux Klan.
They'd all dress up in their robes
and their bed sheets
and act like a bunch of ghosts
or spooks or something.
They'd even put bed sheets
on their horses and ride around.
And anyway, that's how I got my name,
Forrest Gump.
Mama said that the "Forrest" part
was to remind me that sometimes
we all do things that,
well, just don't make no sense.
Okay... Get it, get it...
Wait, is it this way? Hold on.
All right...
What are you all staring at?
Haven't you ever seen a little boy
with braces on his legs before?
Don't ever let anybody tell you
they're better than you, Forrest.
lf God intended
everybody to be the same,
he'd have given us all braces
on our legs.
Mama always had a way of explaining
things so I could understand them.
We lived about a quarter mile
off Route 17,
about a half mile from
the town of Greenbow, Alabama.
That's in the county of Greenbow.
Our house had been in Mama's family
since her grandpa's grandpa's grandpa
had come across the ocean
about 1,000 years ago,
something like that.
Since it was just me and Mama
and we had all these empty rooms,
Mama decided to let those rooms out,
mostly to people passing through,
like from, oh, Mobile,
Montgomery, places like that.
That's how me and Mama got money.
Mama was a real smart lady.
Remember what I told you, Forrest.
You're no different than anybody else is.
Did you hear what I said, Forrest?
You're the same as everybody else.
You are no different.
Your boy's different, Mrs. Gump.
Now, his IQ is 75.
Well, we're all different, Mr. Hancock.
She wanted me to have
the finest education,
so she took me to
the Greenbow County Central School.
I met the principal and all.
I want to show you something,
Mrs. Gump.
Now, this is normal.
Forrest is right here.
The state requires a minimum IQ of
80 to attend public school, Mrs. Gump.
He's gonna have to go
to a special school.
Now, he'll be just fine.
What does "normal" mean, anyway?
He might be a bit on the slow side,
but my boy Forrest is gonna get
the same opportunities
as everyone else.
He's not going to some special school
to learn how to re-tread tires.
We're talking about
five little points here.
There must be something can be done.
We're a progressive school system.
We don't want to see anybody
left behind.
Is there a Mr. Gump, Mrs. Gump?
He's on vacation.
Well, your mama sure does care
about your schooling, son.
You don't say much, do you?
"Finally, he had to try.
"It looked easy, but,
"oh, what happened.
-"First, there..."
-Mama, what's "vacation" mean?
-Vacation?
-Where Daddy went.
Vacation's when you go somewhere
and you don't ever come back.
Anyway, I guess you could say
me and Mama was on our own.
But we didn't mind.
Our house was never empty.
There was always folks
coming and going.
Supper.
-It's supper, everyone. Forrest...
-My, my. That sure looks special.
Sometimes we had
so many people staying with us
that every room
was filled with travelers.
You know, folks living out
of their suitcases
and hat cases and sample cases.
Forrest Gump, it's suppertime!
Forrest...
One time, a young man
was staying with us,
and he had him a guitar case.
Forrest! I told you not to bother
this nice young man.
Oh, no, that's all right, ma'am.
I was just showing him a thing or two
on the guitar here.
All right, but your supper's ready
if y'all want to eat.
Yeah, that sounds good.
Thank you, ma'am.
Say, man, show me that crazy
little walk you just did there.
Slow it down some.
I liked that guitar.
It sounded good.
I started moving around to the music,
swinging my hips.
This one night,
me and Mama was out shopping,
and we walked right by
Benson's furniture and appliance store,
and guess what?
This is not for children's eyes.
Some years later,
that handsome young man
who they called "The King,"
well, he'd sung too many songs,
had himself a heart attack,
or something.
Must be hard being a king.
You know, it's funny how you remember
some things, but some things you can't.
-You do your very best now, Forrest.
-I sure will, Mama.
I remember the bus ride
on the first day of school very well.
Are you coming along?
Mama said not to be taking
rides from strangers.
This is the bus to school.
I'm Forrest. Forrest Gump.
-I'm Dorothy Harris.
-Well, now we ain't strangers anymore.
This seat's taken.
It's taken!
You can't sit here.
You know, it's funny what
a young man recollects,
'cause I don't remember being born.
I don't recall what I got
for my first Christmas,
and I don't know when I went
on my first outdoor picnic.
But I do remember the first time I heard
the sweetest voice in the wide world.
You can sit here if you want.
I had never seen anything
so beautiful in my life.
She was like an angel.
Well, are you gonna sit down,
or aren't you?
What's wrong with your legs?
Nothing at all, thank you.
My legs are just fine and dandy.
I just sat next to her on that bus
and had a conversation
all the way to school.
...my back's crooked like
a question mark.
These are going to make me...
And next to Mama, no one ever
talked to me or asked me questions.
Are you stupid or something?
Mama says, "Stupid is as stupid does."
-I'm Jenny.
-I'm Forrest. Forrest Gump.
From that day on,
we was always together.
Jenny and me was like
peas and carrots.
She taught me how to climb.
Come on, Forrest, you can do it.
I showed her how to dangle.
"...a good little monkey and..."
She helped me learn how to read,
and I showed her how to swing.
Sometimes we'd just sit out
and wait for the stars.
-Mama's gonna worry about me.
-Just stay a little longer.
For some reason,
Jenny didn't never want to go home.
Okay, Jenny, I'll stay.
She was my most special friend.
My only friend.
Now, my mama always told me that
miracles happen every day.
Some people don't think so, but they do.
Hey, dummy!
Are you retarded, or just plain stupid?
-"Look, I'm Forrest Gimp."
-Just run away, Forrest.
Run, Forrest! Run away! Hurry!
-Get the bikes!
-Hurry up! Let's get him!
-Come on!
-Look out, dummy, here we come!
We're gonna get you!
Run, Forrest, run! Run, Forrest!
Come back here, you!
Run, Forrest!
Run!
Now, you wouldn't believe it
if I told you,
but I can run like the wind blows.
From that day on,
if I was going somewhere,
I was running!
He's getting away! Stop him!
That boy sure is a running fool.
Now, remember how I told you that
Jenny never seemed
to want to go home?
Well, she lived in a house
that was as old as Alabama.
Her mama had gone up to heaven
when she was five,
and her daddy was
some kind of a farmer.
Jenny?
He was a very loving man.
He was always kissing and touching
her and her sisters.
And then this one time,
Jenny wasn't on the bus to go to school.
Jenny, why didn't you come
to school today?
Daddy's taking a nap.
-Jenny!
-Come on!
Jenny, where'd you run to?
You'd better get back here, girl!
Where you at?
Jenny! Jenny! Where you at?
Jenny!
Pray with me, Forrest. Pray with me.
Dear God, make me a bird
so I can fly far,
far, far away from here.
Dear God, make me a bird
so I can fly far,
far, far away from here.
Mama always said
that God is mysterious.
Jenny!
He didn't turn Jenny into a bird that day.
You'd better get back here!
Instead,
he had the police say Jenny didn't
have to stay in that house no more.
She went to live with her grandma
just over on Creekmore Avenue,
which made me happy,
'cause she was so close.
Some nights, Jenny would sneak out
and come on over to my house,
just 'cause she said she was scared.
Scared of what, I don't know,
but I think it was her grandma's dog.
He was a mean dog.
Anyway, Jenny and me was best friends
all the way up through high school.
-Hey, stupid!
-Quit it!
-Run, Forrest, run!
-Hey,
did you hear me, stupid?
-Run, Forrest!
-Come on, get in the truck!
Get in the truck! Let's move it!
Come on, he's getting away! Move it!
Run, Forrest! Run!
-You better be running, stupid!
-Come on, dummy!
-Haul ass, dummy!
-Yeah, you better get running!
Jack rabbit!
Yeah!
Go! Go! Go!
Run, Forrest!
Now, it used to be,
I ran to get where I was going,
I never thought it would
take me anywhere.
-Who in the hell is that?
-That there is Forrest Gump, Coach.
Just a local idiot.
And can you believe it?
I got to go to college, too.
Forrest! Forrest! Run!
-Okay!
-Run!
Run, you stupid son of a bitch! Run!
You son of a bitch! Run! Go! Run!
No! Turn! Go!
He must be the stupidest
son of a bitch alive,
but he sure is fast!
Now, maybe it's just me,
but college was very confusing times.
Federal troops enforcing a court order
integrated the University
of Alabama today.
Two negroes were admitted,
but only after Governor George Wallace
had carried out his symbolic threat
to stand in the school house door.
Governor Wallace,
I take it from that statement, that...
Earl, what's going on?
-Coons are trying to get into school.
-Coons?
When raccoons try to get
on our back porch,
Mama just chase them off with a broom.
Not raccoons, you idiot, niggers,
and they want to go to school with us.
With us? They do?
Shortly after Governor Wallace
had carried out his promise
to block the doorway,
President Kennedy
ordered the Secretary of Defense
then to use military force.
Here, by videotape,
is the encounter by General Graham,
commander of the National Guard,
and Governor Wallace.
...because these National Guardsmen
are here today
as federal soldiers for Alabamans.
They live within our borders,
they are all our brothers.
We are winning in this fight,
because we are awakening
the American people
to the dangers that we have spoken
about so many times,
just so evident today, the trend towards
military dictatorship in this country.
And so, at day's end,
the University of Alabama
in Tuscaloosa had been desegregated
and students Jimmy Hood
and Vivian Malone
had been signed up
for summer classes.
Ma'am, you dropped your book.
Ma'am...
Governor Wallace did what
he promised to do.
By being on the Tuscaloosa campus,
he kept the mob from gathering...
Say, wasn't that Gump?
-Nah, that couldn't be.
-It sure as hell was.
A few years later, that angry little man
at the school house door
thought it would be a good idea
and ran for president.
But somebody thought that it wasn't.
But he didn't die.
My bus is here.
-Is it the number nine?
-No, it's the number four.
It was nice talking to you.
I remember when that happened,
when Wallace got shot.
I was in college.
Did you go to a girls' college,
or to a girls-and-boys-together college?
It was co-ed.
'Cause Jenny went to a college
I couldn't go to.
It was a college just for girls.
But I'd go and visit her
every chance I got.
That hurts.
Forrest! Forrest!
-Forrest, stop it! Stop it!
-Jesus!
What are you doing?
-He was hurting you.
-What the hell is going on here?
-No, he's not! Get over there!
-Who is that? Who is that?
-Billy, I'm sorry.
-What the hell?
-Just get away from me!
-Don't...
-Don't go! Billy, wait a second!
-Get away from me.
He doesn't know any better!
Forrest, why did you do that?
I brought you some chocolate.
I'm sorry.
-I'll go back to my college now.
-Forrest...
Look at you.
Come on. Come on.
Is this your room?
Do you ever dream, Forrest,
about who you're gonna be?
-Who I'm gonna be?
-Yeah.
Aren't I going to be me?
Well, you'll always be you,
just another kind of you.
You know? I want to be famous.
I want to be a singer like Joan Baez.
I just want to be on an empty stage
with my guitar, my voice.
Just me.
And I want to reach people
on the personal level.
I want to be able to say things,
just one-to-one.
Have you ever been with a girl, Forrest?
I sit next to them in my Home
Economics class all the time.
-I'm... Sorry.
-It's okay.
It's all right.
-Oh, I'm dizzy.
I bet that never happened in Home Ec.
No.
I think I ruined
your roommate's bathrobe.
I don't care. I don't like her, anyway.
Run! Run! Run!
-Run! Run! Run!
College ran by real fast,
'cause I played so much football.
They even put me on a thing
called the All-America Team,
where you get to meet
the President of the United States.
President Kennedy met
with the Collegiate
All-American Football Team
at the Oval Office today.
Now, the really good thing
about meeting
the President of the United States
is the food.
They put you in this little room
with just about anything
you'd want to eat or drink.
And since, number one,
I wasn't hungry, but thirsty,
and number two, they was free,
I must have drank me about
15 Dr. Peppers.
Congratulations.
How does it feel to be an All-American?
It's an honor, sir.
Congratulations.
How does it feel to be an All-American?
Very good, sir.
Congratulations.
How does it feel to be an All-American?
Very good, sir.
-Congratulations. How do you feel?
-I gotta pee.
I believe he said he had to "go pee."
Sometime later,
for no particular reason,
somebody shot that
nice young President,
when he was riding in his car.
And a few years after that,
somebody shot his little brother, too,
only he was in a hotel kitchen.
It must be hard being brothers.
I wouldn't know.
Forrest Gump.
Now can you believe it?
After only five years of playing football,
I got a college degree.
Congratulations, son.
Mama was so proud.
Forrest, I'm so proud of you.
Here, I'll hold this for you.
Congratulations, son.
Have you given any thought
to your future?
Thought?
Hello, I'm Forrest. Forrest Gump.
Nobody gives a hunk of shit
who you are, fuzzball!
You're not even a low-life,
scum-sucking maggot!
Get your faggotty ass on the bus.
You're in the Army now!
This seat's taken.
Taken.
At first, it seemed like I made a mistake,
seeing how it was only
my induction day
and I was already getting yelled at.
You can sit down if you want to.
I didn't know who I might meet,
or what they might ask.
You ever been on a real shrimp boat?
No, but I been on a real big boat.
I'm talking about
a shrimp-catching boat.
I've been working
on shrimp boats all my life.
I started out on my uncle's boat,
that's my mama's brother,
when I was about maybe nine.
I was just looking into buying a boat
of my own and got drafted.
My given name is Benjamin Buford Blue.
People call me Bubba.
Just like one of them old redneck boys.
Can you believe that?
My name's Forrest Gump.
People call me Forrest Gump.
So, Bubba was from
Bayou La Batre, Alabama,
and his mama cooked shrimp,
and her mama before her
cooked shrimp,
and her mama before her mama
cooked shrimp, too.
Bubba's family knew everything
there was to know
about the shrimping business.
I know everything there is to know
Matter of fact, I'm going into
the shrimping business for myself
after I get out the Army.
Okay.
Gump! What's your sole purpose
in this Army?
To do whatever you tell me,
Drill Sergeant!
God damn it, Gump!
You're a goddamn genius!
That's the most outstanding answer
I've ever heard.
You must have a goddamn IQ of 160!
You are goddamn gifted, Private Gump!
Listen up, people!
Now, for some reason, I fit in the Army
like one of them round pegs.
It's not really hard.
You just make your bed real neat
and remember to stand up straight,
and always answer every question
with, "Yes, Drill Sergeant!"
Is that clear?
-Yes, Drill Sergeant!
What you do is, you just drag
your nets along the bottom.
On a good day, you can catch over
100 pounds of shrimp.
lf everything goes all right,
two men shrimping 10 hours,
less what you spend on gas, you can...
-Done, Drill Sergeant!
-Gump!
Why did you put that weapon
together so quickly, Gump?
You told me to, Drill Sergeant.
Jesus H. Christ,
this is a new company record.
lf it wouldn't be a waste
of such a damn fine enlisted man,
I'd recommend you for OCS,
Private Gump.
You are gonna be
a general some day, Gump.
Now, disassemble your weapon
and continue!
Anyway, like I was saying,
shrimp is the fruit of the sea.
You can barbecue it,
boil it, broil it, bake it, sauté it.
There's shrimp kebabs, shrimp Creole...
...shrimp gumbo, pan fried,
deep fried, stir fried.
There's pineapple shrimp,
lemon shrimp,
coconut shrimp, pepper shrimp...
...shrimp soup, shrimp stew,
shrimp salad, shrimp and potatoes,
shrimp burger, shrimp sandwich...
That's... That's about it.
Night time in the Army is a lonely time.
We'd lay there in our bunks
and I'd miss my mama.
And I'd miss Jenny.
Hey, Gump, get a load of the tits on her!
Turns out, Jenny had gotten into
some trouble over
some photos of her
in her college sweater,
and she was thrown out of school.
But that wasn't a bad thing,
because a man who owns
a theater in Memphis, Tennessee,
saw those photos and offered Jenny
a job singing in a show.
The first chance I got,
I took the bus up to Memphis
to see her perform in that show.
That was Amber, Amber Flame.
Give her a big hand, guys.
Good job, Amber.
And now, for your listening
and viewing pleasure,
direct from Hollywood, California,
our very own beatnik beauty,
let's give a big round of applause
to the luscious Bobbi Dylan.
-All right!
-Bobbi!
Her dream had come true.
She was a folk singer.
Come on, baby. Shake it up.
Shake it up, now.
Hey, buddy, get her a harmonica.
Hey, honey, this ain't Captain Kangaroo.
Hey, honey,
I got something here for you.
-God damn it!
-Hey! Hey! Stupid jerk!
I'm singing a song here.
Polly, get out here!
-Shut up, there!
-Don't be so shy, honey.
Oh, shut up!
Forrest, what are you doing here?
-What are you doing?
-Hey!
-Come on.
-What are you doing?
Forrest, let me down!
You can't keep doing this, Forrest.
You can't keep trying
to rescue me all the time.
-They was trying to grab you.
-A lot of people try to grab me.
Just... You can't keep
doing this all the time.
I can't help it. I love you.
Forrest, you don't know what love is.
You remember that time
we prayed, Forrest?
We prayed for God to turn me
into a bird so I could fly far, far away?
Yes, I do.
You think I could fly off this bridge?
What do you mean, Jenny?
Nothing.
I gotta get out of here.
Wait, Jenny...
Forrest, you stay away from me, okay?
You just stay away from me, please.
Can I have a ride?
-Where you going?
-I don't care.
Get in the truck.
So, bye-bye, Jenny.
They sending me to Vietnam.
It's this whole other country.
Just hang on a minute.
Listen, you promise me
something, okay?
Just, if you're ever in trouble,
don't try to be brave. You just run, okay?
Just run away.
Okay.
Jenny.
I'll write you all the time.
And just like that, she was gone.
You come back safe to me,
do you hear?
Now, they told us that Vietnam
was gonna be very different
from the United States of America.
And except for all the beer cans
and the barbecue, it was.
Hey, I bet there's shrimp
all in these waters.
They tell me these Vietnams
are good shrimpers.
You know, after we win this war,
and we take over everything,
we can get American shrimpers
to come out here
and shrimp these waters.
We'll just shrimp all the time, man.
So much shrimp, why,
you wouldn't believe it.
You must be my FNGs.
-Morning, sir!
Get your hands down! Do not salute me.
There's goddamn snipers
all around this area
who would love to grease an officer.
I'm Lieutenant Dan Taylor.
Welcome to Fourth Platoon.
What's wrong with your lip?
I was born with big gums, sir.
Yeah, well, you better tuck that in.
Gonna get that caught on a trip wire.
Where you boys from in the world?
-Alabama, sir!
You twins?
No, we are not relations, sir.
Look, it's pretty basic here.
lf you stick with me
and learn from the guys
who've been in country a while,
you'll be all right.
There is one item of GI gear
that can be the difference between
a live grunt and a dead grunt.
Socks. Cushion sole, OD green.
Try and keep your feet dry.
When we're out humping,
I want you boys to remember
to change your socks
whenever we stop.
The Mekong will eat a grunt's feet
right off his legs.
Sergeant Sims, God damn it,
where is that sling rope
I told you to order?
I put in the requisitions at Battalion.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, well,
you call those sons of bitches again...
Lieutenant Dan sure knew his stuff.
I felt real lucky he was my lieutenant.
He was from a long,
great military tradition.
Somebody in his family
had fought and died
in every single American war.
-God damn it, kick some ass!
-I'm on it, Lieutenant.
Get on it!
I guess you could say he had
a lot to live up to.
So, you boys are from Arkansas, huh?
Well, I've been through there.
Little Rock's a fine town.
Now, go shake down your gear,
see the platoon sergeant,
draw what you need for the field.
lf you boys are hungry,
we got steaks burning right over here.
Two standing orders in this platoon:
one, take good care of your feet,
two, try not to do anything stupid,
like getting yourself killed.
I sure hope I don't let him down.
I got to see a lot of the countryside.
We would take these real long walks.
And we were always looking
for this guy named Charlie.
-Hold it up!
-Hold up, boys!
It wasn't always fun.
Lieutenant Dan was always getting
these funny feelings about a rock,
or a trail, or the road,
so he'd tell us to get down, shut up...
Get down! Shut up!
...so we did.
Now, I don't know much about anything,
but I think some of America's
best young men served in this war.
There was Dallas, from Phoenix,
Cleveland, he was from Detroit.
Hey, Tex. Hey, Tex.
Man, what the hell's going on?
And Tex was... Well, I don't remember
where Tex come from.
Nothing.
Fourth Platoon, on your feet.
Still got 10 clicks to go to that river.
Move out.
Come on, move out.
Step it up. Look alive out there.
The good thing about Vietnam
is there was always some place to go.
Fire in the hole!
Gump, check out that hole.
And there was always something to do.
-Mount them up.
-Spread out! Cover his back.
One day, it started raining,
and it didn't quit for four months.
We'd been through
every kind of rain there is:
little bitty stinging rain,
and big old fat rain,
rain that flew in sideways.
And sometimes, rain even seemed
to come straight up from underneath.
Shoot, it even rained at night.
-Hey, Forrest.
-Hey, Bubba.
I'm gonna lean up against you.
You just lean right back against me.
This way, we don't have to sleep
with our heads in the mud.
You know why we a good partnership,
Forrest?
'Cause we be watching out
for one another,
like brothers and stuff.
Hey, Forrest, there's something
I've been thinking about.
I got a very important question
to ask you.
How would you like to go
into the shrimping business with me?
Okay.
Man, I tell you what,
I got it all figured out, too.
So many pounds of shrimp
to pay off the boat,
so many pounds for gas,
we can just live right on the boat.
We ain't got to pay no rent.
I'll be the captain,
we can just work it together,
split everything right down the middle.
Man, I'm telling you, 50-50.
And, hey, Forrest,
all the shrimp you can eat.
That's a fine idea.
Bubba did have a fine idea.
I even wrote Jenny
and told her all about it.
I sent her letters,
not every day, but almost.
I told her what I was doing
and asked her what she was doing,
and told her
how I thought about her always,
and how I was looking forward
to getting a letter from her
just as soon as she had the time.
I'd always let her know that I was okay.
Then, I'd sign each letter,
"Love, Forrest Gump."
This one day, we was out walking,
like always,
and then, just like that,
somebody turned off the rain
and the sun come out.
Ambush!
Take cover!
Get down!
Get the sixty!
Get that pig up here, God damn it!
Forrest, you okay?
Strongarm! Strongarm!
Be advised, Strongarm!
Medic, we got a man down!
Strongarm, this is Leg Lima 6, over!
Roger, Strongarm, be advised
we have incoming from the tree line
at points blue plus two.
AKs and rockets...
Misfire! Misfire!
God damn it! Mac!
Get that thing...
Fuck it, get it in the tree line!
Jesus!
My unit is down hard and hurting!
Six are pulling back to Blue Line,
Leg Lima 6 out.
Pull back! Pull back!
Run! Run, Forrest!
-Pull back!
-Forrest, Forrest!
Run, man! Run!
Pull back! Run!
Run, God damn it, run!
Medic! Can I get a medic?
I ran and ran, just like Jenny told me to.
I ran so far and so fast
that pretty soon I was all by myself,
which was a bad thing.
Bubba!
Bubba was my best good friend.
I had to make sure that he was okay.
Any friendlies out there?
Yeah, I've got three over here.
Where the hell are you?
Bubba?
And on my way back to find Bubba,
well, there was this boy
laying on the ground.
Tex!
Okay.
I couldn't just let him lay there all alone,
scared the way he was,
so I grabbed him up
and run him out of there.
And every time I went back
looking for Bubba,
somebody else was saying,
"Help me, Forrest. Help me."
Can't hear... Can't hear...
No sweat, man. Just lay back.
You'll be okay. You'll be okay.
I started to get scared
that I might never find Bubba.
...over.
Roger, Strongarm,
I know my position is danger close.
We got Charlie all over this area.
I gotta have those fast movers
in here now. Over.
-Six, Strongarm, we want...
-Lieutenant Dan, Coleman's dead!
I know he's dead!
My whole goddamn platoon
is wiped out!
-Leg Lima 6, Leg Lima 6.
-God damn it!
-Copy this transmission. Over.
-What are you doing?
Just leave me here! Get away.
Just leave me here! Get out!
Leg Lima 6, Strongarm.
How copy this? Over.
God, I said leave me here, God damn it!
Leg Lima 6, Leg Lima 6,
this is Strongarm, be advised
your fast movers
are inbound at this time, over.
Then, it felt like something
just jumped up and bit me.
Something bit me!
You chink son of a bitch!
I can't leave the platoon.
I told you to leave me there, Gump.
Forget about me. Get yourself out!
Did you hear what I said?
God damn it, put me down!
Get your ass out of here!
I didn't ask you to pull me out of there,
God damn you!
Where the hell
do you think you're going?
To get Bubba.
I got an air strike inbound right now.
They're gonna nape the whole area.
Gump, you stay here, God damn it!
That's an order!
I gotta find Bubba!
Forrest.
-Bubba.
-I'm okay, Forrest.
I'm okay.
Oh, Bubba, no...
Nah, I'm gonna be all right.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
I'm okay, Forrest.
I'm okay, man. I'm fine.
Helo's inbound.
Top smoke, get it out there!
lf I'd a known this was gonna be the
last time me and Bubba was gonna talk,
I'd of thought of something better to say.
Hey, Bubba.
Hey, Forrest.
Forrest, why'd this happen?
You got shot.
Then Bubba said something
I won't ever forget.
I wanna go home.
Bubba was my best good friend.
And even I know that ain't something
you can find just around the corner.
Bubba was gonna be
a shrimping boat captain,
but instead he died right there
by that river in Vietnam.
That's all I have to say about that.
It was a bullet, wasn't it?
-A bullet?
-That jumped up and bit you.
Oh, yes, sir.
Bit me directly in the buttocks.
They said it was a million-dollar wound,
but the Army must keep that money,
'cause I still ain't seen a nickel
of that million dollars.
The only good thing
about being wounded in the buttocks
is the ice cream.
They gave me all the ice cream
I could eat.
And guess what?
A good friend of mine
was in the bed right next door.
Lieutenant Dan,
I got you some ice cream.
Lieutenant Dan, ice cream.
It's time for your bath, Lieutenant.
Harper!
Cooper, Larson,
Webster,
-Gump. Gump.
-I'm Forrest Gump.
Kyle, Nichols,
McMill, Johnson, Tyler,
Holiday...
Surprise, surprise, surprise!
Gump, how can you watch
that stupid shit?
-From the DMZ to the Delta...
-Turn it off!
...you are tuned to the
American Forces Vietnam Network.
This is Channel 6, Saigon.
Good catch, Gump.
You know how to play this?
Come on, let me show you. Here.
Now, the secret to this game is,
no matter what happens,
never ever take your eye off the ball.
All right.
For some reason,
Ping-Pong came very natural to me.
See? Any idiot can play.
So, I started playing it all the time.
I played Ping-Pong
even when I didn't have anyone
to play Ping-Pong with.
The hospital's people said
it made me look like a duck in water,
whatever that means.
Even Lieutenant Dan would come
and watch me play.
I played Ping-Pong so much,
I even played it in my sleep.
Now, you listen to me.
We all have a destiny.
Nothing just happens,
it's all part of a plan.
I should have died out there
with my men,
but now I'm nothing
but a goddamn cripple,
a legless freak! Look! Look! Look at me!
Do you see that?
Do you know what it's like
not to be able to use your legs?
Yes, sir, I do.
Did you hear what I said?
You cheated me.
I had a destiny.
I was supposed to die in the field,
with honor!
That was my destiny,
and you cheated me out of it!
Do you understand
what I'm saying, Gump?
This wasn't supposed to happen,
not to me.
I had a destiny.
I was Lieutenant Dan Taylor.
You're still Lieutenant Dan.
Look at me.
What am I gonna do now?
PFC Gump?
Yes, sir!
As you were.
Son, you've been awarded
the Medal of Honor.
Guess what, Lieutenant Dan,
they want to give me a...
Ma'am, what'd they do
with Lieutenant Dan?
They sent him home.
Two weeks later, I left Vietnam.
The ceremony was kicked off
with a candid speech by the President
regarding the need for further escalation
of the war in Vietnam.
President Johnson awarded
four Medals of Honor
to men
from each of the Armed Services.
America owes you
a debt of gratitude, son.
I understand you were wounded.
Where were you hit?
-In the buttocks, sir.
-That must be a sight.
I'd kind of like to see that.
God damn, son.
After that,
Mama went to the hotel to lay down,
so I went out for a walk
to see our nation's capital.
Hilary, all right, I've got the vets,
what do you want me to do with them?
What are you doing here so late?
It's a good thing Mama was resting,
'cause the streets was awful crowded
with people looking
at all the statues and monuments,
and some of them people were loud
and pushy.
Okay, follow me! Come on.
Let's move it out.
Everywhere I went,
I had to stand in line.
Follow me, let's go!
Come on. Let's go.
Stand here.
Hey, you're a good man
for doing this. Good!
Okay.
There was this man giving a little talk.
And for some reason, he was
wearing an American flag for a shirt.
Now, I'm gonna
bring up some soldiers...
And he liked to say the "F" word.
A lot. "F" this and "F" that.
And every time he said the "F" word,
people, for some reason,
well, they'd cheer.
...where to stick this fucking war! Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
Come on, man, come up here, man.
Come on. Come on. Yeah, you!
Come on. Move, move, move.
You can do it. Just get up there.
Go on. That's it.
Tell us a little bit about the war, man.
The war in Vietnam?
-The war in Viet-fucking-nam!
-Yeah!
Peace!
Come on, man, go!
-Come on!
-Peace!
Well...
There was only one thing
I could say about the war in Vietnam.
...there's only one thing
I can say about the war in Vietnam.
In Vietnam, your...
Hey, what the hell are you...
I'll beat your head in,
you goddamn oinker!
Jesus Christ, what'd they do with this?
We can't hear you!
We can't hear anything!
-This one! This one! Give me that!
-Turn it up!
Speak up!
That's it!
...and that's all I have to say about that.
That's so right on, man. You said it all.
What's your name, man?
My name is Forrest. Forrest Gump.
Forrest Gump!
-Gump!
Forrest! Forrest!
-Jenny!
-Forrest!
Hey! Hey!
It was the happiest moment of my life.
Jenny and me were just like
peas and carrots again.
She showed me around,
and even introduced me
to some of her new friends.
Shut that blind, man.
And get your white ass
away from that window.
Don't you know we in a war here?
Hey, man, he's cool. He's cool.
He's one of us.
-Let me tell you about us.
-Where the hell have you been?
Our purpose here
is to protect our black leaders
from the racial onslaught of the pig
who wishes to brutalize
our black leaders,
rape our women,
and destroy our black communities.
Who's the baby killer?
This is my good friend I told you about.
This is Forrest Gump.
Forrest, this is Wesley.
Wesley and I lived together in Berkeley,
and he's the president
of the Berkeley chapter of SDS.
Let me tell you something else.
We are here to offer protection and help
for all of those who need our help,
because we, the Black Panthers,
are against the war in Vietnam.
Yes, we are against any war where
black soldiers are sent to the frontline
to die for a country that hates them.
Yes, we are against any war
where black soldiers go to fight
and come to be brutalized and killed
in their own communities
as they sleep in their beds at night.
You are a fucking asshole!
Yes, we are against all these racist
and imperial dog acts.
Forrest! Quit it! Quit it!
Forrest!
Stop it! Stop it!
Oh, God...
I shouldn't have brought you here.
I should have known it was just
gonna be some bullshit hassle.
He should not be hitting you, Jenny.
Come on, Forrest.
Sorry I had a fight in the middle
of your Black Panther party.
He doesn't mean it when
he does things like this. He doesn't.
I would never hurt you, Jenny.
I know you wouldn't, Forrest.
I wanted to be your boyfriend.
That uniform is a trip, Forrest.
You look handsome in it. You do.
-You know what?
-What?
I'm glad we were here together
in our nation's capital.
Me, too, Forrest.
We walked around all night,
Jenny and me, just talking.
She told me about
all the traveling she'd done.
And how she'd discovered ways
to expand her mind
and learn how to live in harmony,
which must be out west somewhere,
'cause she made it
all the way to California.
Try to love one another right now
Hey!
Anybody want to go to San Francisco?
-I'll go.
-Far out.
It was a very special night
for the two of us.
I didn't want it to end.
I wish you wouldn't go, Jenny.
I have to, Forrest.
Jenny?
Things got a little out of hand.
It's just this war
and that lying son of a bitch, Johnson!
I would never hurt you, you know that.
You know what I think?
I think you should go home
to Greenbow, Alabama!
Forrest, we have very different lives,
you know.
I want you to have this.
Forrest, I can't keep this.
I got it just by doing
what you told me to do.
Why are you so good to me?
You're my girl.
I'll always be your girl.
And just like that, she was gone,
out of my life again.
That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
I thought I was going back to Vietnam,
but instead, they decided the best way
for me to fight the Communists
was to play Ping-Pong.
So, I was in the Special Services,
traveling around the country
cheering up all them wounded veterans
and showing them
how to play Ping-Pong.
I was so good that some years later
the Army decided that I should be
on the All-American Ping-Pong team.
We were the first Americans
to visit the land of China
in like a million years,
or something like that.
Somebody said world peace
was in our hands,
but all I did was play Ping-Pong.
When I got home,
I was a national celebrity.
Famouser even than Captain Kangaroo.
Here he is, Forrest Gump, right here.
Mr. Gump, have a seat.
Forrest Gump, John Lennon.
-Welcome home.
-You had quite a trip.
Can you tell us, what was China like?
In the land of China,
people hardly got nothing at all.
No possessions?
And in China, they never go to church.
No religion, too?
-Hard to imagine.
-Well, it's easy if you try, Dick.
Some years later,
that nice young man from England
was on his way home
to see his little boy
and was signing some autographs,
and for no particular reason at all,
somebody shot him.
They gave you
the Congressional Medal of Honor.
Now, that's Lieutenant Dan.
Lieutenant Dan!
They gave you
the Congressional Medal of Honor!
Yes, sir, they surely did.
They gave you,
an imbecile,
a moron who goes on television
and makes a fool out of himself
in front of the whole damn country,
the Congressional Medal of Honor.
Yes, sir.
Well, then, that's just perfect!
Yeah, well,
I just got one thing to say to that.
God damn bless America.
Hey!
Oh, God!
-Oh, God!
-Lieutenant Dan!
Lieutenant Dan said
he was living in a hotel.
And because he didn't have no legs,
he spent most of his time
exercising his arms.
Take a right. Take a right.
Hey! Come on, already!
What do you do here in New York,
Lieutenant Dan?
I'm living off the government tit.
Sucking it dry!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Are you blind?
-I'm walking here!
-Get out of the way!
Get out! Come on, go! Go! Go!
I stayed with Lieutenant Dan
and celebrated the holidays.
You have a great year.
Hurry home and God bless you.
Have you found Jesus yet, Gump?
I didn't know I was supposed to be
looking for him, sir.
That's all these cripples,
down at the VA,
that's all they ever talk about.
Jesus this and Jesus that.
Have I found Jesus?
They even had a priest come
and talk to me.
He said God is listening,
but I have to help myself.
How if I accept Jesus into my heart,
I'll get to walk beside him
in the kingdom of heaven.
Did you hear what I said?
Walk beside him
in the kingdom of heaven.
Well, kiss my crippled ass.
God is listening? What a crock of shit.
I'm going to heaven, Lieutenant Dan.
Oh?
Well,
before you go, why don't you get
your ass down to the corner
-and get us another bottle of Ripple.
-Yes, sir.
We are at approximately 45th Street
in New York City at One Astor Plaza.
This is the site of the old Astor Hotel.
What the hell is in Bayou La Batre?
-Shrimping boats.
-Shrimping boats?
Who gives a shit
about shrimping boats?
I gotta buy me
one of them shrimping boats,
soon as I have some money.
I made me a promise to Bubba
in Vietnam
that as soon as the war was over,
we'd go in partners.
He'd be the captain of the
shrimping boat and I'd be his first mate.
But now that he's dead,
that means I gotta be the captain.
-A shrimp boat captain.
-Yes, sir.
A promise is a promise, Lieutenant Dan.
Now hear this!
Private Gump here
is gonna be a shrimp boat captain.
Well, I tell you what, Gilligan,
the day that you are
a shrimp boat captain,
-I will come and be your first mate.
-Okay.
lf you're ever a shrimp boat captain,
that's the day I'm an astronaut.
Danny, what are
you complaining about?
-What are you doing, hon?
-Mr. Hot Wheels.
-Who's your friend?
-My name is Forrest, Forrest Gump.
This is Cunning Carla
and Long-Limbs Lenore.
So, where you been, baby cakes, huh?
Haven't seen you around lately.
You know, you should have
been here for Christmas,
'cause Tommy bought a round
on the house
and gave everybody a turkey sandwich.
Well, well, I had company.
Hey, hey! We was just there.
That's at Times Square.
Don't you just love New Year's?
You get to start all over.
-Hey, Lenore...
-Everybody gets a second chance.
It's funny,
but in the middle of all that fun,
I began to think about Jenny,
wondering how she was spending
her New Year's night out in California.
...eight, seven, six, five,
four, three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year, Lieutenant Dan!
What are you, stupid or something?
What's your problem?
What's his problem?
Did you lose your pecker in the war
or something?
What, is your friend stupid
What did you say?
I said, is your friend stupid
or something?
Hey! Don't call him stupid!
-Hey, don't you push her!
-You shut up!
-Don't you ever call him stupid!
-What's the matter, baby?
-Why are you so upset?
-Just get the hell out of here.
-Stupid damn...
-Get your goddamn clothes...
You belong in Ripley's Believe It Or Not!
-Get the hell out of here!
-You should be in a sideshow!
Go on! Get out of here!
Come on, Lenore.
We don't need this shit!
Get out of here!
-You retard.
-Loser. You freak.
No, no.
I'm sorry I ruined your
New Year's Eve party, Lieutenant Dan.
She tasted like cigarettes.
I guess Lieutenant Dan figured there's
some things you just can't change.
He didn't want to be called crippled,
just like I didn't want to be called stupid.
Happy New Year, Gump.
The US Ping-Pong team
met with President Nixon today
at an Oval Office ceremony...
And wouldn't you know it?
A few months later,
they invited me and the Ping-Pong team
to visit the White House.
So, I went, again.
And I met the President
of the United States, again.
Only, this time, they didn't get us rooms
in a real fancy hotel.
So, are you enjoying yourself
in our nation's capital, young man?
-Yes, sir.
-Well, where are you staying?
-It's called the Hotel Ebbott.
-Oh, no, no, no, no.
I know of a much nicer hotel.
It's brand-new, very modern.
I'll have my people
take care of it for you.
Security, Frank Wills.
Yeah, sir, you might want
to send a maintenance man
over to that office across the way.
The lights are off, and they must be
looking for a fuse box or something,
'cause them flashlights,
they're keeping me awake.
Okay, sir. I'll check it out.
-Thank you.
-No problem.
-Good night.
Therefore, I shall resign the presidency
effective at noon tomorrow.
Vice President Ford
will be sworn in as president
at that hour in this office.
As I recall the high hopes for America
with which we began this second term...
Sergeant Gump.
-Yes, sir!
-As you were.
I have your discharge papers.
Your service is up, son.
Does this mean
I can't play Ping-Pong no more?
For the Army it does.
And just like that, my service
in the United States Army was over.
So, I went home.
-I'm home, Mama.
-I know, I know.
-Louise, he's here.
-Now, when I got home,
I had no idea,
but Mama had had all sorts of visitors.
We've had all sorts of visitors, Forrest.
Everybody wants you
to use their Ping-Pong stuff.
One man even left a check for $25,000
if you'd be agreeable to saying
you liked using their paddle.
Oh, but, Mama,
I only like using my own paddle.
-Hi, Miss Louise.
-Hey, Forrest.
I know that. I know that.
But it's $25,000, Forrest.
I thought maybe you could hold it
for a while, see if it grows on you.
-Oh, you look good, Forrest.
-That Mama, she sure was right.
-You look real good.
-It's funny how things work out.
I didn't stay home for long,
because I'd made a promise to Bubba,
and I always try to keep my promise.
So, I went on down to Bayou La Batre
to meet Bubba's family
and make their introduction.
Are you crazy, or just plain stupid?
Stupid is as stupid does, Mrs. Blue.
I guess.
And, of course,
I paid my respect to Bubba himself.
Hey, Bubba, it's me, Forrest Gump.
I remember everything you said,
and I got it all figured out.
I'm taking the $24,562
and 47 cents that I got...
Or, that's left after a new hair cut
and a new suit,
and I took Mama out
to a real fancy dinner,
and I bought a bus ticket
and three Dr. Peppers.
Tell me something.
Are you stupid or something?
Stupid is as stupid does, sir.
Well, that's what's left after me saying,
"When I was in China
on the All-America Ping-Pong team,
"I just loved playing Ping-Pong with
my Flex-O-Light Ping-Pong paddle,"
which everybody knows isn't true,
but Mama says it's just a little white lie
so it wouldn't hurt nobody.
So, anyway, I'm putting all that on gas,
ropes and new nets
and a brand-new shrimping boat.
Now, Bubba had told me everything
he knew about shrimping,
but you know what I found out?
Shrimping is tough.
I only caught five.
A couple more,
you could have yourself a cocktail.
Hey, you ever think
about naming this old boat?
It's bad luck
to have a boat without a name.
I'd never named a boat before,
but there was only one I could think of,
the most beautiful name
in the wide world.
Now, I hadn't heard from Jenny
in a long while,
but I thought about her a lot,
and I hoped that whatever
she was doing made her happy.
I thought about Jenny all the time.
Hey!
Lieutenant Dan,
what are you doing here?
Well, thought I'd try out my sea legs.
But you ain't got no legs,
Lieutenant Dan.
Yes, I know that.
You wrote me a letter, you idiot.
Well, well. Captain Forrest Gump.
I had to see this for myself.
And I told you if you were ever
a shrimp boat captain
that I'd be your first mate.
Well, here I am.
-I am a man of my word.
-Okay.
Yeah, but don't you be thinking that
I'm going to be calling you "sir."
No, sir.
That's my boat.
I have a feeling if we head due east,
we'll find some shrimp,
so take a left.
-Take a left!
-Which way?
Over there! They're over there!
-Get on the wheel and take a left!
-Okay.
Gump, what are you doing?
Take a left! Left!
That's where we're going
to find those shrimp, my boy!
That's where we'll find them.
-Still no shrimp, Lieutenant Dan.
-Okay, so I was wrong.
How are we going to find them?
Well, maybe you should
just pray for shrimp.
So, I went to church every Sunday.
Sometimes Lieutenant Dan came, too,
though I think
he left the praying up to me.
-No shrimp.
-Where the hell's this God of yours?
It's funny Lieutenant Dan said that,
'cause right then, God showed up.
-You'll never sink this boat!
-Now, me, I was scared,
but Lieutenant Dan, he was mad.
Come on!
You call this a storm?
Come on, you son of a bitch!
It's time for a showdown! You and me!
I'm right here! Come and get me!
You'll never sink this boat!
Hurricane Carmen
came through here yesterday,
destroying nearly everything in its path.
And as in other towns
up and down the coast,
Bayou La Batre's
entire shrimping industry
has fallen victim to Carmen
and has been left in utter ruin.
Speaking with local officials,
this reporter has learned,
in fact, only one shrimping boat
actually survived the storm.
Louise. Louise, there's Forrest.
After that, shrimping was easy.
Since people still needed
them shrimps for shrimp cocktails
and barbecues and all,
and we were the only boat left standing,
Bubba-Gump Shrimp's what they got.
We got a whole bunch of boats,
12 Jennys,
a big old warehouse. We even have
hats that say "Bubba-Gump" on them.
Bubba-Gump Shrimp.
It's a household name.
Hold on there, boy.
Are you telling me you're the owner of
the Bubba-Gump Shrimp Corporation?
Yes, sir. We got more money
than Davy Crockett.
Boy, I heard some whoppers in my time,
but that tops them all.
We was sitting next to a millionaire.
Well, I thought it was a very lovely story,
and you tell it so well,
with such enthusiasm.
Would you like to see
what Lieutenant Dan looks like?
Well, yes, I would.
That's him right there.
And let me tell you something
about Lieutenant Dan...
Forrest,
I never thanked you for saving my life.
He never actually said so,
but I think he made his peace with God.
For the second time in 17 days,
President Ford escaped
possible assassination today.
Base to Jenny 1.
-Base to Jenny 1.
-Jenny 1. Go, Margo.
Forrest has a phone call.
Yeah, well, you'll have to tell them
to call him back.
-He is indisposed at the moment.
-His mama's sick.
-Where's Mama?
-She's upstairs.
Hi, Forrest.
-I'll see you tomorrow.
-All right.
We sure got you straightened out,
didn't we, boy?
-What's the matter, Mama?
-I'm dying, Forrest.
Come on in, sit down over here.
-Why are you dying, Mama?
-It's my time.
It's just my time.
Now, don't you be afraid, sweetheart.
Death is just a part of life,
something we're all destined to do.
I didn't know it,
but I was destined to be your mama.
-I did the best I could.
-You did good, Mama.
Well, I happen to believe
you make your own destiny.
You have to do the best
with what God gave you.
What's my destiny, Mama?
You're going to have
to figure that out for yourself.
Life is a box of chocolates, Forrest.
You never know
what you're going to get.
Mama always had a way of explaining
things so I could understand them.
I will miss you, Forrest.
She had got the cancer
and died on a Tuesday.
I bought her a new hat
with little flowers on it.
And that's all I have to say about that.
Didn't you say you were waiting
for the number seven bus?
There'll be another one along shortly.
Now, because I had been a football star,
and a war hero,
and a national celebrity,
and a shrimping boat captain,
and a college graduate,
the city fathers of Greenbow, Alabama
decided to get together
and offered me a fine job.
So, I never went back to work
for Lieutenant Dan,
though he did take care
of my Bubba-Gump money.
He got me invested
in some kind of fruit company.
And so then, I got a call from him saying
we don't have to worry about money
no more, and I said,
"That's good. One less thing."
Now, Mama said there's only
so much fortune a man really needs,
and the rest is just for showing off.
So, I gave a whole bunch of it
to the Foursquare gospel church,
and I gave a whole bunch to the
Bayou La Batre fishing hospital.
And even though Bubba was dead
and Lieutenant Dan said I was nuts,
I gave Bubba's mama Bubba's share.
You know what?
She didn't have to work
in nobody's kitchen no more.
That smells wonderful.
And 'cause I was a gazillionaire
and I liked doing it so much,
I cut that grass for free.
But at night time
when there was nothing to do
and the house was all empty,
I'd always think of Jenny.
And then, she was there.
-Hello, Forrest.
-Hello, Jenny.
Jenny came back and stayed with me.
Maybe it was because
she had nowhere else to go,
or maybe it was because she was
so tired, 'cause she went to bed
and slept and slept,
like she hadn't slept in years.
It was wonderful having her home.
Every day we'd take a walk and
I'd jabber on like a monkey in a tree,
and she'd listen about Ping-Ponging,
and shrimping,
and Mama making a trip up to heaven.
I did all the talking.
Jenny most of the time was real quiet.
How could you do this?
Sometimes I guess there
just aren't enough rocks.
I never really knew why she came back,
but I didn't care.
It was like olden times.
We was like peas and carrots again.
Every day, I'd pick pretty flowers
and put them in her room for her,
and she gave me the best gift anyone
could ever get in the wide world.
-New shoes.
-They make them just for running.
And she even showed me
how to dance.
And, well, we was like family,
Jenny and me.
And it was the happiest time in my life.
...and this Fourth is witnessing
one of the
largest fireworks displays
in the nation's...
-You done watching it?
-...here in New York Harbor...
-I'm going to bed.
-...with a spectacular display
of tall ships earlier.
The Statue of Liberty...
Will you marry me?
I'd make a good husband, Jenny.
You would, Forrest.
But you won't marry me.
You don't want to marry me.
Why don't you love me, Jenny?
I'm not a smart man,
but I know what love is.
Jenny.
Forrest, I do love you.
-Where are you running off to?
-I'm not running.
That day, for no particular reason,
I decided to go for a little run.
So, I ran to the end of the road,
and when I got there,
I thought maybe I'd run
to the end of town.
President Carter, suffering from heat
exhaustion, fell into the arms of...
And when I got there,
I thought maybe I'd just
run across Greenbow County.
And I figured since I'd run this far,
maybe I'd just run across
the great state of Alabama.
And that's what I did.
I ran clear across Alabama.
For no particular reason,
I just kept on going.
I ran clear to the ocean.
And when I got there,
I figured since I'd gone this far,
might as well turn around
and just keep on going.
And when I got to another ocean,
I figured since I'd gone this far,
I might as well just turn back
and keep right on going.
When I got tired, I slept.
When I got hungry, I ate.
When I had to go, you know...
I went.
And so, you just ran.
Yeah.
I'd think a lot about Mama
and Bubba and Lieutenant Dan.
But most of all, I thought about Jenny.
I thought about her a lot.
For more than two years now,
a man named Forrest Gump,
a gardener from Greenbow, Alabama,
stopping only to sleep,
has been running across America.
Charles Cooper brings us this report.
For the fourth time
on his journey across America,
Forrest Gump,
the gardener from Greenbow, Alabama,
is about to cross
the Mississippi River again today.
-I'll be damned. Forrest?
-Sir, why are you running?
Why are you running?
Are you doing this for world peace?
Are you doing this for the homeless?
-Are you running for women's rights?
-Or for the environment?
Or for animals?
They just couldn't believe that
somebody would do all that running
for no particular reason.
Why are you doing this?
I just felt like running.
It's you. I can't believe it's really you.
Now, for some reason, what I was doing
seemed to make sense to people.
I mean, it was like an alarm
went off in my head, you know?
I said,
"Here's a guy that's got his act together.
"Here's somebody
who's got it all figured out.
"Here's somebody who has the answer."
I'll follow you anywhere, Mr. Gump.
So, I got company.
And after that, I got more company.
And then, even more people joined in.
Somebody later told me
it gave people hope.
Now... Now, I don't know
anything about that,
but some of those people
asked me if I could help them out.
Hey, man, hey, listen, I was wondering
if you might help me, huh?
Listen, I'm in the
bumper sticker business
and I've been trying
to think up a good slogan.
And since you have been such a big
inspiration to the people around here,
I thought you might
be able to help me jump into...
Whoa, man! You just ran through
a big pile of dog shit!
-It happens.
-What, shit?
Sometimes.
And some years later,
I heard that that fellow
did come up with
a bumper sticker slogan,
and he made a lot of money off of it.
Another time, I was running along,
somebody who had lost all his money
in the T-shirt business,
he wanted to put my face on a T-shirt,
but he couldn't draw that well,
and he didn't have a camera.
Here, use this one.
Nobody likes that color anyway.
Have a nice day.
Well, some years later,
I found out that that man
did come up with an idea for a T-shirt.
He made a lot of money off of it.
Anyway, like I was saying,
I had a lot of company.
My mama always said,
"You got to put the past behind you
before you can move on."
And I think that's what
my running was all about.
I had run for three years, two months,
14 days and 16 hours.
Quiet. Quiet.
He's going to say something.
I'm pretty tired.
Think I'll go home now.
Now what are we supposed to do?
And just like that,
my running days was over.
So, I went home to Alabama.
Moments ago, at 2:25 p.m.,
as President Reagan was leaving the...
...five or six gunshots were fired
by an unknown would-be assassin.
The President was shot in the chest,
and the assailant...
I picked up the mail.
And one day, out of the blue clear sky,
I got a letter from Jenny,
wondering if I could come down
to Savannah and see her,
and that's what I'm doing here.
She saw me on TV, running.
I'm supposed to go on the
number nine bus to Richmond Street
and get off and go one block left
to 1947 Henry Street, Apartment 4.
Why, you don't need to take a bus.
Henry Street is just five
or six blocks down that way.
-Down that way?
-Down that way.
It was nice talking to you.
I hope everything works out for you!
Hey!
Forrest!
How you doing? Come in, come in!
I got your letter.
I was wondering about that.
Is this your house?
Yeah. It's messy right now.
I just got off work.
It's nice. You got air conditioning.
-Thank you.
-I ate some.
Hey, I kept a scrapbook
of your clippings and everything.
There you are.
And this, I got you running.
I ran a long way,
for a long time.
And there...
Listen, Forrest,
I don't know how to say this.
I just I want to apologize
for anything that I ever did to you,
'cause I was messed up
for a long time, and...
-Hey.
-Hi.
Hey, you.
-This is an old friend from Alabama.
-How do you do?
Listen, next week my schedule changes,
so I'll be able to... But thanks...
No problem. Got to go, Jen,
I'm double-parked.
-Okay. Thanks.
-Bye.
This is my very good friend, Mr. Gump.
Can you say hi to him?
-Hello, Mr. Gump.
-Hello.
-Can I go watch TV now?
-Yes, you can. Just keep it low.
-You're a mama, Jenny.
-I'm a mama.
His name's Forrest.
Like me.
I named him after his daddy.
He got a daddy named Forrest, too?
You're his daddy, Forrest.
Hey.
Forrest, look at me.
Look at me, Forrest.
There's nothing you need to do, okay?
You didn't do anything wrong.
Okay?
Isn't he beautiful?
He's the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen.
But...
Is he smart, or...
He's very smart.
He's one of the smartest in his class.
Yeah, it's okay. Go talk to him.
-What are you watching?
-Bert and Ernie.
Forrest,
I'm sick.
What, do you have
a cough due to a cold?
I have some kind of virus,
and the doctors don't...
They don't know what it is,
and there isn't anything
they can do about it.
You could come home with me.
Jenny, you and little Forrest could
come stay at my house in Greenbow.
I'll take care of you if you're sick.
Would you marry me, Forrest?
Okay.
Please take your seats.
Forrest? It's time to start.
Hi.
Your tie.
Lieutenant Dan.
Hello, Forrest.
You got new legs. New legs!
Yeah. I got new legs. Custom-made.
Titanium alloy.
It's what they use on the space shuttle.
Magic legs.
This is my fiancée, Susan.
-Lieutenant Dan.
-Hi, Forrest.
Lieutenant Dan, this is my Jenny.
Hey. It's nice to meet you finally.
Do you, Forrest,
take Jenny to be your wife?
Do you, Jenny,
take Forrest to be your husband?
And so I pronounce you man and wife.
-Hey.
Hey, Forrest.
Were you scared in Vietnam?
Yes. Well, l...
I don't know.
Sometimes it would stop raining long
enough for the stars to come out.
And then it was nice.
It was like just before the sun
goes to bed down on the bayou.
There was always
a million sparkles on the water.
Like that mountain lake.
It was so clear, Jenny,
it looked like there were two skies,
one on top of the other.
And then, in the desert,
when the sun comes up,
I couldn't tell where heaven stopped
and the earth began.
It was so beautiful.
I wish I could've been there with you.
You were.
I love you.
You died on a Saturday morning.
And I had you placed
here under our tree.
And I had that house of your father's
bulldozed to the ground.
Mama
always said that dying was a part of life.
I sure wish it wasn't.
Little Forrest is doing just fine.
But...
About to start school again soon,
and I make his breakfast, lunch
and dinner every day.
I make sure he combs his hair
and brushes his teeth every day.
Teaching him how to play Ping-Pong.
Okay.
He's really good.
Forrest, you go.
We fish a lot.
And every night, we read a book.
He's so smart, Jenny.
You'd be so proud of him.
I am.
He wrote you a letter.
And he says I can't read it.
I'm not supposed to,
so I'll just leave it here for you.
Jenny,
I don't know if Mama was right,
or if it's Lieutenant Dan.
I don't know
if we each have a destiny,
or if we're all just floating around
accidental-like on a breeze.
But I think
maybe it's both.
Maybe both is happening
at the same time.
But I miss you, Jenny.
lf there's anything you need,
I won't be far away.
Here's your bus. Okay.
Hey. I know this.
I'm gonna show that
for show-and-tell because
Grandma used to read it to you.
My favorite book.
Here we are.
Okay.
Here you go.
Hey, Forrest, don't...
-I wanted to tell you, I love you.
-I love you, too, Daddy.
I'll be right here when you get back.
You understand this is
the bus to school, now, don't you?
Of course, and you are Dorothy Harris,
and I'm Forrest Gump.