...broke in right on the tour.
No matter what they say,
it's all about money.
So let's imagine, ladies, that you're
a savings and loan officer.
Watch. One, two, three.
See? You've got it all,
and we've got nothin'.
- And you have all four. Take a look.
- Oh!
But I wouldn't trust you with
real gold. That's why this one's
only worth about a penny.
- Hmm.
- And if you wonder where
the other one went, watch.
Penny from the ear.
How much for the rest?
- Have you seen Edward?
- No, I haven't. Great party, Philip.
Well, my wife went to a lot of trouble.
She called a caterer.
- Excuse me, Anne. Howard, how are ya?
- Philip, good.
Hey, I understand Edward's
taking over Morse Industries.
- Yeah, well, he's not
here to get a suntan.
- Can I get in on it?
- Yeah, call me.
- When?
- Just call me.
Uh, hi. I'm Philip Stuckey,
Edward Lewis' lawyer.
- Hey, where's
the guest of honour anyway?
- Well, if I know him,
he's probably off in a corner
somewhere charming a very
pretty lady. How are you?
I told my secretary to make
the arrangements. Didn't she call you?
Yes, she did. I speak to your secretary
more than I speak to you.
- I see.
- I have my own life too,
you know, Edward.
This is a very important week for me.
I need you here.
But you never give me any notice. You
just think I'm at your beck and call.
I do not believe that you
are at my "beck and call."
Well, that's the way you always make me
feel. Maybe I should just move out.
- If that's what you want, yes.
- All right, when you get back
to New York, we'll discuss it.
- Now is as good a time as any.
- That's fine with me, Edward. Goodbye.
Goodbye, Jessica.
- Phil suggested that maybe
I should take a look...
- Phil is just my lawyer, okay?
- Yes, sir.
- How did the Morse stock open
at the Nikkei?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
Tokyo opened maybe 90 minutes ago.
You have to keep on top
of these things, all right?
- Done.
- Hello, Mr Lewis.
- Hi, hi. How ya doin'?
I want this whole thing
wrapped up as soon as possible.
I gotta get to New York by Sunday.
- I got tickets to the Met.
- Yes, sir.
- Your coat, Mr Lewis.
- Thank you.
- Edward!
- Susan!
- Hi.
- I was sorry to hear about Carter.
- Oh, yeah. Thanks.
- Heard you got married.
- Well, yeah, I couldn't wait for you.
- Susan, tell me something.
- Yes?
When you and I were dating,
did you speak to my secretary
more than you spoke to me?
She was one of my bridesmaids.
Huh.
- Your husband's a very lucky guy. Bye.
- Thanks. Bye.
...up to you.
- Absolutely.
- Wonderful.
He's leaving.
Edward's leaving.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
Is this Mr Stuckey's car?
- Edward, where ya goin'?
- You got the keys to your car?
Why? What's wrong with the limo?
Look, the limo is buried back there.
Darryl can't get it out.
- Please give me the keys.
- All right, look.
I don't think you should drive.
You're a little excited. Don't drive
my car. Let me work something out here.
Fellas, what kind of a system is this?
Can you move these cars out of here?
- Look, Edward, Edward.
Are you familiar with a stick shift?
- Oh, yeah.
- Have you driven a shift?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Listen... All right. Just...
Just be ginger with it. Don't...
- It's a new car. Don't...
- Okay, I can do it.
- It's just a little... Edward!
- Give me a break, please?
- I love this car.
I love it too. Look, you don't
even know where you're going.
You... You're gonna
get lost in the dark!
Beverly Hills is down the hill!
I don't need to fall at your feet
Just 'cause you cut me to the bone
- And I won't miss
the way that you kiss me
- Oh, shit!
We were never carved in stone
If I don't listen
to the talk of the town
Then maybe I can fool myself
I'll get over you
I know I will
I'll pretend my ship's not sinking
And I'll tell myself I'm over you
- 'Cause I'm the king of wishful thinking
- Maps here! Maps!
Good one.
- What do you say, blondie?
- Hi, honey. Want some fun?
- Hey, baby, you lookin' for a date?
- Yeah, honey, we're lookin'.
- Well, here I am.
- I'm Al, and this is my friend, Joe.
Get in the car.
Well, I'm just outta school
Like I'm real, real cool
Gotta dance like a fool
Got the message
and I gotta be a wild one
Ooh, yeah, I'm a wild one
Gonna break the news
Gonna keep on movin' wild
Gonna keep on swingin', baby
I'm a real wild child
Now wait a minute.
You don't seem to understand me.
That's my job. At the end of the month,
I collect everybody's rent.
Now give me the money,
or you're outta here.
Gonna meet all my friends
Gonna have ourself a ball
Gonna tell my friends
Gonna tell them all that I'm a wild one
Ooh, yeah, I'm a wild one
Gonna break the news
Gonna keep on movin' wild
Gonna keep on swingin', baby
I'm a real wild child
I'm a real wild one
and I like-a wild fun
In a world goin'crazy
everything seems hazy
I'm a wild one
Ooh, yeah, I'm a wild one
Gonna break the news
Gonna keep on movin' wild
Gonna keep on swingin', baby
I'm a real wild child
Welcome to Hollywood! Everybody
comes to Hollywood got a dream.
What's your dream?
What's your dream? Hey, mister?
Hey! What's your dream?
Have a good one.
- What happened?
- Some chick. She bought it over there.
Detective Albertson.
What do you know about that girl?
I'll tell you, man.
I don't know who she hang with.
Come on, guy. We just pulled her
out of a Dumpster in the back.
Who was her pimp?
Cocaine her pimp.
She a strawberry.
She be out on these streets
day in, day out, tradin' her
sorry self for some crack.
- And, and what do you do?
- I cool.
Oh, I'll bet. Hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Awful.
- What are you, from the press?
- No, no. We're from Orlando.
- Oh, I don't believe this.
Do you see... I got tourists
photographing the body, Al.
I don't know what happened.
A man in a blue...
In a world that can be so insane
I don't think it's very strange
for me to be in love with you
I wanna know more than your brain
- Hey, Pops, has Kit been in here?
- Upstairs in the pool room.
Not something that I'm expecting
Now I smile for your affection
We have made a soul connection
Just for me does your bell toll
Don't be cold
Show me your soul
- Yo, Viv!
- Is it all gone?
Carlos, you know my roommate, Vivian.
This is Angel. That's Bermuda.
I know everybody.
Is it all gone, Kit?
Carlos sold me some great shit. We just
had this party. I was the hostess.
I can't believe you
bought drugs with our rent!
What is going on with you, Kit?
- I needed a little pick-me-up.
- Oh, well, we need rent money!
- Whoa. Calm down, chica.
She only owes me 200 more.
- Carlos!
- Another 200 dollars?
- That was from way before.
That's right, 200, Vivian.
But if you wanna work off her money
with me, we can work something out.
That's a very sweet offer,
Carlos, but not now.
- Come on, Viv. Come downstairs.
- Work out... Work out what?
What do we work out?
- You really like her, Carlos?
- You took it while I was sleeping?
- You were unavailable for consultation.
- Hey, let's go.
Snack! Snack!
- Besides, it's my apartment.
- Yeah, well, I have
to live there too, Kit.
Look, you came here, I gave you
some money, I gave you a place to stay,
and some valuable vocational advice.
He was on my case. I had to give him
something. So don't irritate me.
This ain't a buffet, Kit!
"Irritate you"? "Irritate you"?
I just saw a girl
pulled out of a Dumpster.
I know. Skinny Marie.
But she was a, a flake.
She was a crackhead. Dominic was
trying to straighten her out for months.
- Hey, you just knocked my drink...
- Get off of her!
- Leave her alone!
Don't you wanna get outta here?
Get out where?
Where the fuck you wanna go?
Ah, this stuff.
There's nothin' but garbage.
- Uh, excuse me.
- Huh?
- Can you tell me how to get to Beverly Hills?
You're here! That's
Sylvester Stallone's house right there!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Hey, yo, Rachel?
- What?
- Yeah, you see the stars
on the sidewalk, babe?
- Yeah.
Well, Vivian and me,
we work Bob Hope,
we work the Ritz Brothers,
we work Fred Astaire...
we work all the way down
to Ella Fitzgerald.
This is our turf. We got seniority.
You better get off our corner.
Forgive me. I was just takin'
a rest here. Besides, she's new.
Yeah, well, I'm old. So go rest up
by Monty Hall or Esther Wilson.
- Williams.
- Esther Williams, where you belong!
Back off, Kit. You know,
you're really becoming a grouch.
- Am I really a grouch?
- Yes. Sometimes.
Well, just 'cause I'm hungry!
I'm gonna go get something to eat.
- Hey, girls!
- Hey, yo, baby!
How 'bout a freebie?
It's my birthday!
Dream on!
It's looking really slow tonight.
Yeah, well, maybe we should get a pimp,
you know. Carlos really digs you.
And then he'll run our lives
and take our money. No.
You're right. We say who,
we say when, we say how much.
- Do you think I look
like Carol Channing?
- No, I love this look.
It's very glamorous.
Glamour choice.
Oh, yo! Oh, yo! Catch this.
Wait a minute.
That's a Lotus Esprit.
No, that's rent.
You should go for him.
You look hot tonight.
Don't take less than a hundred.
Call me when you're through.
Take care of you.
Work it. Work it, baby. Work it.
Work it! Own it!
Yes, you can handle this.
First is here somewhere.
Hey, sugar,
you lookin' for a date?
No, I wanna find Beverly Hills.
Can you give me directions?
Sure, for five bucks.
- Ridiculous!
- Price just went up to ten.
- You can't charge me for directions.
- I can do anything I want to, baby.
I ain't lost.
All right. Okay. All right. You win,
I lose. Got change for a twenty?
For twenty I'll show you personal.
Even show you where the stars live.
Oh, that's all right.
I already been to Stallone's.
Right. Uh, down the street.
Make a right.
Lights!
Lights would be good here.
- This is a hot car!
- It's a little, little temperamental.
- Yours?
- No, it isn't.
- Stolen?
- N-Not exactly.
What's your name?
What do you want it to be?
Vivian. My name is Vivian.
Vivian.
- So what hotel you staying at?
- The, uh, Regent Beverly Wilshire.
Then down the block,
right at the corner.
Man, this baby must corner
like it's on rails.
Beg your pardon?
Well, doesn't it blow your mind?
This is only four cylinders!
You know about cars.
W-Where did that come from?
Road and Track. Boys back home
I grew up with, they were really
into American heavy metal.
Mustangs, Corvettes.
They bought 'em cheap and fixed 'em up.
I paid attention.
So how is it you know
so little about cars?
My first car was a limousine.
So where is this... heavy metal home?
Millageville, Georgia.
You know, I think you left
your transmission back there.
You're not shifting right.
This is a standard "H."
Standard "H."
Like I know what that means.
You ever driven a Lotus?
- No.
- You're gonna start right now.
- You're joking.
- No, it's the only way
I can get you off my coat.
Fasten your seat belt. I am taking you
for the ride of your life.
I'm gonna show you what this car
can really do. Are you ready?
- I am ready.
- Hang on.
- Okay.
- Here we go.
This has pedals like a race car.
They're really close together.
So it's probably easier for a woman
to drive 'cause they have little feet.
Except me. I wear a size nine.
You know, your foot's as big as your arm
from your elbow to your wrist?
- Did you know that?
- No, I didn't know that.
Just a little bit of trivia.
Tell me, what kind of... What kind
of money you girls make these days?
- Ballpark.
- Can't take less than a hundred dollars.
- Hundred dollars a night?
- For an hour.
An hour?
You make a hundred dollars an hour
and you got a safety pin
holding your boot up?
- You gotta be joking.
- I never joke about money.
Neither do I.
Hundred dollars an hour.
Pretty stiff.
Well, no, but it's got potential.
Good evening, Mr Lewis. Will you
be needing the car any more tonight?
I hope not!
Ah... you're here.
Yeah.
- So you'll be all right?
- Yeah, I'm gonna grab
a cab with my 20 bucks.
Go back to your office.
Yeah! My office. Yeah.
Well, thanks for the ride.
- See ya.
- Goodbye.
No taxis?
No, I like the bus.
I was thinking. Did you really
say a hundred dollars an hour?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Hmm.
Well, if you don't have
any prior engagements,
I would be very pleased if you
would accompany me into the hotel.
You got it.
- What is your name?
- Edward.
Edward? That's my favourite name
in the whole world.
- No!
- I tell you what.
This is fate, Edward.
That's what this is.
- Now why don't you put this on?
- Why?
Well, this hotel is not
the kind of establishment
that rents rooms by the hour.
Ah.
- Wow!
- It's all right.
- Holy shit.
- You're gonna be fine.
Come with me.
And stop fidgeting.
- Good evening, Mr Lewis.
- Hello. You have messages?
- Yes, we have several.
- Thank you.
Would you send up some champagne
and strawberries, please?
Of course.
Room service for Mr Lewis, please.
Oh, honey. You know what's happened?
I've got a runner in my panty hose!
I'm not wearing panty hose!
Well, colour me happy!
There's a sofa in here for two!
- First time in an elevator.
- Ah.
Close your mouth, dear.
- Sorry. Couldn't help it.
- Try.
- Penthouse.
- The penthouse! Mm!
- Yes.
To the left.
Oh, I miss keys.
- Impressed?
- You kidding me?
I come here all the time.
- As a matter of fact,
they do rent this room by the hour.
- Sure they do.
Wow! Great view!
I bet you can see all the way
to the ocean from out here.
I'll take your word for it.
I don't go out there.
Why don't you go out there?
- I'm afraid of heights.
- You are?
So how come you rented the penthouse?
It's the best. I looked all around
for penthouses on the first floor,
but I can't find one.
Well, now that you have me here,
what are you going to do with me?
- Wanna know something?
I don't have a clue.
- No?
I hadn't exactly planned this.
Well, do you plan everything?
- Always.
- Yeah. Me too.
I'm actually... No, I'm not a planner.
I wouldn't say I was a planner.
I would say I was, um, a kinda
"fly by the seat of my pants" gal.
You know? Moment to moment.
That's me. That's... Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
You know, you could pay me.
That's one way to maybe break the ice.
Oh, yeah. I'm sorry.
Uh, I assume cash is acceptable?
Cash works for me. Yeah.
You're on my fax.
Well, that's one
I haven't been on before.
Cute. Very cute. Thank you.
All right. Here we go.
Pick one. I got red,
I got green, I got yellow.
I'm outta purple, but I do have
one Gold Circle Coin left.
The condom of champions.
The one and only.
Nothin' is gettin' through this sucker.
- What do you say? Hmm?
- A buffet of safety.
I'm a safety girl.
- All right.
Let's get one of these on you.
- Hey, hey, no. I...
Why don't we just talk
for a little bit, okay?
Talk. Yeah.
Um, okay.
Edward, are you in town on,
uh, business or pleasure?
- Business, I think.
- Business, you think.
Well, let me guess.
That would make you... a lawyer.
- A lawyer?
- Mm-hmm.
What makes you think I'm a lawyer?
You've got that, um,
sharp, useless look about you.
Bet you've known a lot of lawyers.
I've known a lot of everybody.
What is that?
- Champagne.
- Oh. Well.
Might as well make myself useful.
Take a load off.
- Good evening.
- Hi.
- Uh, where would you like it?
- Where would we like it?
Uh, over by the bar.
- Excuse me.
- It'll be on your bill, Mr Lewis.
Thank you.
What are you looking at?
- What is he looking at?
- Uh, yes. Here we go.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you very much, sir.
Have a nice evening.
Tip. Wow.
I missed that one. I'll...
Don't worry about it.
- You mind if I take my boots off?
- Not at all.
So, do you have a wife?
Girlfriend?
- I have both.
- Where are they? Shopping together?
My ex-wife...
is now in Long Island
in my ex-home...
with my ex-dog.
There you go. My ex-girlfriend,
Jessica, is in New York,
moving out of my apartment
even as we speak.
- Try a strawberry.
- Why?
It brings out the flavour
in the champagne.
Oh, groovy.
Pretty good.
- Don't you drink?
- No.
Listen, I, I appreciate this whole
seduction scene you got going,
but let me give you a tip:
I'm a sure thing. Okay?
So, I'm on an hourly rate.
Could we just move it along?
Somehow I'm sensing that this
time problem is a major issue with you.
- Why don't we just get
through that right now?
- Great. Let's get started.
How much for the entire night?
Stay here?
- You couldn't afford it.
- Try me.
- Three hundred dollars.
- Done.
Thank you. Now we can relax.
I'll be out in just a minute.
That champagne kinda got to me.
- I didn't hear you. What did you say?
- Um, I said I'd be out in just a minute.
What is... What do you have
in, uh, your hand there?
- What are you hiding?
- Nothing.
All right, look. I do not want any
drugs here. I don't want any of this.
- Get your things and your
money and please leave.
- I don't do drugs, all right?
- I stopped doing drugs when I was 14.
- What is this? What is this?
- This is dental floss.
- Yeah? So?
I had all those strawberry seeds.
And you shouldn't neglect your gums.
- I'm sorry. Please, continue.
- Thank you.
- Are you gonna watch?
- No, I'm going.
Thank you.
It's just that, uh,
very few people surprise me.
Yeah, well, you're lucky.
Most of'em shock the hell outta me.
- You're watching.
- I'm going.
Yes, that may be true, Vance.
Yes, I know, but I still need
the numbers on Morse Industries.
Uh-huh. I've got 'em from London.
I need 'em now from Tokyo.
I'll call down and get them when
I want them. Thank you very much.
I have a little carpet picnic here.
Are you sure you don't want a drink?
I'm high on life.
Can't you tell?
You know, I never saw this episode.
- What do you want?
- What do you do?
Everything.
But I don't kiss on the mouth.
Neither do I.
- Hey, how you doin'?
- Good. Thanks.
- Good morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning, Mr Thompson.
- Good morning, good morning.
- Morning, sir.
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning, Mr Thompson.
- Good morning, Marjorie.
Of course Morse is going to fight.
It's to be expected.
He's run his company
for a very long time now.
I don't think he's ready to have
his name taken off the stationery.
He wants to meet you
face-to-face. Hmm?
- Okay.
- I wouldn't do it.
Sure you wouldn't, but do it anyhow.
Tonight, dinner. Set it up.
Oh, Edward, Edward. I... Look. It's
really not a good idea that you see him.
Definitely not alone, you know?
He's a feisty old guy.
You know, we say the wrong thing,
we could wind up in court.
Well, you know, there's always
a possibility things are gonna go wrong.
That's why I enjoy this so much.
- Oh, by the way, Phil, about your car.
- Oh, God. What?
- It corners like it's on rails.
- What? What does that mean?
Edward. Edward!
Hi.
Well, good morning.
- Red.
- Better.
You didn't wake me.
I can see you're really busy.
- I'm gonna be outta here
in just a minute.
- No, there's no hurry.
Are you hungry? You must be. Why don't
you sit and have something to eat?
I, uh, took the liberty of
ordering everything on the menu.
I didn't know what you'd like.
- Thanks.
- All right? Good.
- Did you sleep well?
- Yeah. Too good.
- Forgot where I was.
- Occupational hazard?
Yeah. Did you sleep?
Uh, yes, a little, on the couch.
I was, uh, working last night.
You don't sleep, you don't do drugs,
you don't drink. You hardly eat.
What do you do, Edward?
'Cause I know you're not a lawyer.
That's right.
There are four other chairs here.
Oh.
- So what do you do?
- I buy companies.
What kind of companies?
Well, I buy companies that are
in financial difficulty.
If they have problems, you must
get 'em for a bargain, huh?
Well, the company
I'm buying this week...
I'm getting for the bargain price
of about one billion.
- A billion dollars?
- Yes.
Wow! You must be really smart, huh?
I only got through the 11 th grade.
How far did you go in school?
I went all the way.
Your folks must be really proud, huh?
So you don't actually have
a billion dollars, huh?
No, I get some of it
from banks, investors.
It's not an easy thing to do.
- And you don't make anything?
- No.
- And you don't build anything?
- So what do you do with
the companies once you buy 'em?
- I sell 'em.
Here, let me do that.
You sell them.
Well, I don't sell the whole company.
I break it up into pieces,
and then I sell that off.
It's worth more than the whole.
So it's sort of like, um, stealing cars
and selling 'em for the parts, right?
- Yeah, sort of. But legal.
- Mm-hmm.
- There. See? Now it's perfect.
- Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Where'd you learn to do that?
Well, I screwed the debate team
in high school.
I had a grandpa who was nice to me.
He liked ties on Sundays.
Mind if I, uh, take a swim
in your tub before I go?
Not at all.
Just stay in the shallow end.
- Hello?
- Edward, it's Phil.
Listen, I'm running out the door.
I just wanna let you know.
- Morse is all set for tonight.
- Oh, that's good.
- He's bringing his grandson.
He's grooming him to take over.
I don't know.
Ah, yes. Very intense young man
named David. Plays polo.
Look, I gotta say this again.
I don't like you going alone.
I want your extra time and your
Look. Wh... I just think
it'd be better if you, if you
went with a date, you know?
Keep it social.
- You got to know how to talk dirty, baby
- Edward, do you hear me?
- Uh, yes. Yeah, I'm here.
- What is that?
- If you wanna impress me
- Housekeeping is singing.
- Oh, oh, oh, you can't be
too flirty, mama
- I know how to undress me
- Yeah. Listen,
- Edward, I know a lot of nice girls.
- No, you don't.
I just want your extra time and your
- Kiss
- Besides, I already have one.
- If you wanna impress me
- You just concentrate on
finding out what Morse is up to.
- You can't be too flirty, mama
- I'm on my way.
I know how to undress me
Mm-hmm, yeah, baby
I wanna be your fantasy
Well, maybe you could be mine
Mm-hmm, you just leave it
all up to me
- Don't you just love Prince?
- More than life itself.
- Don't you knock?
- Vivian,
I have a business
proposition for you.
- What do you want?
- I'm gonna be in town until Sunday.
I'd like you to spend
the week with me.
- Really?
- Yes.
Yes, I'd like to hire you
as an employee.
Would you consider
spending the week with me?
And I will pay you to be
at my beck and call.
Look, I'd love to be
your beck-and-call girl,
but, um, you're a rich,
good-lookin' guy.
You could get
a million girls free.
I want a professional. I don't need
any romantic hassles this week.
If you're talkin' 24 hours a day,
it's gonna cost you.
Oh, yes, of course.
All right. Here we go.
Give me a ballpark figure.
How much?
Six full nights. Days too.
- Four thousand.
- Six nights at 300 is 1,800.
- You want days too.
- Two thousand.
- Three thousand.
- Done.
Holy shit!
Vivian?
Vivian, is that a yes?
Y-Y-Yes.
Yes!
I'll be gone most of the day.
I want you to buy some clothes.
- You really should think
about traveller's cheques.
- We may be going out evenings.
- You'll need something to wear.
- Like what?
Oh, nothing too flashy.
Not too sexy.
- Conservative. You understand?
- Boring.
Elegant. Any questions?
- Can I call you "Eddie"?
- Not if you expect me to answer.
I would've stayed for 2,000.
I would've paid four.
I'll see you tonight.
Baby, I'm gonna treat you so nice,
you're never gonna wanna let me go.
Three thousand for six days,
and, Vivian, I will let you go.
But I'm here now.
Three thousand dollars!
Whoo!
- Hello.
- I called and called.
Where were you last night?
- Ma?
- It's Viv.
Oh, hi. I had to party.
Where are you?
Oh, man, are you ready for this?
The guy? The Lotus?
I am in his hotel room
in Beverly Hills.
The penthouse. His bathroom
is bigger than the Blue Banana.
- Do I have to hear this?
- Kit, he wants me to stay the whole week.
And you know what he's gonna give me?
Guess. You'll never guess.
- Three thousand dollars.
- Bullshit!
I swear to God, and extra
money to buy clothes.
Oh, man, I am bummed!
I gave that guy to you!
Three thousand. Really?
Is he twisted?
- No.
- Ugly?
- He's good-looking.
- Oh, what's wrong with him?
- Nothing.
- Did he give you the money yet?
- The end of the week.
- That's what's wrong with him.
- Well, he gave me 300 for last night,
and, Kit, I'm gonna leave some
at the front desk for you.
I want you to pick it up.
I'm at the Regent Beverly Wilshire.
Write it down. Are you writing it down?
You'll forget it.
Write it down.
- Reg... Bev... Wil.
- Now, one more thing.
Where do I go for the clothes?
Good stuff. On him.
- In Beverly Hills?
- Yeah.
- Rodeo Drive, baby.
- Hi.
- Yes, ma'am. May I help you?
Yeah, I'm leaving this here for
Kit De Luca. She's gonna pick it up.
- Don't open that.
- Uh, no, ma'am.
- Miss Wilson, do you know that lady?
- No, sir.
Wild women do
And they don't regret it
Wild women show what
they're goin'through
Ooo-whoo
Wild women do what you
think they'll never
What you only dream about
Wild women do
Oh, yes, they do
You tell me you want a woman who
Is simple as a flower
Well, if you want me
to act like that
You've got to pay me by the hour
Wild women do
And they don't regret it
Oh, wild women show
What they're going through
Ooo-whoo, yeah, ha
- Wild women do what you
think they'll never
- May I help you?
I'm just checking things out.
Are you looking for something
in particular?
No. Well, yeah.
Um, something conservative.
Yes.
- You got nice stuff.
- Thank you.
- How much is this?
- I don't think this would fit you.
Well, I didn't ask if it would fit.
I asked how much it was.
- How much is this, Marie?
- It's very expensive.
It's very expensive.
Look, I got money to spend in here.
I don't think we have anything for you.
You're obviously in the wrong place.
Please leave.
Doctor's office.
Two blocks down, to the left.
You have an appointment?
Tiffany's taking the corner space.
They'll like the project.
I've very excited
about the whole thing.
Did you realize that Via Rodeo
is the first new street in
Beverly Hills in 75 years?
- Excuse me, miss. May I help you?
- I'm going to my room.
- Uh, do you have a key?
- Oh, I forgot that cardboard thing.
- I'm on the top floor.
- You're a guest here?
- I'm with a friend.
- Oh? And who would that be?
- Edward.
- Edward?
Edward. Edward, uh...
- He knows me.
- Dennis.
Dennis, did you just come
off the night shift? Hmm?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you know this young lady?
- She's with Mr Lewis.
- Mr Lewis.
That's it. Edward Lewis.
Thanks, Dennis.
- Evidently, she joined him last night.
- Thank you.
Oh, God, what now? What? What?
- What is with everybody today?
- I am the manager of the hotel.
Now just come with me.
- We'll have a little chat.
- I'm coming. Yeah, I'm coming.
- Thank you, Dennis. Thank you.
- And what is your name, miss?
- What do you want it to be?
- Don't play with me, young lady.
- Vivian.
Thank you. Vivian.
Well, Miss Vivian,
things that go on in other hotels don't
happen at the Regent Beverly Wilshire.
Now, Mr Lewis, however,
is a very special customer,
and we'd like to think of
our special customers as friends.
Now, as a customer, we would expect Mr
Lewis to sign in any additional guests,
but as a friend,
we're willing to overlook it.
Now, I'm assuming that you're a...
relative?
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm. I thought so.
Then you must be his...
- Niece?
- Of course.
Naturally, when Mr Lewis leaves,
I won't see you in this hotel again.
I assume you have
no other uncles here?
Good. Then we understand
each other.
I would also encourage you
to dress a little more appropriately.
That'll be all.
No, that's not all.
That's what I was trying to do.
I tried to go get a dress on Rodeo Drive
today, and the women wouldn't help me.
And I have all this money now
and no dress.
Not that I expect you to help me,
but I have all of this, okay?
I have to buy a dress for dinner
tonight, and nobody will help me.
Oh, man, if you are
calling the cops...
Yeah, call the cops.
That's... That's great.
- Tell 'em I said hi.
- Women's clothing.
Bridget, please.
Yes, Bridget. Hello.
This is Barnard Thompson here
at the Regent Beverly Wil...
Oh, thank you. Yes, but I'd like you
to do a favour for me, please.
I'm sending someone over.
Her name is Vivian.
She's a special guest.
She's the niece of a very special guest.
Now, this is the jewel
in Morse's crown.
Prime industrial property straddling
the port of Long Beach and Los Angeles.
The real estate possibilities
are endless, but most of the
yard we'll just level.
We just got the information,
Mr Stuckey.
Edward, we just got the Morse update.
Don, can you hold
the projection, please?
- Yeah, what? Speak.
- Old man Morse just got
the inside track...
on a $350 million contract
to build destroyers for the Navy.
Navy contract?
I can't believe this.
I thought you said they had
nothing in the hopper on this one!
- I thought they didn't.
- Hey, you know, if that's true,
it could cost a lot more.
- Those stocks could go through the roof.
- Yeah, no shit, Sherlock!
Maybe we're lucky to get
this information now, sir.
- See, we can still walk away from it.
- "Walk away"?
Hey, forget it, pal.
We got a thousand man-hours in on this.
- Nobody's walking away from anything.
- Philip, I think he's right.
- Forget it, Mark.
- I do too, but why is he...
- I don't wanna hear it! Well, at least you're...
Gentlemen, relax. Relax.
Who do we know on the Senate
Appropriations Committee?
- Senator Adams.
- All right, Senator Adams.
Let's find out where he is.
The Navy's not going to spend
$350 million on anything without
going to Appropriations first.
I don't understand what's
going on here today, gentlemen.
- Hello?
- Well, that's why I hired you, Phil...
to do my worrying for me.
I'll be in your office. Bob, if you
want to send over the geologicals.
- No problem.
- Thank you.
- Edward.
- Listen. Everything all set
for the meeting tonight?
- Yes, Senator Adams, please.
- Well, who, who is this girl
you're goin' with?
- Yes?
- Nobody you know.
- Yes, Edward Lewis Enterprises.
Phil Stuckey.
Yes, I have him right here.
Don't worry, Mrs Rainey.
I'll call you the minute it comes in.
- Thank you.
- Have a nice day.
- Hello. You must be Vivian.
My name's Bridget.
- Yeah, hi.
- Barney said you'd be nice to me.
- He's very sweet.
What are your plans
while you're in town?
- We're gonna have dinner.
- Oh, don't sit up there. Here.
- Oh.
- You're gonna go out? Dinner?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, you'll need a cocktail dress then.
Come with me.
Now, I'm sure we're gonna find something
here that your uncle would love.
- You're a size six, right?
- Yeah. How'd you know that?
- Well, that's my job.
- Bridge, he's not really my uncle.
They never are, dear.
Barney. Sorry, mister.
- I got a dress.
- Well, I'd rather hoped
you'd be wearing it.
Oh, no. I didn't wanna get it messed up.
Listen, I got shoes too. You wanna see?
No, that won't be necessary. I'm sure
they're quite lovely. Thank you.
Okay, well, listen.
I didn't mean to interrupt you,
but Bridget was really great,
and I just wanted to say thanks.
- You're cool.
- You're welcome, Miss Vivian.
- Hello.
- Never ever pick up the phone.
- Then why are you calling me?
- Did you buy clothes today?
- I got a dress. A cocktail one.
- That's good.
I'll be in the hotel lobby
7:45 sharp.
- What, you're not comin'up to the door?
- This isn't a date. It's business.
- Where are you takin' me, anyway?
- I'm taking you to a restaurant
called the Voltaire.
- Very elegant.
- All right.
I'll meet you in the lobby,
but only 'cause you're payin' me to.
Well, thank you very much.
Get her back for me, please.
- Mr Stuckey wanted to see you.
- Yes, tell him I'm in the middle
of a very important phone call.
- Hello.
- I told you not to pick up the phone.
Then stop callin' me.
Sick.
Barney...
- It didn't fit.
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Uh, I've got a little problem.
All right, Miss Vivian.
One more time.
- Dinner napkin.
- Dinner napkin, lay gently in the lap.
Good. Elbows off the table.
Don't slouch.
Shrimp fork, salad fork, dinner fork.
I definitely have the salad fork.
The rest of the silverware
is a little confusing.
All right. If you get nervous,
just count the tines.
Now four tines: dinner fork.
And sometimes there are
three tines: the salad fork.
And sometimes...
Pardon me, Mr Lewis. I'm Mr Thompson.
I'm the manager of the hotel.
Uh-huh. Excuse me.
I just wanna make one call.
Yes, I'm sorry.
I have a message for you, sir.
- From who?
- From your niece, sir.
- My what?
- The young lady's who's staying
with you in your room, sir.
Oh. Hmm.
- I think we both know
that she's not my niece.
- Of course, sir.
The reason I know that
is that I am an only child.
- Yes, sir.
- What's the message?
She's waiting for you in the lounge.
Intriguing young lady, Miss Vivian.
- Intriguing.
- Have a good evening, sir.
- Thank you, Mr...
- Thompson. I'm the...
- Thompson.
manager... manager
of the hotel, sir.
- You're late.
- You're stunning.
You're forgiven.
Shall we go to dinner?
- This way, Mr Lewis.
Your party's waiting.
- Stop fidgeting.
- Mr Morse.
- Yes. Mr Lewis. I'm Jim Morse.
This fireball is my grandson, David.
Yeah, well, I don't know
about the fireball part,
but grandson's true enough.
Well, I'm pleased to meet you both.
This is a friend of mine, Vivian Ward.
- Hi. Really glad to meet you.
- Mr Morse, David.
- Hi.
- Please sit.
Excuse me.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to the ladies' room.
- Upstairs, to the right.
- Okay. Excuse me.
- Shall I order for you?
- Yeah.
- Please do so. Thank you.
- I'll do that.
Mr Lewis,
my grandfather believes...
the men who create a company
should control its destiny.
Where's the salad?
- Oh, the salad comes
at the end of the meal.
- But that's the fork I knew.
Let me, uh, put it another way.
Between your public statements and
the rumours flying around on this thing,
we find it very hard to figure out
what your real intentions are.
I don't know about you,
but I've never been able
to figure which goes with what.
You know, there was a time
when we built ships the size of cities.
Men like my grandfather
made this country.
- Who ordered this?
- The gentleman did, ma'am. Bon apptit.
These are escargot. It's French
for snails. It's a delicacy. Try it.
- David.
- Mr Lewis, if you were to get control...
and I don't think you will...
but if you did,
what do you plan to do
with the company?
Break it up and sell off
the pieces.
I'm sure you understand
I'm not thrilled at the idea...
of your turning 40 years of
my work into your garage sale.
At the price I'm paying
for this stock, Mr Morse,
you are going to be a very rich man.
I'm rich enough.
I just wanna have my shipyard.
Slippery little suckers.
It happens all the time.
I met your father. What's his name?
- Carter.
- Yeah. Carter. Carter Lewis.
He's not quite the bastard
everybody says he is.
- No, I have the franchise on that.
- Does that make him proud?
I doubt it.
It doesn't really matter now.
He passed away.
- I hadn't heard. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry too.
Mr Morse, you asked for this meeting.
What can I do for you?
- Leave my company alone!
- I can't do that.
I own ten million shares.
- I'll buy your stock back.
- You don't have the money.
We will. We're getting a contract
to build ten destroyers.
There will be no contract. The contract
is now buried in Appropriations
Committee and it will remain there.
And how the hell do you pull something
like that? What, you got a...
- You got dirty politicians
in your pockets now or something?
- Easy, easy, easy.
- Calm down. Calm down, David.
Mr Lewis plays hardball.
- Yes. Yes, I do.
I've heard enough of this. Vivian,
it was a great pleasure to meet you.
I'm sorry, Grandfather.
I've got to get some air. Mr Lewis.
I better join my grandson.
You two enjoy your dinner. I'm sure
it'll be delicious. Good luck, miss.
Watch out, Lewis.
I'm gonna tear you apart.
I look forward to it, sir.
Edward?
Edward, you said
you never come out here.
Well, I'm only halfway out.
You didn't say much in the car
on the way home.
You thinking about dinner?
I was a maniac.
I mean, the business was good,
I think, you know?
He's in trouble.
You want his company.
- He doesn't wanna let it go.
- Thanks for the recap.
Problem is, I think
you like Mr Morse.
What I would like is
for you to get down from there.
You're making me very nervous.
- Please, come down.
- It's making you nervous?
What if I just lean back
a little bit like this?
- Would you...
Would you rescue me if I fell?
- Vivian, I'm serious.
- Come... I'm not looking.
- It's really high. Look.
No hands. No hands!
Okay. All right. I'm sorry.
The truth is,
it really is totally irrelevant
whether I like this man or not.
I will not let myself become
emotionally involved in business.
I know.
Kit's always saying to me,
"Don't get emotional
when you turn tricks."
That's why no kissing.
It's too personal.
It's like what you're saying.
You stay numb, you don't get involved.
When I'm with a guy,
I'm like a robot. I just do it.
- Well, I mean, except with you.
- Of course not with me.
You and I are
such similar creatures, Vivian.
We both screw people for money.
I was sorry to hear
about your dad.
- When did he die?
- Last month.
Do you miss him?
I hadn't spoken to him
in 14 and a half years.
I wasn't there when he died.
- Do you wanna talk about this?
- No.
Well, I'll tell ya what.
'Cause I got an idea.
Let's watch old movies all night.
We'll just veg out
in front of the TV.
- Veg out?
- Yeah. Be still like vegetables.
Lay like broccoli.
Look, I'll tell you what. I'll be back.
We'll do broccoli tomorrow.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going downstairs for a while.
- Did you say "marriage licence"?
- Now don't change the subject.
- Just give me the stand.
- Ohhh!
Oh, I love you, Adam Alex Bider Bryan,
whatever your name is!
Oh, I love you.
Hi, uh, I'm in the penthouse.
The guy that was here, Mr Lewis?
Have you seen him
down there anywhere?
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- I didn't know you played.
- I only play for strangers.
I was getting lonely upstairs
all by myself.
Gentlemen, would you mind
leaving us, please?
Thank you.
People always do
what you tell them to do?
I guess so.
Wake up. Time to shop.
Now, if you have any trouble
using this card, have 'em call
the hotel. All right?
- Oh, more shopping.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm surprised you didn't buy
more than one dress yesterday.
It wasn't as much fun
as I thought it was gonna be.
- Why not?
- They were mean to me.
Mean to you?
- People are looking at me.
- They're not looking at you.
They're looking at me.
The stores are not nice to people.
I don't like it.
Stores are never nice to people.
They're nice to credit cards.
Okay. Stop fidgeting.
- All right.
- Get rid of your gum.
I don't believe you did that.
- Yes?
- I am Mr Hollister, the manager.
May I help you?
- Edward Lewis.
- Ah. Yes, sir.
- You see this young lady over here?
- Yes.
Do you have anything in this shop
as beautiful as she is?
Oh, yes. Oh, no.
No, no, no. I'm saying we have
many things as beautiful
as she would want them to be.
That's the point I was getting at,
and I think we can all agree with that.
- That's why when you came in here,
you knew from the first...
- Excuse me. You know what we're gonna need here?
We're gonna need a few more people
helping us out. I'll tell you why.
We are going to be spending
an obscene amount of money in here.
So we're gonna need a lot more help
sucking up to us, 'cause that's
what we really like.
- You understand me.
- Oh. Sir, if I may say so,
you're in the right store,
and the right city, for that matter.
Anything you see here,
we can do, by the way.
- Get ready to have some fun, okay?
- Okay.
Mary Pat, Mary Kate, Mary Francis,
Tovah. Let's see it. Come on.
- Pick it up, girls.
- Oh, this is absolutely divine!
- You're doing great, but you...
- Excuse me, sir. Uh...
- Yeah.
Exactly how obscene an amount
of money were you talking about?
Just profane or really offensive?
- Really offensive.
- I like him so much.
Mr Lewis, sir? Mr Lewis? How's it
going so far? Pretty well, I think.
- I think we need some major sucking up.
- You should just see you!
Very well, sir. You're not only
handsome, but a powerful man.
I could see the second you walked in
here you were someone to reckon with...
- Hollister.
- Yes, sir.
Not me. Her.
I'm sorry, sir. I'm sorry.
How are we doing, ladies?
Oh, Edward, Edward. Where the hell
are you? The word's all over the street.
- Morse is gonna raise your offer, pal.
- He's countering?
God, he is a tough old bird.
He knows the Navy contracts are stalled.
Where's he gonna get the money?
I don't know. He... I think
he's throwing in with the employees.
He still needs someone
to underwrite the paper.
- Find out who it is.
I'll be in the office in an hour.
- Yeah, okay. You got it.
You're on your own. I have to go
back to work. You look great.
- She has my card.
- And we'll help her use it, sir!
Pretty woman
walkin'down the street
the kind I like to meet
Pretty woman
I don't believe you
You're not the truth
No one could look
as good as you
Mercy
- Edward would love that tie.
- Would you give her the tie?
- The tie?
- Take off the tie. Give her the tie.
- Oh, the tie.
- He really wants to do this.
- He would go crazy about this tie.
- Give her the tie.
- He really would.
- Who ordered pizza?
Pretty woman, stop a while
Pretty woman, talk a while
Pretty woman,
give your smile to me
Pretty woman, yeah, yeah, yeah
Pretty woman, look my way
- Pretty woman, say you'll stay with me
- May I help you?
- No, thank you.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Do you remember me?
- No, I'm sorry.
- I was in here yesterday.
You wouldn't wait on me.
- Oh.
- You work on commission, right?
- Uh, yes.
- Big mistake.
Big. Huge.
I have to go shopping now.
Pretty woman,
don't walk on by
don't make me cry
Pretty woman
Don't walk away, hey
Oh. Thank you.
Oh, oh, pretty woman
...just where it is.
- Mr Lewis.
- Gentlemen.
- Let's see that...
Fellas, let's finish this up
this afternoon, huh?
Jake, set something up with Blair.
About, uh, 2:00, 2:30 would be good.
You were right about Morse.
He mortgaged everything he owns
right down to his underwear...
to secure a loan from the bank.
It's not just any bank.
Plymouth Trust, huh?
- Hmm.
- So it goes without saying...
that your business means a lot more
to them than our friend Mr Morse.
So all you gotta do is call the bank.
Yeah.
Edward, excuse me for saying this,
but what the hell is
wrong with you this week?
Are you giving Morse
a chance to get away?
You know what I used to love
when I was a kid, Phil?
- What?
- Blocks.
Building blocks. Erector sets.
So I liked Monopoly. Huh?
Boardwalk, Park Place.
- Well, wh... what's the point?
- We don't build anything, Phil.
We don't make anything.
We make money, Edward.
We worked for a year on this deal.
It's what you said you wanted.
I'm handing it to you.
Morse's jugular is exposed.
It's time for the kill.
Let's finish this. Call the bank.
How was your day, dear?
Nice tie.
I got it for you.
Well, my mother was a music teacher,
and married my father,
whose family was extremely wealthy.
Then he divorced my mother
to be with another woman,
and he took his money with him.
And then she died.
I was very angry with him.
It cost me $ 10,000 in therapy
to say that sentence.
"I was very angry with him."
I do it very well, don't I? I'll say it
again. I was very angry with him.
Hello, my name is Mr Lewis.
I'm very angry with my father.
I would've been angry
at the $ 10,000.
My father was president of
the third company I ever took over.
I bought it.
I sold it off, piece by piece.
- What'd the shrink say?
- Said I was cured.
Well, so, you got even.
That must've made you happy.
Did I mention my leg
is 44 inches from hip to toe?
So basically we're talkin' about...
88 inches of therapy...
wrapped around you
for the bargain price of...
- $3,000.
- Yeah.
Ebersol of the Falcons
passes to Keenan.
This is Bill Fricker with Gwen Olsen
giving you play-by-play
of this marvellous charity event.
Watch where you're walking,
because if you step in something,
we're not going back in the car.
Not too near the tree.
I don't like the ants. Hello!
- Hello! How are you?
- Have you seen Edward anywhere?
- What if someone recognizes me?
- Not likely.
- They don't spend too much time
on Hollywood Boulevard.
- You did.
Come on. Let go. Let go.
All right. You look great.
You look like a lady.
You're gonna have a wonderful time.
Okay, don't fidget and smile.
Humboldt's coming
around from the side.
Toquenee is on Keenan.
Penalty on that play.
This is Gwen and Gretchen,
the infamous Olsen sisters...
who have made marrying well
an art form.
- Edward!
- Be back in just a second. Hold on.
So, you're the flavour
of the month, hmm?
Uh, she's just being testy.
Edward's our most eligible bachelor.
- Everybody is trying to land him.
- Well, I'm not trying to land him.
I'm just using him for sex.
Oh!
Go on!
- Well done.
- Well done! Woof! Woof! Woof!
Tell me again why we're here.
- Business.
- Business mingling?
Yeah.
That's the chukker,
ladies and gentlemen.
Falcons, 7, Gems, 4.
Excuse me. Edward.
Edward. Over here.
- Phil.
- Ah, it's good to see you.
You too. I want you to meet
a new friend of mine, Vivian Ward.
Well, hi. Philip Stuckey, Vivian.
This is my wife, Elizabeth.
It's always a pleasure
meeting one of Edward's girls.
Oh, my God!
It's Tate Whitley Wallington!
Tate! It's me,
Elizabeth from Workout World!
She's an aerobics queen.
Feel the burn. Well, hey,
let me get you something to drink.
- Eli... Vivian, why don't
you start with that, okay?
- Thank you.
I'll be right back. By the way,
did you notice Senator Adams is here?
Mm-hmm. I asked him.
That is why I have pledged
my eternal love to you. Mmph!
Real genuine guy. Who is he?
He's my lawyer. He's all right.
You could freeze ice
on his wife's ass.
- Maybe we'll try that later.
- Are these people your friends?
- I spend time with them, yeah.
- Well, no wonder.
- No wonder what?
- No wonder why
you came looking for me.
And I do need some help from you
ladies and gentlemen in the audience.
We need you to help us replace some
of the divots out here on the grass.
- So come on out now.
- Come on! Come on, folks.
You heard her.
The stomping of the divots.
This is a time-honoured tradition,
ladies and gentlemen.
As old as the game
of polo itself.
Kings and queens
used to do this.
She's sweet, Edward.
Wherever did you find her?
976-BABE.
Only one word of advice.
Avoid the steaming divot.
No, it's all part
of the game of polo.
You get to have your shoes polished
by a member of the club.
Think I've got something
in the car that'll buff that up.
Thank you.
- Vivian. Hi. David Morse.
- Excuse me.
- David.
- How are you?
- I'm okay.
- I thought that was you.
I like this hat.
- It's new.
- Yeah? It's nice.
- Yeah. Thanks.
- Come meet my horse, Vivian.
- Well, Edward's waiting for me.
I don't wanna...
- Well, come on. He's right here.
- Okay, I'll...
Just for a second, though.
I didn't know
you were playing today.
Uh, I was asking for directions.
There she was.
Oh, so you just ran into her?
That's great. Jesus.
So, then, what does she do?
She... Does she work?
- She's in sales.
- Sales? That's terrific.
That's good. What does she sell?
Why do you wanna know?
Now just hear me out on this, okay?
I've known you a long time, you know.
I, uh, I see some differences in you
this week, like the tie and, uh...
I'm wondering if maybe this girl
isn't the difference.
Especially when I see her
talking to David Morse.
I introduced them
at dinner the other night.
So, what? Now they're best friends?
I mean, this girl appears
from out of nowhere.
Now she's talkin' to a guy
whose company we're tryin' to buy.
- That's a little convenient,
don't you think?
- I don't believe this.
Edward, how...
How do you know that this girl
hasn't attached herself to you...
because she's bringing
information back to Morse?
- This happens.
- Phil. Phil.
- Industrial espionage goes on almost every...
- Phil. Phil! Listen to me.
- What?
- She is not a spy. She is a hooker.
- Oh!
She is a hooker.
I picked her up on Hollywood
Boulevard... in your car.
- Yes.
- Oh, you are...
- Oh, man!
You know, you're the only millionaire
I ever heard of...
who goes looking for a bargain-basement
streetwalker, you know?
Edward!
I'm sorry I told you. Senator.
Senator Adams.
I'm pleased you could make it.
Thank you. I hope the information
I gave you was helpful.
Oh, absolutely, yes. Thank you for it.
Now there's no change in it, is there?
No, it's still bogged down.
- Having a nice time, Vivian?
- Yeah, I'm having a great time.
Must be quite a change
from Hollywood Boulevard, hmm?
What?
Yeah, Edward told me.
But don't worry.
Your secret is safe with me.
Listen. Maybe, uh,
you and I could get together
sometime after Edward leaves.
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Well, then we'll just
have to do that, hmm?
Philip!
Hi, tailgaters. I'd like to mention
a couple of our silver sponsors:
Jacobs Distributors
and Norrell Saddlery.
And we'd like to give a great big thanks
to our platinum sponsor,
Edward Lewis Enterprises.
The ball is in
for chukker number four.
Ay!
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
"Fine." Oh, that's good.
Seven "fines" since we left the match.
Could I have another word, please?
Asshole. There's a word.
- Think I liked "fine" better.
- You know what? Just tell me one thing.
Why did you make me
get all dressed up?
Well, for one thing,
the clothing was appropriate.
No. What I mean is, if you
were gonna tell everybody I'm a hooker,
- why didn't you just let me
wear my own clothes, okay?
- I did not... I did not...
I mean, in my own clothes, when someone
like that guy Stuckey comes up to me,
I can handle it... I'm prepared.
I'm very sorry.
I'm not happy with Stuckey at all
for saying that or doing that.
But he is my attorney.
I've known him for ten years.
He thought you were some kind of
an industrial spy. The guy's paranoid.
What are you, my pimp now?
You know, you think you can just
pass me around to your friends?
- I'm not some little toy!
- No, you're not my toy.
I know you're not my toy. Vivian.
Vivian! I'm speaking to you.
Come back here.
I hate to point out the obvious,
but you are, in fact, a hooker,
and you are my employee.
Look, you don't own me!
I decide! Okay?
- I say who, I say when,
- I...
- I say who!
I refuse to spend the next
three days fighting with you!
I said I was sorry. I meant it!
That's the end of it!
I'm sorry I ever met you.
I'm sorry I ever got
into your stupid car.
As if you had so many
more appealing options.
I've never had anyone make me feel
as cheap as you did today.
Somehow I find that
very hard to believe.
- Where you going?
- I want my money.
I wanna get outta here.
Come on!
I'm sorry.
I wasn't prepared to answer
questions about us.
It was stupid and cruel.
I didn't mean it.
I don't want you to go.
- Could you stay the week?
- Why?
I saw you talking to David Morse.
I didn't like it.
We were just talking.
Down?
- You hurt me.
- Yes.
Don't do it again.
First guy I ever loved
was a total nothing.
The second was worse.
My mom called me a bum magnet.
If there was a bum
within a 50-mile radius,
I was completely attracted to him.
That's how I ended up here.
I followed bum number three.
So here I was:
no money, no friends, no bum.
And you chose this
as your profession?
I worked at
a couple fast-food places.
Parked cars at wrestling.
I couldn't make the rent.
I was too ashamed to go home.
That's when I met Kit.
She was a hooker
and made it sound so great.
So one day I did it.
I cried the whole time.
But then I got some regulars and, you
know, it's not like anybody plans this.
It's not your childhood dream.
You could be so much more.
People put you down enough,
you start to believe it.
I think you are a very bright,
very special woman.
The bad stuff is easier to believe.
You ever notice that?
- No, I don't want to talk to him now.
Tell him I'll call him on Monday.
- Yes, sir.
- Where you going? Did he sign this?
- No, he said he had to leave.
Hey, Edward, you can't disappear now.
We're in this too deep.
Don't panic, Philip.
Morse isn't going anywhere.
I'll be back here in the morning.
- Did you send the tickets to the hotel?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
- Where are you going?
- I have a date.
- With the hooker?
Be careful, Philip.
- Do I look okay?
- Mm.
- Mm?
- Something's missing.
Well, nothing else is gonna fit
into this dress, I'll tell ya that.
Oh, maybe something in this box.
I don't want you to get too excited.
This is only on loan.
They really let you borrow this
from the jewellery store?
I'm a very good customer.
- If you were gonna buy this,
how much would it cost?
- Quarter of a million.
A quarter of a million dollars?
So where we going?
It's a surprise.
If I forget to tell you later,
I had a really good time tonight.
Thank you.
When you're not fidgeting, you look
very beautiful... and very tall.
You're a dream coming true
I can't believe how
I have fallen for you
You are the one
Who's led me to the sun
- How could I know
- You don't want to go all the way to
San Francisco in a limousine, do you?
- That I was lost without you
- I've never been on a plane before.
- How'd you get to L. A?
- Like this.
- And I want to tell you
You control my brain
And you should know that
You are life in my veins
Well, it should be
a pretty smooth flight, Mr Lewis.
The weather is clear
all the way up to San Francisco.
We should be there
in about 50 minutes.
- We're late.
- No, it's all right.
- Opening night never starts on time.
- Okay.
- Programme, sir?
- Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
Right this way, Mr Lewis.
- Doris.
- Edward, how are you?
- It's nice to see you.
- Always nice to see you.
- Sir?
- Good evening, Edward.
- Wonderful. Wonderful news.
Congratulations.
- Hey, come here.
- You gotta look at this.
- It's all right. I've already seen it.
Oh. If you're afraid of heights,
why do you get seats up here?
Because they're the best.
- Is there anything else, sir?
- No, thank you.
- The glasses are there. Enjoy the opera.
- Oh.
So... you said this is in Italian.
- Mm-hmm.
- So how am I gonna know
what they're saying?
These are broken.
Mine are broken.
No, no, it's okay.
It's all right.
- Oh.
- You'll know. Believe me,
you'll understand.
The music's very powerful.
There's a band.
People's reactions to opera the first
time they see it is very dramatic.
They either love it or they hate it.
If they love it, they will
always love it. If they don't,
they may learn
to appreciate it,
but it will never become
part of their soul.
- Bravo!
Bravo!
Did you enjoy the opera, dear?
Oh, it was so good
I almost peed in my pants.
What?
She said she liked it better
than Pirates of Penzance.
- Oh!
- Yes.
- No, don't touch.
- I move the queen. I like the queen.
No, you can't move
the queen there.
I thought you were gonna do that!
Why don't we finish this tomorrow?
It's really late, and I have to work.
Why don't you not go to work tomorrow?
Take the day off.
- Me not work?
- Yeah.
I do own the company.
Here are the storage reports you wanted,
and Mr Lewis called.
- What'd he say?
- He said he's taking the day off.
- He's taking the day off?
- That's what he said.
I'm starving. There's a snap dog vendor
over there. Do you have any money?
I have money. I don't know
what a snap dog is, but I have money.
Well, I'm gonna give...
You'll buy a snap dog, we'll cop
a squat under a tree somewhere.
- Cop a what?
- Cop a squat.
All right.
Read the first two pages.
Okay.
I was talking to someone.
I was talking to...
"...death ever,
my hopeless cries,
and look upon myself
and curse my fate."
He sleeps.
I love you.
What are you thinking about,
sitting here all by yourself?
The fact that this will be
our last night together.
Then you'll finally be rid of me.
Well, you've been
pretty tough to take.
My business is almost over,
so I'll be going back to New York.
I'd really like to see you again.
- You would?
- Yes. Yes, I would.
I've arranged for you to have
an apartment, have a car,
have a wide variety of stores
guaranteed to suck up to you...
any time you wanna go shopping.
Everything's done.
What else?
You gonna leave some money by the bed
when you pass through town?
Vivian, it really
wouldn't be like that.
- How would it be?
- Well, for one thing, it would
get you off the streets.
That's just geography.
Vivian, what is it you want?
- What do you see happening between us?
- I don't know.
When I was a little girl,
my mama used to lock me in the attic
when I was bad, which was pretty often.
And I would... I would
pretend I was a princess...
trapped in a tower
by a wicked queen.
And then suddenly, this knight...
on a white horse,
with these colours flying,
would come charging up
and draw his sword.
And I would wave, and he would climb
up the tower and rescue me.
But never, in all the time...
that I had this dream,
did the knight say to me,
"Come on, baby. I'll put you up
in a great condo."
- Yes.
- I had to call.
I just got off the phone
with James Morse. Get this.
He wants to meet with you today.
- What about?
- He wouldn't say.
Edward, I think we got him.
His nuts are on the block.
We got him.
Look, if he's really caving in,
I want to get him...
to commit his stocks
to us this afternoon. Hmm?
No, that's no good.
If he's really caving in, I don't
want to wait 'til this afternoon.
Have Morse meet me downtown
this morning. Goodbye.
I have to go now.
I want you to understand.
I heard everything you said,
but this is all
I'm capable of right now.
It's a very big step for me.
I know. It's a really good offer
for a girl like me.
I've never treated you
like a prostitute.
You just did.
Yes, Barnard Thompson here,
Miss Vivian.
Could you come down to the front desk?
There's someone here who wants
to speak to you.
- She says her name is Miss De Luca.
- Let me talk to her.
Let me... Let me
just talk to her.
Yo, Viv, babe.
Would you come down here?
The sphincter police
won't let me through.
- Okay. She's on her way.
- Fine.
- Mr Thompson.
- Yes.
The window washer
is refusing to come down.
It's a Saturday.
Wait here, please. Watch her.
Yes, sir.
Fifty bucks, Grandpa.
For 75, the wife can watch.
- Listen, I've been calling you.
- Yeah, I know. They told me
at the Banana you were looking for me.
You were supposed to come by Tuesday.
I left the money at the desk.
- I was hidin' out from Carlos.
- Well, if you picked up the money,
you wouldn't have to hide.
Hey, I was busy. I had a life,
you know. Nino got beat up.
We had to visit him in the hospital.
Rachel got arrested. It was a mess!
Anyway, I got the money.
Thank you very much for saving my ass.
Now Carlos can get off of it. You know,
he was talking about you last night.
He would bust something
if he saw you in this outfit.
I was afraid to hug you up there.
I might wrinkle you!
- You look really good.
- Over there?
- No, something in the shade.
You clean up real nice.
Sure don't fit in down on
the boulevard looking like you do,
not that you ever did.
Well, thanks, but it's easy
to clean up when you got money.
Yeah.
- So, when does he leave?
- Tomorrow.
- You get to keep the clothes?
- Yeah.
Edward asked me if I
wanted to see him again,
but I think,
I think definitely no.
I mean, it's just
another week, right?
- Definitely no.
- Yeah.
- Oh, no!
- What?
- I know this weepy look on your face.
- Oh, no, you don't!
- You fell in love with him, didn't you?
- No. Kit, please!
- Oh, stop it.
- You've fallen in love with him?
- Kit!
- Did you kiss him on the mouth?
- Uhhh, uh, yeah. I did.
- You kissed him on the mouth?
- I did. It was nice.
You fall in love with him
and you kiss him on the mouth?
Did I not teach you anything?
Look, I'm not stupid, okay?
I'm... I'm not in love with him.
I just... I like him.
- You like him?
- Yeah.
You definitely like him.
Well, he's not a bum.
He's a rich, classy guy.
Who's gonna break my heart, right?
Oh, no. Come on. You don't know that.
Hey, he asked you, right?
Maybe you guys could, like, um,
you know, get a house together,
and like, buy some diamonds
and a horse.
I don't know.
Anyway, it could work. It happens.
When does it happen, Kit?
When does it really happen?
Who does it really work out for? Did it
work out for Skinny Marie or Rachel? No.
Those were very specific cases
of crackheads.
I just wanna know
who it works out for.
You give me one example of somebody
that we know that it happened for.
- Name someone?
You want me to name someone?
- Yeah, one person that it worked out for.
- You want me to, like, give you
a name or something?
- Yeah, I'd like a name.
Oh, God, the pressure of a name.
Cinder-fuckin'-rella.
Mr Morse, you said this morning
you wish to speak to Mr Lewis.
Mr Lewis is now listening.
I've reconsidered my position
on your acquisition offer.
On one condition.
I'm not so concerned about me,
but the people who are working for me.
It's not a problem.
They'll be taken care of.
Now then, gentlemen,
if we could address ourselves
to the contracts in front of you.
- If you look...
- Excuse me, Phil.
Gentlemen, I'd like to speak
to Mr Morse alone.
Thank you.
All right, gentlemen.
You heard the man. Please wait outside.
You too, Phil.
- What do you mean?
- I mean I would like
to speak to Mr Morse alone.
Why does he get to stay?
Please. Please.
- I'll be right outside.
- Good.
- Is that better?
- It's all right.
- Would you like a cup of coffee?
- Black.
Mr Morse... my interests
in your company have changed.
What is it you're after now,
Mr Lewis?
Well, I no longer wish to buy
your company and take it apart.
But I don't want
anyone else to either.
And it is still
extremely vulnerable.
So I find myself
in unfamiliar territory.
I wanna help you.
Why?
Mr Morse, I think we can do something
very special with your company.
What about our Navy contracts?
Ah, they weren't dead.
Just delayed.
- I bluffed a little bit.
- You're very good at it.
Thank you very much.
It's my job.
I think we can leave the details
up to the others.
I find this hard to say
without sounding condescending,
but... I'm proud of you.
Thank you.
I think we can let in
the other suits now.
Let's continue the meeting.
Come in, gentlemen. Sit down.
Edward, please.
What was this all about?
It's all yours, Phil.
Finish it up.
Hold it. Hold it, these aren't signed.
These aren't signed!
Can someone please tell me
what the fuck is going on here?
Mr Lewis and I are going
to build ships together.
Great big ships.
You know, I think
I'm gonna go for a walk.
- Just stay here for a while.
I'll be back.
- Yes, sir, Mr Lewis.
Well, well. Hello again.
I'm looking for Edward.
Edward's not here.
I thought he was with you.
No. Uh, Edward is
definitely not with me.
No, if Edward were with me...
When, actually.
When Edward was with me,
he didn't blow off
billion-dollar deals.
No, I think that, uh,
Edward's with you,
that's what I think.
- Mind if I have a drink?
- No.
No, thank you.
Well, I'll just wait.
Uh, Edward will be back soon.
Any minute, he'll be home.
You know...
This is not home.
This is, uh, a hotel room.
And, uh, you are not...
the little woman.
You're a hooker.
Maybe you're a very good hooker,
you know?
I mean, maybe if I do you,
then I wouldn't care about
losing millions of dollars,
because I have to be very honest
with you right now, Vivian.
Right now I really do care.
I really do.
And right now I am
really pissed, you know?
Right now
I am just freaking out.
So maybe if I screw you, huh,
and take you to the opera,
- then I could be a happy guy
just like Edward.
- Hey, get off me!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Goddam it!
- Ow!
- Come on! Come on! Okay, whore.
- Get off me!
- Let's do it!
- How much is it? A hundred bucks?
- Ninety bucks? Fifty?
- Get off me!
- You a 50-dollar whore, Vivian?
What are you doing?
Get off her! Get off her!
- Stop! I don't wanna hurt you! Stop!
- I don't know how to tell you this.
You already did, Edward!
- Ow! All right. All right!
- Get outta here!
Look. She's a whore, man.
She's a goddam... Ah!
- Damn it!
- Shit! Goddam it!
- I think you broke my nose.
- Get outta here.
What is wrong with you?
Come on, Edward! I gave you ten years!
I devoted my whole life to you!
That's bullshit.
This is such bullshit!
It's the kill you love, not me!
And I made you a very rich man
doing exactly what you loved!
Now get outta here!
Get out!
Why do guys know how to hit a woman
right across the cheek?
Wham! And it feels like
your eye is gonna explode.
What do they do? Do they, they
pull you aside in high school
and show you how to do this?
Is that... Ow!
Not all guys hit.
I heard about what you did
with Morse.
It was a business decision.
- It was good.
- It felt good.
I think this is okay.
I gotta get going.
Yes, I noticed you packed.
Why are you leaving now?
Edward, there'll always be some guy,
even some friend of yours,
thinking he can treat me
like Stuckey...
thinking that it's allowed.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna beat up everybody?
That's not why you're leaving.
Look. You made me
a really nice offer.
And a few months ago, no problem.
But now everything is different, and you
changed that, and you can't change back.
I want more.
I know about wanting more.
I invented the concept.
The question is, how much more?
I want the fairy tale.
Impossible relationships.
My special gift
is impossible relationships.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
If you ever need anything...
dental floss, whatever...
you give me a call.
I had a good time.
Me too.
You want me to get you a bellboy?
- No, I got it.
- I'll carry this.
Thanks.
Stay. Stay the night with me.
Not because I'm paying you,
but because you want to.
I can't.
Goodbye.
I think you have
a lot of special gifts.
- I didn't do it, sir.
- No, no. I know.
I didn't say that.
I want you to call Maintenance
and have them deal with this.
- You must delegate authority.
- Yes, sir.
- Hi, Barney.
- Miss Vivian.
- Thank you.
- I wanted to say goodbye.
Well, then I gather you're not
accompanying Mr Lewis to New York?
Come on, Barney. You and me live
in the real world, most of the time.
Have you arranged
for transportation?
- I'm gonna call a cab.
- No, allow me. Darryl.
Yes, sir?
Please take Miss Vivian
anywhere she wishes to go.
Yes, sir.
It's been a pleasure knowing you.
Come and visit us again sometime.
Stay cool.
Lay a whisper
On my pillow
Leave the winter
On the ground
I wake up lonely
The stare of silence
In the bedroom
- And all around
- All around
Touch me now
I close my eyes
And dream away
It must have been love
But it's over now
It must have been good
But I lost it somehow
It must have been love
But it's over now
From the moment we touched
'Til the time had run out
Is that everything, sir?
- Yes, yes, that's everything.
- I'll meet you downstairs.
Thank you.
You look so dopey!
San Francisco's
not that great, you know.
It's a bad climate.
- It's foggy. It's unpredictable.
- I'll wear a sweater.
What are you gonna do there?
Get a job. Finish high school.
You know, I got things I can do,
you know. I used to make pretty
good grades in high school.
Yeah, I could see that about you.
I could see that.
Sure you won't come with me?
And leave all this?
Not in a million.
Come here.
Whoa! Whoa, what is this?
It's part of the Edward Lewis
Scholarship Fund.
We think you got a lot
of potential, Kit De Luca.
You do?
- You think I got potential?
- Oh, yeah.
Don't let anybody
tell you different, okay?
Okay.
- Take care of you.
- Oh, no. I can't. I can't.
It's your favourite.
What time's your bus?
An hour.
Yeah, well, I gotta split
'cause goodbyes make me crazy.
- So take care of you.
- Whoa.
- Mr Lewis.
- You don't have any messages
for me, do you?
No, I'm afraid not, sir.
- I'll need a car
to the airport also.
- Of course.
Darryl will take you
wherever you need to go.
- Darryl, the limousine
out front, please?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you, Darryl.
- One last thing.
- Yes.
If you could possibly return
this to Fred's for me, please.
Yes, of course, sir.
- May I, sir?
- Of course, please.
It must be difficult to let go
of something so beautiful.
You know, Darryl also drove
Miss Vivian home yesterday.
I'll take care of it.
Thank you, Mr Thompson.
Your plane is leaving
as scheduled, sir,
and you should be back
in New York on time.
I'm gonna have to charge you
a little more rent than Vivian...
because I got this beauty course
I'm lookin' into.
I'm not gonna be there that much.
You know? 'Cause you can't...
You just can't turn tricks forever. You
gotta have a goal. Do you have a goal?
Well, I always wanted to be
in the Ice Capades.
Help you, love?
Here we go.
Thank you very much.
So you got a lot of stuff
you gotta move in?
No, Carlos burned most of my stuff
when I said I was movin' out.
Vivian!
Princess Vivian, come down!
- It had to be the top floor, right?
- It's the best!
All right. I'm coming up.
So what happened after he
climbed up the tower and rescued her?
She rescues him right back.
Welcome to Hollywood!
What's your dream?
Everybody comes here.
This is Hollywood, land o' dreams.
Some dreams come true, some don't.
But keep on dreamin'.
This is Hollywood.
Always time to dream,
so keep on dreamin'.
Pretty woman
walking down the street
Pretty woman,
the kind I like to meet
Pretty woman
I don't believe you
You're not the truth
No one could look
as good as you
Mercy
Pretty woman,
won't you pardon me
I couldn't help but see
Pretty woman
And you look lovely as can be
Are you lonely just like me
Oh, oh
Pretty woman
You really took me by surprise
You're someone I've needed
for a lifetime
Your heart was cleverly disguised
And didn't look that way
in my mind
Tell me how could it be
I was the last to know
Darlin', I couldn't read
what was in your mind
To turn around and love me
With no explanation
I gave you everything I had
I didn't know
that you would take it
With sweet consideration
And after all
that we've been through
I can't believe it's true
Until I hear you say it
Ooo-ooo-ooo-ooo-ooo
And on and on and on and on
There's no explaining
With no explanation
I gave you everything I had
I didn't know
that you would take it