Good evening! Namaskaar,
Sasrakaar, Aadaam.
Welcome to "Who Wants To Be A Millionaire"!
Are you ready?
Yes.
- Please give a big round of applause to...
- Good Luck Kid
-...a very first contestant of the night
Jamal Malik from our very
own... Aarmchi Mumbay!
Hello, let's play.
Smile, you'll be fine.
Name.
Motherfucker, name!
Jamal... Malik.
You have a name. Good. Stop, crying.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, very much.
Uh, so, Jamal...
tell me something about yourself.
I work in a call-center...
- ...in Juhu.
- Good.
A phone basher..
And what type of call-center should that be?
XL5 mobile phones.
So you are the one who calls me up
every single day of my life
with special offers, huh?
No, actually I am an assistant.
An assistant phone basher?
And what does an assistant
phone basher do exactly?
I get tea for people and...
Chaiwalla? A chaiwalla!
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
Jamal Malik... one who serves
hot tea from Mumbay,
let's play "Who Wants To Be A Millionaire?"!
So, has he confessed yet?
Except his name I could not get
anything out of the runt.
You have been here the whole bloody
night, Srinivas. What have you been doing?
He's a tough guy.
A little electricity will
loosen his tongue, give him.
Yes sir.
Ok, so were you wired up?
Mobile phone or a pager?
Or coughing accomplice in the audience?
Or microchip under your skin, huh?
The chip is not here.
Not here? Ok, leave it.
Leave it.
It's hot, and my wife is giving me hell.
I've got a desk full of murderers, rapists,
extortionists, bomb bandits, and you.
So why don't you save us both a lot of time
and tell me how you cheated.
Mmm... Hmm.
I'm done sir.
Now listen.
Hello!
He's is unconscious,
fucker. What good is that?
How many times have I told
you, you should once...
I'm sorry sir.
Good, good, good Srinivas...
Now we'll have Amnesty International here next
peeing in their pants about human rights.
Sir I was thinking...
Get him down, tidy him up please.
For God's sake!
Sir, what if he did know the answers?
Professors, doctors, lawyers,
general knowledge-wallas
never get beyond 60000 rupees.
He's on 10 million.
What the hell can a slumdog possibly know?
The answers!
I knew the Answers...
Jamal, catch it, catch it, Jamal!
Jamal, take the catch!
Hey man, how did you manage to drop
a sitter like that, damn it?
Private property!
Get lost from here!
Catch him!
Let's run.
The dogs are coming! Run!
Hey fatso!
If the planes won't kill you, we will!
Hey brother!
Hey fatso.
Yahoo!...
- Hey, why running here?
- Not running!
Run, run!
Hey, what..?
Sorry!
There comes...
- Go, go, go...
- I'm very sorry.
Oh shit, it's Mum.
Want to break your bones, huh?
Brother, please forgive them.
Come on.
We are going to school.
Athos.
The Three Musketeers.
Repeat it!
"You have sent for me, Sir?" said Athos.
Ah, here come our very own musketeers.
Thank you for gracing us all
with your presence.
Porthos!
Open it.
Salim, open it correctly.
Don't know how to open a book.
What do you think yourself, huh?
Athos?
So... Mr. Malik
the man who knows all the answers.
Talk.
Whoreson talk!
So Jamal, are you ready for the
first question, for 1000 rupees?
Yes.
Not bad money to sit on a chair
and answer a question.
Better than making tea, no?
No. Yes. No.
No? Yes? No? Is that your final answer?
So remember. You have three lifelines.
Ask the audience, fifty-fifty
and call a friend.
So the first question, for 1000 rupees,
here we go.
Who was the star in the 1973
hit-film "Zanjeer"?
I'm in trouble, here...
Here... Money. Take the money...
Get out of there, Jamal.
Prakash wants a big one.
Not finished.
Stop your time-pass boys. This is urgent...
It's a shy one...
and since when there is
a time limit on a crap?
This is borderline kid. Get a move on...
Since there was a customer waiting,
that's when Jamal!
Give me the money back!
Give! I'll go elsewhere.
Bloody idiot.
You just lost me a bloody customer.
Amitabh's helicopter!
That's Amitabh's helicopter!
Amitabh!
Amitabh Bachchan!
Salim, open it!
My Amitabh sir!
Move, move! Out of the way!
Please wait, I am coming for you!
Amitabh sir, please give me your autograph
Yea, got Amithab's autograph!
You've got it now have you?
Amitabh's autograph?
That was my autograph!
My autograph!
Amitabh gave it to me!
I'll never get another!
He offered a good price, so I sold it.
But it was mine...
A, Amitabh Bachchan.
Guess what, you're right.
You just won 1,000 rupees.
You don't have to be a genius.
I knew it was Amitabh Bachchan.
- Hmm..?
- Umm.
Like I said, you do not have to be a genius.
He's the most famous man in India.
A picture of three lions, as seen
on the national emblem of India.
What is written underneath?
A: The truth alone triumphs
B: Lies alone triumph
C: Fashion alone triumphs
D: Money alone triumphs
What do you think, Jamal?
The most famous phrase of our country.
Do you like to call a friend?
Ask the audience.
Put the poor man out of his
misery, ladies and gentlemen?
My five-year old daughter
can answer that question,
but you couldn't.
That's strange for a millionaire genius.
What happened?
Your accomplice sneaked out for a piss?
The inspector is asking something.
How much is panipuri at
Dharisha store on Chowpatty?
What?
Panipuri. One plate. How much?
- 10 rupees.
- Wrong.
15 since Diwali.
Who stole Constable Varmy's bicycle
outside Santa Cruz station last Thursday?
You know who that was?
Everyone in Juhu knows that.
Even five year olds.
Congratulations, Jamal.
You just won 4,000 rupees.
A 16 thousand rupees.
Religion. Interesting.
In depictions of God Rama he is
famously holding what in his right hand?
Hey, Jamal.
Run, Jamal!
Run!
Salim, Jamal! Run!
They're Muslims, get them!
Come on Salim, come on.
Jamal let's go!
Run!
Let's Run!
Hey, get lost!
Why are you standing? Go home!
- Go Jamal.
- Come with us.
I wake up every morning wishing I did
not know the answer to that question.
If it wasn't for Rama and Allah...
I would still have a mother.
A bow and arrow.
Final answer?
Final answer.
Computer-ji, lock D.
You just won 16000 rupees.
Well done, my friend.
Time for commercial break.
Don't go away, now.
You got lucky, huh?
If I were you I'd take the money and run.
You're not going to the next one.
Piss off!
She'll have the security guard on us!
Let her in?
She could be our third musketeer.
I'm elder in the family,
and I say, she's not coming in, okay?
After all...
Which rascal knows the name
of the third musketeer.
Run Jamal..
Run!
Salim?
Hey.
Hey!
Come here.
You have mother?
Father?
I'm Jamal.
And that's my elder brother Salim.
I'm Latika.
You can sleep here if you want.
Thank you Jamal.
Welcome back to "Who
Wants To Be A Milionaire?"
Our contestant, Jamal Malik,
call-center assistant from Mumbay,
is on 16 thousand rupees,
and has already used only one
lifeline, ask the audience.
So my friend, you're into serious money.
Shall we play?
Yes.
The song "Darshan Do Ghanshyam" was
written by which famous Indian poet?
A: Surdas
B: Tulsidas
C: Mira Bai
D: Kabir
Jamal.
Hello.
It's hot, huh?
Here son.
The way he's taking care of
us, he must be a good man.
Must be a bloody saint.
We're not allowed to talk to the others.
Why?
If he is giving us food for the third time, then
he really must be a saint.
Arvind.
Very good, Arvind. It's good.
Salim.
Laughing at me. I'll kill you.
Hey, get off her.
Don't touch me!
You fat bastard!
Don't touch me.
Don't touch!
Punnoose, I think you've found your dog.
Okay, get to work.
Let's get to work.
Think you're here for a picnic?
Rascals, never do the job...
always play all day long?
What are you laughing at?
Give me that.
No.
Just give...
Shut up!
Brother Salim.
What's up little brother, you got a problem?
Hey take her. She's for you.
I don't want her.
Take her. It's for your own
good. Babies earn double.
She said she doesn't want her.
You shut up Jamal!
Take her or i'll drop.
No! No!
Crying baby, triple price.
Come on! Come on! Get to work!
Let's get to work.
Get lost, have to go there.
We'll use the hottest ones.
Come.
Chillies on his willy!
I'll get you back!
Go back to sleep all of you!
Silence.
Shut up! Go back to sleep.
Very good. I am happy.
- He is ready.
- Yes, I'm ready as well.
Come on, move the lamp.
Okay.
Salim...
Bring Jamal over.
Jamal.
Listen, kid. Time has arrived to take decision.
You want the life of a slumdog
or the life of a man, huh?
A real man. A gunfighter.
Your destiny is in your hands, brother.
You can take my place or...
Understand?
Understood.
Go. Get Jamal.
Punnoose.
I just need Maman to like my
singing, and we're in the money.
Big money, Latika.
And then can we stop begging?
Begging? Are you crazy?
We'll live in a big house on Harbour Road.
You, me and Salim. The Three Musketeers.
Harbour Road. Really?
Yes.
In the moonlight night...
You and me.
You'll dance like this, huh?
I hope you don't sing just like the way you dance.
Jamal, let's go.
It's my turn.
Sing well.
So this is it, our day, huh, brother?
Today our time has changed, brother.
Athos.
Porthos?
Hmm, when I say, then.
Jamal.
It's time to get professional.
What? Really?
First, let me hear that devotional song...
Okay.
Darshan to Ghanshyam.
That's my favourite devotional song.
Fifty rupees.
I'm a professional now, what can I do?
Rascal.
Here you go.
Jamal, go. Run!
Hold on! Catch them!
Run!
Get the torches! Get them!
Run Jamal, run!
Salim they are going to kill you!
Stop, rascal!
Latika, run! Run!
Salim!
Jamal.
Brother, run.
Get that rascal.
Come on, Latika! Grab the hand!
Grab the hand! Latika!
Latika.
Latika!
- What happened?
- She let go!
- What happened to her?
- What can I do?
Salim!
We've got to go back.
We've got to go.
Go back and we're dead.
Have you gone mad?
He was going to take your eyes out!
With a spoon.
Don't worry about her. She'll be fine.
She always is.
Surdas.
Surdas?
Surdas, is your final answer?
Yes.
Guess what, you're right!
Blind singers earn double you know that?
What happened to a girl?
They blinded her too?
They had other plans.
Well it took me a long time to find out.
Let it go, man.
Come on.
Where?
Rats are running inside my stomach.
Buy peanuts, kurkura.
Three for two.
Get up!
Is this your father's train?
So is it your father's train then?
Hey, the boy stealing the paratas!
Get off me.
Is this heaven?
You are not dead, Jamal.
What is it?
Some hotel huh?
The Taj Mahal is considered the
finest example of Mugal architecture.
Taj Mahal was completed around 1648 using
the labour force of 20'000 workers.
In 1980 it became a UNESCO
World Heritage Site and was cited as the...
Official tour guide.
Please take off your shoes
Please, please.
What time is the next tour?
We are on tight schedule.
We have to see the Red
Fort this afternoon.
VISITORS ARE REQUESTED TO COLLECT RECEIPT
- No, I...
- Please, would it be possible
to show us up round now?
Obviously we understand that it
costs more for just the two of us.
But of course madam!
Please follow me.
The Taj Mahal was built by Emperor Khurrama
for his wife Mumtaz, who was the
maximum beautiful woman in the world.
Then when she died, the emperor
decided to build this five-star hotel,
for everyone who would
like to visit her tomb.
But he died in 1587 before any of the
rooms were built, or any of the lifts.
But this swimming pool as you can see was
completed on schedule in top class fashion.
Is says nothing of this in the guide book.
The guide book was written by a bunch
of lazy good-for-nothing Indian beggars.
And this lady and gentlemen
is the burial place of Mumtaz.
How did she die?
- A road traffic accident.
- Really?
Maximum pile-up.
I thought she died in childbirth.
Exactly sir. She was on the way
to hospital when it happened.
Ready?
Smile.
Shoes! American brands!
It's high temperature, huh?
Smile.
Hey thieves, stop!
This, Mr David, is the biggest
Dhobi Ghat in the whole of India.
That's amazing.
Come on, take a real good look at this.
They say that every man in Uttar Pradesh
is wearing a kurta that has been
at least washed once out here.
Fast, fast!
Move it around! Pit-stop's god
speed! Schumacher's style!
There are the cows or are those
buffalos... What are those over there?
Go, go. Let's run!
Oh, shit.
What the hell happened here?
Motherfucker!
Ok, that's enough!
Ok. Hold it!
Hold it, will you.
You've got the insurance don't you?
Are you ok?
You wanted to see a bit
of real India? Here it is!
Alright!
Well, here is a bit of
the real America, son.
("Money")
Oh, yes, yes! Jesus...
Here.
On an american 100 dollar bill
there's a portrait of
which american statesman?
A: George Washington
B: Franklin Roosevelt
C: Benjamin Franklin
D: Abraham Lincoln
Pay or play, Jamal?
You decide.
Oh god he's looking at the
camera. He hasn't got a clue.
This is gonna be a walk away. Stand by.
No, he's gonna play with him first.
Jamal?
Get a lot of 100 dollar bills
in your in your line of work?
A minimum tip for my services.
Oh, now I know why my
cellphone bills are so high.
They tip the chaiwalla
with 100 dollar bills.
It's C. Benjamin Franklin.
You're gonna play, huh?
I think I've just had, hadn't I?
So you exactly have C, right?
Who's on 1,000 rupee note?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Ghandi-ji
Oh, I have heard of him.
Don't get clever
or I'll get the electricity out again.
Look.
They didn't ask me that
question. I don't know why.
Ask them.
It's funny, you don't seem
like you're interested in money.
By the fact you have...
one million rupees!
Explain the 100 dollar bill.
Bombay had turned name to Mumbay.
Why don't you understand?
A girl lived here. As tall as me perhaps.
- Her name was Latika.
- We don't know anyone of that name.
Ok, she stayed somewhere over there,
you know right?
Don't know.
Two chicken burgers, two
fries, one mango rassi, one coke!
One mineral water!
Shimla.
I'm going to Chowpatty, ok? Wanna come?
For god's sake, you've got some disease?
You're forcing back to this shithole.
We leave our friends, a good life,
lots of money. For this?
We came back to find her.
You did. I don't give a shit about her.
Plenty of pussy in Bombay for Salim.
Oh yes sir!
You should come back to
the Cages on Saturday night,
instead of ghost searching
for your lost love.
I'm going to Chowpatty.
I'm going to Chowpatty!
There are 19 million
people in this city, Jamal.
Forget about her.
She is a WOMAN.
Greetings, Sir.
Blessings be unto those
who do good for others.
Dollars. How much?
- 100.
- Why are you fooling me sir?
Honestly. I swear on my mothers soul.
What's on this note? Tell me. Whose picture is it?
There's an old man...
He's bald on top with long
hair on the sides, like a girl.
Benjamin Franklin.
So you're a big guy now, Jamal.
Good. I'm happy for you.
I'm sorry...
You got saved my friend. I wasn't so lucky.
That's the only difference.
Arvind, I'm trying to find...
You owe Maman. Stay away.
He never forgets.
I owe Latika.
She's alive isn't she?
More than alive. She's on Pila
street. They call her Cherry.
Thanks.
I'll be singing at your funeral.
Know Cherry?
- Where can we found Cherry?
- You want Cherry? Get lost! Go home.
Where's Cherry?
Get lost! Take another one.
- Cherry?
- Inside.
So, is it her or not?
She's sexy, man!
Get on, Latika!
- Who is this?
- Jamal?
- I'll get the bags.
- Who are you? What do you want?
- You stupid boys!
- Pack it in! Put that.
How did you find me?
Later, later...
Take the cash. Come on!
We got it. Let's go! Let's go!
Shit.
Look who we have here!
Hello again.
Jamal, Salim.
I never forget a face.
Right Punnoose?
especially one that I own.
You really thought you could just
walk in and take my prize away?
Latika, come.
Have you any idea how much
this little virgin is worth? Sisterfucker!
- Please continue, Master-ji.
- Ok, sir.
- Get them out of here!
- No!
Move! Get over there!
Let's not be foolish, Salim.
Heavy, isn't it? Give it to me. Huh?
On your knees! Down!
Both of you! Down!
Money!
You can have money, here.
Look.
Take it. Go, disappear with your friend.
And we'll forget all about this, ok?
Maman never forgets. Isn't that right?
Oh, Maman can make an exception, huh?
I can't take that risk Maman. Sorry.
Let's go.
- Stay!
- Jamal!
Let's go! Let's go!
Who invented the revolver?
Samuel Colt.
Final answer?
Final answer.
Jamal Malik, you're on a dream run.
My heart says you're gonna win more.
Computer-ji, lock A.
I was right.
The chaiwalla has done it again.
Incredible!
Reception!
Let's go.
Found something?
Stay there. Look away.
Ok, ok.
I'll know if you're looking.
No i'm not.
Is Salim still there?
Where is Salim?
I don't know.
You're a sweet boy, Jamal.
I'm looking for Javed.
Motherfucker! He's not looking for you.
I killed Maman,
and I'll kill you too.
Easy.
Did you really kill him?
Good. My enemy's enemy is a friend.
Come here, my friend.
Hmm..I've been looking for someone like you.
You came back for me.
Of course.
I thought you'd forgotten.
I never forgot. Not for one moment.
I knew I'd find you in the end.
It's our destiny.
Destiny?
Ok.
Hey.
Come.
No, brother. You had a lot to drink.
I am the elder. I am the boss.
For once, you do as I say.
Now get out!
Come on, I saved your life, didn't I?
Salim, please...
Shut up.
I'll kill you!
Salim!
I am number one now.
Salim! Open!
Shut up!
The man with the Colt 45 says shut up!
Go now or gun master-ji and I will
shoot you right between the eyes.
Don't think you won't.
I'm giving you five seconds.
One.
Two.
Go, Jamal.
Go.
Let's go.
So, did you see them again?
I wouldn't be here if I had.
Was she pretty?
I guess not.
The most beautiful woman in the world.
You mean the bitch of the slum.
Sisterfucker.
Hey hero.
Hey beat him!
Hey lock him down!
Lock him... he fights! Motherfucker!
Well well... the slumdog barks.
Money and women.
The reasons for make most mistakes in life.
Correct.
Looks like you've mixed up both.
Srinivas, you need the exersice.
Go and get me something to eat.
Yes sir.
And tea.
Idiot, Srinivas.
You puzzled me slumdog.
Admitting murder to avoid child fraud.
Is not exactly clever thinking.
Now why would you do that?
When somebody asks me a
question I tell them the answer.
So, how did you manage to get on the show?
Okay everyone, listen up.
It's been a big week for UK.
Kat is back.
But she is already back. Bardi... Jamal?
Oh, well, she did come back, then she
went away when Alfie split up with her.
And now she's back again, but it
looks as if Alfie still fancies more...
Thank you, Jamal.
Bardi, keep up. The
chaiwalla knows more than you.
Anyway, there's also the
festival in Edinburgh.
Anybody knows Edinburgh, Edinburgh?
Kilts, castles, ...uh, haggis. Uh...Ben Navis.
Good, yes?
Inspector Taggart, whiskey, Sean Connery.
Good, and "lochs". Their word for lakes.
No filming.
Jamal, come here.
I'm on "Millionaire" duty today.
Dev!
- Please, just for five minutes.
- I can't.
Sit here.
If the team leader comes just pretend you're
on a call doing an upgrade for...
- ..."Friends and Family", I know.
- Yeah.
Two minutes.
"Who wants to be a millionaire?"
Dial this number now!
Hello. Hello!
I would like to be a contestant of
"Who wants to be a millionaire?"
Bloody bastard. I never get it.
You have to dial, when Prem says "if".
That's when they open the lines.
How the hell do you know that?
That's what Anjum in Technical
says. He put a system in.
Hello? Hello? Forgetting someone there for god's sake?
Hello? Dear god will somebody talk to me?
Uh... Hello, Mrs MacKintosh from Kin.. gussie.
It's Kingussie, love. Pronounced: "Kee-nu-ssi".
So where are you from? Abroad I bet?
Just down the road from
your house, Mrs. MacKintosh.
Uh... Next to the "loch".
Ok, which "loch"?
"Loch" Big... "loch" Ben... "Loch" Big Ben.
Next door to Sean Connery's flat.
Look. I'd like to your supervisor, son?
WHAT NAME DO YOU REQUIRE?
SEARCH COMPLETE. 26,283 RESULTS FOUND.
15 RESULTS FOUND.
Yes?
Salim?
Who is this? Do you know what time is this?
Hello?
Who is this?
I'm calling from XL5 Communications sir.
As a valued customer, we are offering you
a free upgrade with our "Friends and...
...family"
Jamal? Is... Is that you, brother?
Where are you?
I thought you were dead or something.
Listen, we had to go Jamal.
Maman's guys... they
were searching the hotel.
Jamal? Say something, please!
Hello, Salim!
Cambridge Circus is not in Cambridge.
Can I ask why?
Too obvious. There's definitely
an Oxford Circus in London
There's a rowing race
between Oxford and Cambridge,
so ther's probably a
Cambridge Circus too, no?
I'll go for D. London.
Computer-ji, lock D.
Jamal Malik, you are absolutely right.
It's getting hot in here.
Are you nervous?
What?
Am I nervous?
It's you who's in the hot seat, my friend.
Oh yes, sorry.
Balli, he's got prey on the run.
Finally.
A few hours ago...
...you were giving chai for the phone wallas.
And now you're richer
than they will ever be.
What a player!
Ladies and gentlemen, what a player!
Jamal?
God is good, Brother. God is good.
Maman's guys were out for
us. We just had to escape.
- Liar.
- I left a message for you at work.
We waited for weeks for you at Nagpur.
- There was no message.
- Brother. I definitely left a message.
There was no message! There was no message!
There was no message!!
I will never forgive you.
I know.
That used to be our slum.
Can you believe that, huh?
We used to live right there man.
Now is all business.
India is at the center of the world now. Brother.
And I...
I am at the center of the center.
This is all Javed's.
Javed Khan? The gangster from our slum?
You work for him?
Come on. Who else would save
us from Maman's guys, huh?
What do you do for him?
Anything he asks.
He's coming. You need
to go now. Take my card.
What for?
You think them gonna let you
out of my sight again, huh?
You stay with me my younger brother.
Now go. My place.
Salim! Where is Latika?
Still?
She's gone brother. Long gone.
Now go. Go to my place.
Ok, Sir. I'll be right there.
Oh Lord forgive me. I
know that I have sinned.
know that I have sinned a lot.
Go.
Brother-ji, I am your new cook from the
agency. Thousands apologies!
I'm so late for the mensa!
Just a minute.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
There's nothing about any cook.
There's a dishwasher being delivered.
Do you know anything about that?
Oh brother, I... I'm your dishwasher.
Jamal!
Look at you.
I've found you!
Uh, I've found you.
Your face.
You've hurt your eye.
Why are you here?
To see you.
Why? You see me, now what?
Why does everyone love this program?
This is a chance to escape, isn't it?
Walk into another life.
Oh, god.
Javed will kill you. Here.
Javed?
You are with him?
First, you want a dishwasher,
Now you want this fucking cook, huh?
- He's just...
- Shut up!
The cricket is on.
And why you watch this shit tv?
At least I am a millionaire.
Come on, I am hungry. Make me a sandwich.
Come away with me.
Away? Where?
And live out what?
Love.
Come away with me. Now.
Salim will help us.
Salim? You still believe in Salim?
Jamal, I'll be gone soon anyway.
We're getting out of Bombay.
Where?
You think he'd tell me?
No! No! No!
Fuck.
What is this shit?
Get out! Get out!
Motherfucker.
Go, before he kills us both.
- You want to do something for me?
- Anything.
Then forget me.
What? No.
I will wait. The VT station.
5 o'clock, every day until you come.
I love you.
So what? It's too late, Jamal. Now go.
So Jamal.
Which cricketer has scored the most
first class centuries in history?
A:Sachin Tendulkar.
B:Ricky Ponting.
C:Michael Slater.
or D:Jack Hobbs.
But remember, if you answer wrong...
...you lose everything, just like this.
So do you want to do this?
Dreams of so many...
...on the floor.
Latika.
Latika! Latika!!
Jamal! Jamal!... Jamal!
Go! Let's go.
Latika!
Jamal!
Shut up!
Take her!
- Get's go!
- Jamal!
No Jamal!
Latika!
Time for commercial break ladies and gentlemen.
I know, I know. I can't stand the tension either.
We'll be right back.
Guy from the slums becomes
a millionaire overnight.
You know who's the only other
person who's done that?
Me.
I know what it feels like.
I know what you're being through.
I'm not going to become a millionaire.
I don't know the answer.
You said that before, yeah...
No really, this time I don't.
Come on, you can't take the money and run now.
You are on the edge of history kid.
I don't see what else I can do.
Maybe it's written my friend.
I don't know I just have some kind of gut
feeling, you're gonna win this.
Trust me, Jamal.
You're gonna win.
Standby, everyone. We are on line in 13...
Rakesh please give backup, man.
Yeah, he's gone. I'm just giving...
Come fast.
20 seconds!
Do the right thing and in approximately 3 minutes
you'll be as famous as me.
10 seconds!
And as rich as me. Almost.
5 seconds! 4... 3...
From rags to Raja. It's your destiny.
We are on. Applause and music please!
Jugulu out, cut!
Welcome back to "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?"!
In the chair tonight is Jamal
Malik, as if we don't know.
For 10 million rupees.
To question once again.
Which cricketer has scored the most first class centuries in history?
No it isn't Sachin Tendulkar.
That's a start.
So it could be Ricky Ponting, Jack Hobbs or Michael Slater.
I'll use a lifeline. Fifty-fifty.
Ok.
Computer, take away the two wrong answers please.
Well, you were right about Sachin Tendulkar.
That leaves your fifty-fifty choice, Jamal.
B: Ricky Ponting or D: Jack Hobbs.
What do you think?
Decision time. For 10 million rupees.
B: Ricky Ponting
Or D: Jack Hobbs.
D.
Not B?
The Ricky Ponting, the Australian great cricketer?
D, Jack Hobbs.
You know?
So it could be B, Ricky Ponting?
Or D, Jack Hobbs.
The final answer, D.
Computer-ji D...
...Lock D. Computer-ji lock D.
With 197 first class centuries, the answer is...
D, Jack Hobbs!
Jamal Malik! Millionaire!
Do the dance! Come on! Come on!
Well done! Well done.
So, are you ready for the final question?
For 20 million rupees.
No. But maybe it's written, no?
Maybe.
Okay. The final question! On who wants to be a...
Ahh... What a show ladies and gentlemen! What a show!
Join us tomorrow night...
...to see if Jamal Malik has made the biggest mistake
of his life by just one biggest prize, history of Indian television.
This way.
Great show.
See you tomorrow ok.
- Be on time.
- Yeah.
Bye.
- Let's go!
- Easy! Easy!
- No tricks!
- What's going on?
- He's a cheat.
- How do you know he's cheating?
Bloody village boy. I fed him the wrong
answer, and he never should call it right.
You gave him an answer?
Not exactly. Well that doesn't matter. That's my show!
My fucking show!
It is a bizarrely plausible, and yet...
Because I'm a slumdog, a chaiwalla.
I'm a liar right?
Most of you are.
But you are not a liar, Mr Malik. That's for sure.
You are too truthful.
We're done.
I don't know where they've taken her.
Latika.
I went on the show, because I thought she'd be watching.
Did Jamal Malik, an uneducated 18 year
old boy from the slums of Mumbay,
win one crore by fair means or by foul play.
And the crowd around me bears an even bigger question:
Will he be back tonight to play for another 20 million rupees?
Jamal Malik, a name which has been in news
in every town, neighbourhood, villages and homes.
18 year old Jamal Malik, is from Juhu Mumbai
and he's showing his elegance in the show
"Who Wants To Be A Millionaire".
Jamal Malik has won 1 core rupees and just
one question away from...
Bark!
Come on girls!
Hey you come here,
give me a kiss.
Come on girls!
Hey, move back.
Yes buddy, I couldn't hear a thing in there.
Look, you've to make arrangment for us
to come into the town.
As if it wasn't enough drama in a contestant reaching the final question,
Jamal Malik was last night arrested on suspicion of fraud.
That guy. He will never come.
Ever.
Crazy fucker.
Go.
But...
Just drive. There won't be another chance.
He will kill you.
Yes ok.
I'll take care of him.
Salim, I can't.
You have to.
God sake will take you out of this.
Evil what I've done please forgive me.
Have a good life.
Ok, alright.
You're back on the show.
Come on!
Hey, Jamal? The millionaire? Hey son, Jamal...
The millionaire who won 2 cores? The one with all the cash?
With 2 lakhs!
- Go son, go with my blessing and win it all.
- Is that him?... Is that him?
- It's him, Jamal!
- We love you Jamal!
The nation's gripped with millionaire fever.
As Jamal Malik, an uneducated youngman from the Juhu slum in Mumbay,
won a staggering 10 million rupee
on a television show who wants to be a millionaire,
and estimated 90 million people watching us tonight
to see if he will make a one stage further to 20 million rupees.
Come on!
Where is everyone? Get back in there!
Get back to work! Now.
Chaiwalla?
Welcome back to who wants to be a millionaire.
I can safetly say that tonight
is the biggest night of both our lives.
Jamal Malik, the call assistant worker from Mumbay,
has already won 10 million.
He can walk away with that in his pocket
or make the biggest gamble in television history.
And go for the final question
and a staggering 20 million rupees.
Are you ready for that question?
- Yes.
- Jamal!
Big reader are you, Jamal?
I can read.
Lucky.
In Alexandre Dumas' book, the "The Three Musketeers",
two of the musketeers are called Athos and Porthos.
What was the name of the third Musketeer?
Come on in, come inside baby.
A: Aramis
B: Cardinal Richelieu
C: D'Artagnan
Or D: Planchet
Porthos!
She could be our third musketeer.
Final question for 20 million rupees, and he is smiling.
I guess you know the answer.
Do you believe it, I don't.
You don't?
So you take the 10 million and walk?
No. I'll play.
Let remind you, Jamal.
If you get the answer wrong,
you lose everything.
10 million rupees, Jamal.
It's a fortune.
I'd like to phone a friend.
You're going to the wire.
The final lifeline. Here we go.
It's ringing!
Who is it?
That's my brother's number, but...
The kind of brother, who go for a walk on a 20 million rupee question?
It's the only number I know.
You are on your own, Jamal.
Hello?
Hello, Jamal?
I'm guessing that isn't your brother.
This is...
My name is Latika.
Okay, Latika.
You want to hear the question one more time? And let's be clear about this.
20 million rupees right on your answer, you have 30 seconds.
Latika.
- Salim!
- Jamal, please read out the question to Latika now.
- It is really you?
- Yes.
The question, Jamal. The question!
In Alexandre Dumas' book, the "The Three Musketeers",
two of the musketeers are called Athos and Porthos.
What was the name of the third Musketeer?
Was it A: Aramis, B: Cardinal Richelieu, C: D'Artagnan or D: Planchet?
15 seconds!
Where are you?
I am safe.
10 seconds!
Uhh... Latika, what do you think?
I don't know. I've never known.
Jamal, God will ...
You really are on your own now, Jamal.
Your final answer for 20 million rupees.
A.
A, because?
Just... because.
Hey, Salim!
You inside, you shameless Salim...
Final answer?
Latika!
Yes, final answer. A, Aramis.
Computer-ji, lock A.
Salim!... Salim!
Open the door! Salim!
Jamal Malik, call center assistant from Mumbay,
chaiwalla,
for two draws 20 million rupees
Open the door, Salim!
you were asked who the third musketeer
was in novel by Alexander Dumas.
You answered A, Aramis.
Which is. I have to tell you.
The right answer!
Jamal Malik!
Double millionaire!
God is great.
What a man!
What a night!
I knew you'd be watching.
I thought we'd be together only in death.
This is our destiny.
Kiss me.
D:               .
D: it is written
D                .
Directed by
" Victory To Thee, Victory To Thee "
-
[Jai Ho, Jai Ho]
" Come come below the decorated tent of life "
-
[Aaja Aaja Jind Shamiyane Ke Tale]
" Come under the glittering blue sky "
-
[Aaja Jariwale Nile Aasman Ke Tale]
" Victory To Thee, Victory To Thee "
-
[Jai Ho, Jai Ho]
" Come come below the decorated tent of life "
-
[Aaja Aaja Jind Shamiyane Ke Tale]
" Come under the glittering blue sky "
-
[Aaja Jariwale Nile Aasman Ke Tale]
" Victory To Thee, Victory To Thee "
-
[Jai Ho, Jai Ho]
" Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.. "
-
[Jai Ho.., Jai Ho.., Jai Ho.., Jai Ho..]
" Night after night I truly died.. "
-
[Ratti Ratti Sachi Maine Jaan Gavayi Hai]
" Spent the nights dancing on hot coals.. "
-
[Nach Nach Koylo Pe Raat Bitayi Hai]
" I blew the sleep in my eyes with air from my mouth "
-
[Akhiyon Ki Neend Maine Phoonko Se Uda Di]
" I burned my finger with blue star by counting them"
-
[Gin gin Neele Tare Se Maine Ungli Jalayi Hai]
" Come come below the decorated tent of life "
-
[Aaja Aaja Jind Shamiyane Ke Tale]
" Come under the glittering blue sky "
-
[Aaja Jariwale Nile Aasman Ke Tale]
" Victory to thee, Victory to thee, Victory to thee, Victory to thee "
-
[Jai Ho, Jai Ho, Jai Ho, Jai Ho]
" Dance! Dance! "
-
[Baila! Baila!]
" Now with me, you dance for today "
-
[Ahora conmigo, tu baila para hoy]
" For our day, just forget whatever problems there may be "
-
[Por nuestro dia olvidas los problemas que sean]
" Cheers! "
-
[Salud!]
" Dance! Dance! "
-
[Baila! Baila!]
" Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.. "
-
[Jai Ho.., Jai Ho.., Jai Ho.., Jai Ho..]
" Taste it, yes taste it, this night is honey, taste it "
-
[Chakh Le, Ha Chakh Le, Ye Raat Shahad Hai.. Chakh Le]
" Keep it, yes this is heart, heart is last limit.. Keep it "
-
[Rakh Le, Ha Dil Hai, Dil Aakhri Had Hai.. Rakh Le]
" Dark, this eyeliner of yours, is it your black magic? "
-
[Kala Kala Kajal Tera Koi Kala Jadoo Hai Na]
" Come come below the decorated tent of life "
-
[Aaja Aaja Jind Shamiyane Ke Tale]
" Come under the glittering blue sky "
-
[Aaja Jariwale Nile Aasman Ke Tale]
" Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.., Victory to thee.. "
-
[Jai Ho.., Jai Ho.., Jai Ho.., Jai Ho..]
" Victory to thee, Victory to thee "
-
[Jai Ho, Jai Ho]